<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>
<string_table>
  <string id="mil_treasure_1_name">
    <text>Box in truck</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_treasure_1_descr">
    <text>What's the best possible spot in the abandoned army base for stashing stuff? Answer: a hidden box in an already ransacked truck.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_treasure_2_name">
    <text>Barracks</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_treasure_2_descr">
    <text>You can find tons of spots in the barracks for stashing things. Just make sure no one else thinks to look where you picked.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_treasure_3_name">
    <text>Warehouse box</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_treasure_3_descr">
    <text>I doubt someone would want to dig up dusty old boxes in an abandoned base. Can't go wrong with this place.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_treasure_4_name">
    <text>Gas oven</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_treasure_4_descr">
    <text>I'll leave my second backpack in the old oven. It's full of junk I don't need right now.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_treasure_5_name">
    <text>Pipe in tower</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_treasure_5_descr">
    <text>Guess I'll make a stash for my extra stuff on one of the inner protrusions on the tower. The local wildlife should serve as good defense.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_treasure_6_name">
    <text>Burnt-down house</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_treasure_6_descr">
    <text>There's a hard-to-reach crate in the ruins of the burnt house. There's also that pack of bloodsuckers running around outdoors, so I doubt anyone will poke their nose into my stash.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_treasure_7_name">
    <text>Old shack</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_treasure_7_descr">
    <text>I've been watching this guy for a few days by now. He's always in the village bringing junk of all sorts to his little shack. Should shake him down so he doesn't keep it all to himself.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_treasure_8_name">
    <text>Case in bus</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_treasure_8_descr">
    <text>I hit jackpot when taking the contract on this stalker. Never seen this much loot on one guy! I should hide it all 'til things get better.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_treasure_9_name">
    <text>Backpack on the Barrier</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_treasure_9_descr">
    <text>The former Freedom camp on the Barrier is a perfect spot for a fat stash.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_quest_treasure_1_name">
    <text>Case in village</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_quest_treasure_1_descr">
    <text>I know this one nice stash with tons of medical supplies, but it's also got some good security... that is, the bloodsuckers. I'll have to pull up my socks for this one.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_quest_treasure_2_name">
    <text>Backpack in attic</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_quest_treasure_2_descr">
    <text>As a reward for your service, I'll give you the coordinates to a stash in the village. You'd be passing by there anyway. Just watch yourself in those parts!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_quest_treasure_3_name">
    <text>Supplies</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_quest_treasure_3_descr">
    <text>While I was on my way from the village to the farm, I had to scuttle from the bloodsuckers. Was so pumped up I even threw my backpack on the roof. I don't plan on going back myself, but you might find it useful.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_quest_treasure_4_name">
    <text>Safe under car</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_quest_treasure_4_descr">
    <text>You did me a good one, stalker! Have the coordinates to one of my artifact stashes as a reward — I didn't get the chance to retrieve it myself. Whatever you find is yours.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_quest_treasure_5_name">
    <text>In case of a breakthrough</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_quest_treasure_5_descr">
    <text>The Almighty Monolith gave us a powerful weapon, which it was decided to hide on the approaches to the Barrier, in case the stalkers break through to the Radar. No one except the Monolith brothers should know about this cache.</text>
  </string>
</string_table>
