<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1250"?>
<string_table>
  <string id="encyclopedia_locations_yantar_descr">
    <text>Yantar is the name of the remains of a dried up lake and the valley around it. It is located in the western part of the Zone. The plant to the north of the lake has the same name. The most notable place for stalkers here is the mobile bunker of scientists, located in the lowest part of the lake. It is run by Professor Sakharov, who is not averse to offering jobs, talking about science, and accepting biological material of mutants or anomalous formations for a fee. Around the lowland with the bunker is a dirt road leading north to the plant. Before the Chernobyl accident, it produced chemicals, the waste of which was dumped into the lake.  Stalkers have a bad reputation for the old factory on Yantar, few people return from there, because there is an experimental psy emitter Kaimanov, the prototype of the legendary Brain Scorcher. Though it has been dormant in recent years, there have been no more willing visitors to the place. At the moment it is not known how relevant these lines are in the context of the description of the territory of Yantar: recently in this area there was a mysterious cataclysm, after which the connection with the mobile bunker and all the stalkers in its vicinity — was lost. So far no one has any evidence about what happened there.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_locations_darkvalley_descr">
    <text>To the east of the Garbage is an area referred to by stalkers as the Dark Valley. It is a kind of agrarian-industrial terrain, inherent in most suburbs in the post-Soviet countries. In the central part of this area there is a highway bridge separating a large anomalous swamp. To the north is an unfinished building. Previously, this building was the base of the group Freedom, but later bandits settled on it. To the east, across the road, is a gas station. In the central part, to the east, there is a factory, in the basement of which is the entrance to the secret laboratory X18. In the southwestern part there is an old, partially collapsed pig farm with a water tower.\n \nFollowing the east of the Dark Valley you can reach the coast of the Pripyat river. It is not known exactly why this area is called the Dark Valley. According to one version, the sun rarely appeared in these parts and the weather was mostly cloudy and rainy. Recently, however, many mystical rumors and legends have been circulating about the Dark Valley, so the name of this area began to take on a completely different meaning.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_locations_military_descr">
    <text>The Army Warehouses is a hilly area in the northeast, covered with anomalies of various types, adjacent to a huge abandoned military base. Surprisingly, these structures are not currently held by any faction. Not far from the warehouses is a large-looking village, which local stalkers nicknamed Bloodsuckerwood. Across the road from it there is a small farm and an abandoned roadblock, which is almost always held by Mercenaries. A small hamlet can also be stumbled upon on the way from the Bar. The army warehouses are, in fact, the last stronghold of civilization before Radar — constantly the Freedom roadblock, called Barrier, repels waves of mutants and Monolith units coming from the north.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_locations_garbage_descr">
    <text>If on the horizon began to loom piles of radioactive junk — then the stalker got to the Garbage! During the liquidation of the consequences of the accident at the Chernobyl nuclear power plant in this place was taken radiation-contaminated vehicles and other trash. It is in this way in the south of the territory formed a legendary cemetery of abandoned equipment, surrounded by hills of buried piles of rusted metal. Among the rows of rusty vehicles formed a lot of anomalous zones, so such a hot spot instantly took control of the local bandits. Another stronghold of bandits is located in a small flooded and half-destroyed substations, surrounded by chemical anomalies. There is a small forest right behind it, which for some reason smells of rot.\n \nAt the heart of the Garbage is an abandoned Depot. Now it is held by Stalkers led by a local merchant nicknamed Kostyl, but a few months ago this place was a key base of Bandits. The Depot is a good place for a tired Stalker to stop. Here you can spend the night, buy supplies, get medical help and find work. Local gunsmith Vityka Stepak, for a tidy sum, will get you almost any gun. From the depot stretches the railroad tracks towards Agroprom, entering a long, dark tunnel. From its depths are periodically heard some voices, but to check their nature in the local Stalkers have no desire.\n \nIn the north of the Dumpsite there is a roadblock of the Duty group, through which you can get to the territory of the Bar. Not far from the checkpoint there is an obscure ruined building made of reinforced concrete. Judging by the large platform with a Sickle and Hammer pedestal installed on it, this building was supposed to be an administrative building. Previously, stalkers called it Barakholka and used it as a trading post. Not far from it are two large cisterns.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_locations_ts_valley_katakomb_descr">
    <text>The sewers and technical collectors of the X-18 laboratory. They are also part of the Pripyat underground gateway network. The rooms are a network of narrow tunnels and small working rooms.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_locations_ts_military_katakomb_descr">
    <text>Abandoned Gateway "D" of the dungeon network leading to the main gateway of the Pripyat underground. Currently used by the Mercenaries for their own purposes.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_locations_agroprom_underground_descr">
    <text>The underground of the Cereal Research Institute, has many utilities and a pumping station that was used to irrigate the crops. At the moment, most of it is flooded, as it was a real breeding ground for mutants.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_locations_ts_nshep_descr">
    <text>A forest area with the village of Novoshepelichi, a military base, the experimental complex Pool and a railroad bridge over the Pripyat river. The electric train "Slavutich-Semikhody" is left on the bridge for eternal parking. Since the territory of Novoshepelichi has a rather impressive size, the diversity of the contingent of local Stalkers here is very large. In these places you can find a camp of free stalkers, fighters of the Freedom group, groups of Bandits and many loners. In the forest settled a group of hunters. The neighborhood of Novoshepelichi is famous for a large number of anomalous zones, and therefore attracted such an impressive number of guests. Predominantly wooded area has become a great shelter for monsters, so a walk in these parts will be a challenging adventure.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_locations_escape_descr">
    <text>Cordon is the calling card of the Chernobyl Exclusion Zone. It is here that the veil of all the strangeness, mysteries and dangers prepared for every newly arrived stalker opens. People often call Cordon pre-bathroom, because here is equipped with the largest army checkpoint, and a kilometer away from it is the famous Novice Village, where every illegal alien who broke through the perimeter. The main man in this camp is the trader Sidorovich, who is responsible for almost all business in these parts. A kind of headman among the newcomers is an experienced stalker nicknamed Fanat. These two people, having with that their certain benefit, will help the newcomer to get used to the newcomer, to get equipment and work.\n \nDespite the fact that the Zone on Cordon is just beginning, there are already a lot of insidious anomalies, radioactive zones and dangerous monsters. Located here and the local wonder of the world — a flying islands, the nature of the origin of which is still unknown. But the greatest danger here, of course, is man himself. The military at the checkpoint is authorized to shoot without warning at all unaccounted persons. It is a good thing that the soldiers are not afraid to take bribes, so the tongue-tied violators will always be able to negotiate. The same situation appears with local bandits. They have for many years held an abandoned vehicle station, from where they make forays throughout the territory of Cordon in order to gop-stop Stalkers. And a newcomer, often, it is better to lose a couple thousand or artifacts than to engage in a gunfight with the bandits.\n \nAt about the equator of Cordon, near the destroyed bridge, there is a small military checkpoint. To be more precise — the most corrupt checkpoint in the world, because everyone has long known that for 500 money you can get yourself a pass to the northern part of Cordon. Behind the railroad embankment is a few abandoned buildings, sawmill with anomalous zones and empty northern checkpoint, crossing which Stalker essentially ceases to be a newcomer.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_locations_bar_descr">
    <text>Before the accident, in 1986, it was a large industrial area. Now only rusty and old ruins remain of its former grandeur. Near one of the hangars, in the basement, there is a bar called 100 Roentgen: stalkers from all over the Zone gather there. A local trader works as a bartender and maintains the institution. You can bargain with him, find out the latest news or get some paid assignments. There is also an Arena where you can fight stalkers for money. Not far from the Arena is the base of the group Duty. The entire territory of the Bar is under its protection, so behave very carefully here. It is worth remembering that this is a neutral territory, and any manifestation of aggression here is strictly punished.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_locations_agroprom_descr">
    <text>If you follow the road west of the Garbage, very soon the dreary scenery of radioactive junk is replaced by a more pleasing pine forest. In the center of this area is the Borovik loading complex. This place is held by a small group calling themselves the Diggers. A little farther down the road spills a rusty radioactive lake with a pile of old junk and devices. Not far away in a dead end stands the Agroprom Research Institute. Here at one time studied the effects of radiation on cereal crops, and after the emergence of the Zone this place was taken by the Military. At the moment on the territory are based scientists and military stalkers, what they do is not clear, but there is a lot of security. They say that in this place Stalkers often find lucrative jobs.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_locations_labx18_descr">
    <text>X18 is an underground laboratory located beneath the Dark Valley, where various animals and humans were supposedly experimented on to create a super soldier. On the bottom floor, there is a room with broken flasks containing some kind of embryos that resemble the physical bodies of poltergeists.\n \nIn some rooms you can find irradiation equipment and cages for test subjects, obscure autoclaves and other non-standard scientific equipment. Previously known that the profile of the laboratory was the study of mutations and experimentation on genes to create mutants with unusual physical abilities. Previously, the laboratory X18 was damaged and many of its employees died, and some of the test subjects escaped into the wild. Now it is home to unknown monsters.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_locations_ts_millab_descr">
    <text>An unknown private laboratory built in the Zone after the second release. Accordingly, it has advanced equipment and means of defense. The facility is strictly classified and camouflaged, so only a few people know about its existence. The ability to secretly build such a modern and functional laboratory by a private individual in a forbidden territory is a sign that the owner has a large budget and connections.</text>
  </string>
</string_table>
