<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1250"?>
<string_table>
  <string id="encyclopedia_characters_hero">
    <text>Axe</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_characters_hero_descr">
    <text>Damn, I'm looking good! My handle's mediocre at best, but it has a nice story: I once made a run for it from some dogs and realized that a fight was inevitable. Grabbed the closest thing to me — an axe — and started spinning around faster than a stalker caught in a Whirligig. Right then, Fanatic and his men heard my screaming and panting. I don't know how it all would've ended up without him, but since then, I've taken to calling myself "Axe."</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_characters_hero_soldier">
    <text>Alexey Zhuravlev</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_characters_hero_soldier_descr">
    <text>Military stalker. In 2012, he was one of the participants in the military assault on ChNPP. Being not far from the nuclear power plant, he decided to withdraw his detachment. This saved the life of him and his people, but from now on, operations in the center of the Zone were not trusted to him. In recent years, Zhuravlev has been working out a contract in the complex of scientists at Agroprom. Some members of his squad left the Zone or changed their place of service. Some are still in the group.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_characters_hero_sky">
    <text>Sky</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_characters_hero_sky_descr">
    <text>Military Stalker. He is one of the members of the Zhuravlev group. He is responsible for the equipment, but is always able to cover fire and perform various other combat operations.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_characters_esc_trader">
    <text>Sidorovich</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_characters_esc_trader_descr">
    <text>Once in a blue moon, you have an exceptionally slimy "gentleman" such as Sidorovich. If you're fifty rubles short of a bandage or anything of the sort, guess what you get? Nothing. A very stingy man indeed, sticking to his principles like shit to a shovel. However, he does keep his word and pays diligently for work, which is how he's earned the respect of clients.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_characters_esc_fanat">
    <text>Fanatic</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_characters_esc_fanat_descr">
    <text>Reclusive but good-hearted stalker. You could say he's the one who helped pave my way across the Cordon. Last year, he and his men saved my life when I nearly got torn to pieces by a pack of blind dogs.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_characters_gar_messenger_friend_1">
    <text>Mitay</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_characters_gar_messenger_friend_1_descr">
    <text>Myslav on Mitay:\n \n%c[ts_pda_color]"I've already mentioned that he was my late brother's friend. My brother's the one who introduced us, but that's besides the point. When we came to the Zone, we worked for Sidorovich for a long time — back then, there was nothing particularly interesting going on. Together we recovered artifacts and split the pay in half... The guy and I hit things off very well.\n \nNow, here's the thing: after the Scorcher was shut down, we made a move for it. I stayed at the Garbage, but Mitay went all the way to the area around Jupiter. After he returned, he told me he had some trouble with the bandits — even ending up in captivity — but he turned out fine in the end after he was rescued by a few stalkers. Oh, and get this: one of them was part of the military... from the USS, I think. What a twist that was!\n \nAnyway, he stuck around for a while and then went the opposite way toward the Zone's outskirts, after which he joined up with the diggers at Agroprom. That's the story of that stalker."</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_characters_gar_messenger_friend_2">
    <text>Tail</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_characters_gar_messenger_friend_2_descr">
    <text>Myslav on Tail:\n \n%c[ts_pda_color]"Interesting guy for sure, though a bit of an oddball. Back then, I met up with them to talk to Mitay. As I told you, they found the documents that day and drank in celebration of their discovery, and Tail suggested I stay when I was getting ready to leave. We hung out and talked about the lives we've made in the Zone. He told me interesting stories about the many places he's seen — a travel-crazy guy for sure. To my surprise, though, he didn't tell me a lot about himself, so I don't know anything else about him. All in all, a good stalker, if a bit closed up..."</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_characters_gar_messenger_friend_3">
    <text>Barin</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_characters_gar_messenger_friend_3_descr">
    <text>Myslav on Barin:\n \n%c[ts_pda_color]"He used to be part of Duty. Not the most likeable type, actually. I suppose we had a good time drinking, but the vibes he gave off... bit too slithery to my liking. I heard he left Duty for unclear reasons, and he still had his service equipment, which he still carries around the Zone. After that, when Mitay told me about him, it turns out I was right: a very greedy and squeamish person who looks for profit around every corner... That's that about Barin. I only saw him once, so I can't tell you anything else."</text>
  </string>
</string_table>
