<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251"?>
<string_table>
  <string id="mlab_start_scientist_first_dialog_0">
    <text>Everything is complete, professor. The artifact is stabilized and ready for transport.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_start_scientist_first_dialog_1">
    <text>Good work.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_start_scientist_first_dialog_2">
    <text>All we have to do is put on the finishing touches. The main credit goes to the stalker who carried out the transmutation.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_start_scientist_first_dialog_3">
    <text>Indeed. I hope he'll continue to assist us in the future. While this lab does contain state-of-the-art equipment, certain selections can only be performed in a natural environment.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_start_scientist_first_dialog_4">
    <text>I wanted to speak to you about that. I've received word that the stalker is dead.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_start_scientist_first_dialog_5">
    <text>Dead? How?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_start_scientist_first_dialog_6">
    <text>One of our assistants heard it from... Termite... himself. I can still barely bring myself to pronounce his name. He killed him, and was quite pleased to inform his own guards about it.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_start_scientist_first_dialog_7">
    <text>Nonsense. Why would he do that?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_start_scientist_first_dialog_8">
    <text>I don't know. But, professor... let's say we've never had this conversation. I wouldn't want the same to happen to our staff.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_start_scientist_first_dialog_9">
    <text>I'll deal with it. Send the artifact to the contractor if it's ready for transport.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_start_scientist_first_dialog_10">
    <text>Understood, professor. See you at testing!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_start_scientist_first_dialog_11">
    <text>See you soon.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_merc_leader_scientist_boss_dialog_0">
    <text>Professor! To what do I owe the honor of your visit?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_merc_leader_scientist_boss_dialog_1">
    <text>Are these rumors true? About the stalker that helped me transmute.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_merc_leader_scientist_boss_dialog_2">
    <text>What rumors exactly?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_merc_leader_scientist_boss_dialog_3">
    <text>That he was killed. By you!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_merc_leader_scientist_boss_dialog_4">
    <text>He got himself killed. He was doing his work and was supposed to give the artifact to us, but we had to come running after him. And I don't like running around! I had to do it, professor; had I not, you would've surely been in the can by now.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_merc_leader_scientist_boss_dialog_5">
    <text>He was a reliable man and proved useful to our future work! We have too few helpers outside of this facility to be wasting resources!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_merc_leader_scientist_boss_dialog_6">
    <text>He was a fool! And, as it happens, I was appointed here to keep your work safe from people like him, who would interfere with our work. Yes, I did it, and the same awaits anyone who'd pose even the slightest threat to us. It's for your own safety, doc.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_merc_leader_scientist_boss_dialog_7">
    <text>...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_merc_leader_scientist_boss_dialog_8">
    <text>Now, now, don't look at me like that. I'm not just some cutthroat. I'm here so that you can work uninterruptedly on the goals set to you by your management. I'm here to prevent armed individuals don't break in here and put you away into jail for a very long time. As long as you're safe, that means I'm getting the job done!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_merc_leader_scientist_boss_dialog_9">
    <text>I ask that you at least discuss this with me in the future!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_merc_leader_scientist_boss_dialog_10">
    <text>By all means, Einstein!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_merc_leader_scientist_boss_dialog_11">
    <text>Perfect!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_start_scientist_after_zombie_scene_dialog_0">
    <text>What do we do, professor?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_start_scientist_after_zombie_scene_dialog_1">
    <text>Keep going! Today only marks our first step! Try to process the data we've received as soon as possible so that we can start making adjustments by tomorrow.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_start_scientist_after_zombie_scene_dialog_2">
    <text>Got it! What do you think, is this achievable? I heard your speech, but it all seems like fantasy to me.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_start_scientist_after_zombie_scene_dialog_3">
    <text>Everything around here is fantasy! I don't know about you, but that's exactly what I'm here for. The people who brought us here believe in fantasy; they believe in us. That means the sky is the limit for us. We just need a bit of time.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_start_scientist_after_zombie_scene_dialog_4">
    <text>Perhaps so. Then I'll get on to work.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_start_scientist_after_zombie_scene_dialog_5">
    <text>Good luck. Keep me informed about everything!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_mid_final_merc_leader_dialog_0">
    <text>Pack your stuff. We're moving.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_mid_final_merc_leader_dialog_1">
    <text>What? Why?!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_mid_final_merc_leader_dialog_2">
    <text>Because! Gather all research data and head to the teleport room. We only have a couple of hours before guests arrive... and only a couple of days before your former bosses find out about this place.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_mid_final_merc_leader_dialog_3">
    <text>How did this happen? Are they onto us?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_mid_final_merc_leader_dialog_4">
    <text>Yes, but we'll relocate ourselves by the time they get here. Don't worry; you'll like the new place.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_mid_final_merc_leader_dialog_5">
    <text>And what about all this equipment? We can't just take it with us!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_mid_final_merc_leader_dialog_6">
    <text>That won't be an issue. You'll get new equipment.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_mid_final_merc_leader_dialog_7">
    <text>So we'll just keep rushing from one laboratory to the next? Is there nothing else we can do?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_mid_final_merc_leader_dialog_8">
    <text>Listen, professor... Zhuravlyov, who's leading the search for you, is following his mission through to the end. Some of his squadmates have already paid the Zone with their lives, and he's out to settle scores.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_mid_final_merc_leader_dialog_9">
    <text>Zhuravlyov, Zhuravlyov... I know him! Could I speak with him? He wasn't on best terms with our management. I'll try to find the right words to convince him.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_mid_final_merc_leader_dialog_10">
    <text>Your call, professor. He'll be here any minute now, so you can have your heart-to-heart talk with him. But if he turns on us, don't even try to hold me back!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_mid_final_merc_leader_dialog_11">
    <text>I understand. I won't.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_scientist_boss_final_first_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_scientist_boss_final_first_dialog_1">
    <text>Professor Dubinin? What are you doing here?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_scientist_boss_final_first_dialog_2">
    <text>I'm working, and I'd rather you didn't interfere.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_scientist_boss_final_first_dialog_3">
    <text>You left the complex and violated your contract, and now you're working for people who don't even take human lives into account. How can I let that slide? You're coming with me!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_scientist_boss_final_first_dialog_4">
    <text>You have strange notions about good and evil, Zhuravlyov! You must've only seen the tip of the iceberg, and being honest with you, I'm not too fond of it myself. Termite, who you've certainly already met, is a terrible man! He may very well have spoiled your impression of us.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_scientist_boss_final_first_dialog_5">
    <text>So who are you people, exactly?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_scientist_boss_final_first_dialog_6">
    <text>We are researchers with the ability to competently manage the opportunities given to humanity by the Zone. The leadership of the scientific complex, to which I sacrificed five years of my career, only pursues its own goals; they have neither the finances nor desire for developments that could become a discovery for the whole world, yet they are are much more willing to pursue military developments! I have no wish to partake in that. Working at the research institute on Agroprom is just going in circles! Dozens of years would pass before research made in the Zone would get used in healthcare and for the benefit of ordinary civilians. That's why I left and continued where my work would be much more useful; where I'd be able to benefit people and not serve as a puppet for military research.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_scientist_boss_final_first_dialog_7">
    <text>And you believe them? You believe they're good guys who'd help the whole world?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_scientist_boss_final_first_dialog_8">
    <text>There's no helping everyone... but we can help those who are willing to pay. Artifacts that we've synthesized in this laboratory have helped heal hundreds of people. Several factories work on their ??? without depleting natural resources. We help the miracles that originate in the Zone reach people, and not just waste away inside the perimiter. Yes, we sell them for money... but that money is invested into further research!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_scientist_boss_final_first_dialog_9">
    <text>As far as I know, the artifacts that end up outside the Zone decay pretty quickly, and their holders become irradiated. You're spreading this infection around the world. How is this acceptable?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_scientist_boss_final_first_dialog_10">
    <text>Zhuravlyov, don't think that I would resort to evil deeds for the sake of money. I'll say it once more. You mistakenly believe that I'm your enemy; that I and all scientists here are enemies of humanity. We combine the properties of artifacts and stabilize their condition. People who have received them at their disposal have ended up satisfied.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_scientist_boss_final_first_dialog_11">
    <text>And now you want to continue your work even further? You can't hide forever!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_scientist_boss_final_first_dialog_12">
    <text>Nothing can be done forever, but we'll try to continue our work as long as possible. That's why I'm the one standing before you right now, and not Termite. I just want to convey to you that you're on the wrong side. That may sound mad right now, but think for a moment: nobody ever got hurt before you started your hunt for us. Nobody else will get hurt if you leave now and note me in your official report as dead. We've achieved a lot in this laboratory in a short time, and we'll manage even more provided time and opportunity. Such results are impossible to reach in the confines of a government-contracted facility, and you understand that, don't you? You and I both have great talents that are of no use to them. Our leadership has given up completely... and however our conversation ends, I won't look back on my departure. Give us the chance to continue our work and you'll soon see for yourself that it's the right choice.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_scientist_boss_final_first_dialog_13_1">
    <text>Leave. But if anyone finds out about you again, I won't be there to help.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_scientist_boss_final_first_dialog_13_2">
    <text>With all due respect, professor Dubinin, you and your new friends have to face the law. Whether you're telling me the truth or not, you picked the wrong path to your goal.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_scientist_boss_final_second_dialog_0">
    <text>Such a shame. You still understand nothing!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_scientist_boss_final_second_dialog_1">
    <text>Here we are again, professor. Where's Termite?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_scientist_boss_final_second_dialog_2">
    <text>He had a one of a kind handheld teleporter. It's hard to even guess where he might be now.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_scientist_boss_final_second_dialog_3">
    <text>I'm very sorry things turned out like this, especially if everything you've said about helping people is true. But I couldn't let you go. I'm not the one who decides your fate.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_scientist_boss_final_second_dialog_4">
    <text>I can decide my own fate. I'm sorry, but you've stolen my dream from me.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_scientist_boss_final_second_dialog_5">
    <text>Wait!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_scientist_laborant_start_dialog_0">
    <text>Please don't kill me!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_scientist_laborant_start_dialog_1">
    <text>Easy. That's not what I'm here for. Why didn't you leave with the others?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_scientist_laborant_start_dialog_2">
    <text>I couldn't! I don't want to be with them anymore, and I don't want to go to prison either!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_scientist_laborant_start_dialog_3">
    <text>Where are they?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_scientist_laborant_start_dialog_4">
    <text>They're in the room with the test tubes, getting ready to teleport. It'll start any second now!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_scientist_laborant_start_dialog_5">
    <text>Teleport? How?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_scientist_laborant_start_dialog_6">
    <text>I don't know. It's one of the developments in this laboratory.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_scientist_laborant_start_dialog_7">
    <text>And where are they teleporting?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_scientist_laborant_start_dialog_8">
    <text>I don't know. They didn't tell us.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_scientist_laborant_start_dialog_9">
    <text>How about this: you help me and I make sure you get out here safe and sound. Deal?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_scientist_laborant_start_dialog_10">
    <text>And then? Will you let me go?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_scientist_laborant_start_dialog_11">
    <text>I will. You're not who I came for.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_scientist_laborant_start_dialog_12">
    <text>Okay. How can I help you?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_scientist_laborant_start_dialog_13">
    <text>I can't let professor Dubinin and Termite disappear. How can I stop them?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_scientist_laborant_start_dialog_14">
    <text>The teleport runs on an energy source. If we cut the power, it'll stop working.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_scientist_laborant_start_dialog_15">
    <text>Could you show me where?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_scientist_laborant_start_dialog_16">
    <text>I'll show you. Just follow me.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_scientist_laborant_start_dialog_17">
    <text>Let's go.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_scientist_laborant_second_dialog_0">
    <text>There's a switch on the wall. You'll manage.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_scientist_laborant_second_dialog_1">
    <text>Great. Wait here and don't move.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_scientist_laborant_final_dialog_0">
    <text>Is that it? Did I do my part?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_scientist_laborant_final_dialog_1">
    <text>You did. Wait here and I'll come back for you later.</text>
  </string>
</string_table>
