<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>
<string_table>
  <string id="val_treasure_1_name">
    <text>Safe</text>
  </string>
  <string id="val_treasure_1_descr">
    <text>I'll put some of my extra stuff in a safe at the factory. Hope no one goes in there.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="val_treasure_2_name">
    <text>Stump near the farm</text>
  </string>
  <string id="val_treasure_2_descr">
    <text>Was scouting with my binoculars when I saw a guy putting stuff in a stump. I'll have to find a moment and take a look when things calm down.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="val_treasure_3_name">
    <text>Box in camp</text>
  </string>
  <string id="val_treasure_3_descr">
    <text>I'll leave the bulk of my stuff in the camp. Just hope the boys keep watch of it!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="val_treasure_4_name">
    <text>Under the cistern</text>
  </string>
  <string id="val_treasure_4_descr">
    <text>I'll just hide some of my stuff in a pipe under the cistern. A perfect spot; no one will notice!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="val_treasure_5_name">
    <text>Log in anomaly</text>
  </string>
  <string id="val_treasure_5_descr">
    <text>I saw this stalker find an artifact and stash it in a log at light speed! Must've been pretty irradiated for him to hide it so quickly. I should check it out — it might just be worthwhile.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="val_treasure_6_name">
    <text>Backpack in bushes</text>
  </string>
  <string id="val_treasure_6_descr">
    <text>I made a stash in some bushes near the old underground passage. Gotta remember to retrieve it after the raid, 'cause I don't want to lose all this stuff.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="val_treasure_7_name">
    <text>Stump in field</text>
  </string>
  <string id="val_treasure_7_descr">
    <text>Tracked down the rat that was stealing stuff from the base! When I get to his lair, I'mma smash the shit out of it.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="val_treasure_8_name">
    <text>My supplies</text>
  </string>
  <string id="val_treasure_8_descr">
    <text>Made a stash with supplies for when SHTF. Just hope no passerby finds it.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="val_treasure_9_name">
    <text>Gag pipe</text>
  </string>
  <string id="val_treasure_9_descr">
    <text>Found an interesting construct. Crawling in is easy, but getting out? Good luck with that. It'll make a nice spot for my spare supplies.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="val_quest_treasure_1_name">
    <text>Supplies</text>
  </string>
  <string id="val_quest_treasure_1_descr">
    <text>I must say, I've been lining my pockets pretty good as of late! I should find a place for my future stashes...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="val_quest_treasure_2_name">
    <text>Piece of pipe</text>
  </string>
  <string id="val_quest_treasure_2_descr">
    <text>There's a nice hidden spot where this stalker was dropping off his loot. Guy's obviously well-off, so that stash deserves a checking out.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="val_quest_treasure_3_name">
    <text>Safe among trash</text>
  </string>
  <string id="val_quest_treasure_3_descr">
    <text>There, now you have access to my safe at the gas station. Don't forget about the guys in the base, they're just waiting to get their hands on any passing stalkers.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="val_quest_treasure_4_name">
    <text>Backpack</text>
  </string>
  <string id="val_quest_treasure_4_descr">
    <text>One of my bros has a stash nearby, he's been ill from a month from overexposure. It's gotta have valuable stuff inside.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="labx18_quest_treasure_1_name">
    <text>Room with flasks</text>
  </string>
  <string id="labx18_quest_treasure_1_descr">
    <text>Made it into the laboratory through the vents. Hearing some strange sounds nearby. I dropped some equipment to lighten the load, and now I'm off to find a way to the surface...</text>
  </string>
</string_table>
