<string_table>
  <string id="agru_fake_bandit_dialog_0">
    <text>Listen, bro, don't suppose you've got a smoke?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agru_fake_bandit_dialog_1">
    <text>I don't smoke. Don't advise you do either.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agru_fake_bandit_dialog_2">
    <text>Oh, you mean you don't get it, chump? Hand over your stuff — you're ours now!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agru_fake_bandit_dialog_3">
    <text>Oh, for Christ's sake...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agru_stalker_help_dialog_0">
    <text>So, which one are ya lugging off? The one with the fat legs or the skinny ones?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agru_stalker_help_dialog_1">
    <text>What?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agru_stalker_help_dialog_2">
    <text>Just pulling your legs. Heh, maybe I should lay off the Cossacks... Anyway, that's that — they didn't make it. May their souls rest in the anomaly. As I promised you, here's your little reward. And if you find yourself in the Bar, come see me. We'll have a chat, drink, smoke and who knows what else.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agru_stalker_help_dialog_3">
    <text>What about these two?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agru_stalker_help_dialog_4">
    <text>Yeah? What about them? Their only purpose now is to furnish the Zone. They're beyond help now. Of course, if you want, you could snatch the weapon. It just so happens that Buzzard bought himself a gun like that recently and rubbed it in everyone's faces. But I don't recommend you go there, 'cause if this keeps up, we'll have ourselves a treasure trove of skeletons.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agru_stalker_help_dialog_5">
    <text>What were they up to anyway?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agru_stalker_help_dialog_6">
    <text>Artifact hunting. Buzzard even found some unique detector for that purpose. He was an experienced stalker... sneaky, rotten, but with tons of experience under his belt. I'm curious just how he managed to bite the dust. He'd usually bring a decoy stalker to do it for him, which is what that skeleton over there once was. Anyway, I hope you fare better.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agru_stalker_help_dialog_7">
    <text>Bye, then...</text>
  </string>
</string_table>
