<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252" ?>
<string_table>
  <string id="kat_unknown_stalker_wounded_dialog_0">
    <text>Son of a bitch...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="kat_unknown_stalker_wounded_dialog_1">
    <text>Man! You okay?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="kat_unknown_stalker_wounded_dialog_2">
    <text>No... It hurts like hell...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="kat_unknown_stalker_wounded_dialog_3">
    <text>What do I do? How can I help?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="kat_unknown_stalker_wounded_dialog_4">
    <text>Just help me bandage this wound, damn it! I'm like a red fountain here!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="kat_unknown_stalker_wounded_dialog_5">
    <text>Right. Just a sec.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="kat_unknown_stalker_dialog_0">
    <text>Agh...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="kat_unknown_stalker_dialog_1">
    <text>Feeling better?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="kat_unknown_stalker_dialog_2">
    <text>I'll live... Hey, did you see him?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="kat_unknown_stalker_dialog_3">
    <text>Who?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="kat_unknown_stalker_dialog_4">
    <text>What do you mean, "who"? The Master, damn it! He's somewhere around here! I was trying to get away from him, but then I slipped on some concrete!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="kat_unknown_stalker_dialog_5">
    <text>I was hearing voices of some kind. Is that the Master?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="kat_unknown_stalker_dialog_6">
    <text>Bingo.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="kat_unknown_stalker_dialog_7">
    <text>Who is he? And how did you end up here?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="kat_unknown_stalker_dialog_8">
    <text>I was grabbing artifacts when I saw a hole. Went inside, and then God knows what started happening... My head started spinning, the rooms started shifting, and I somehow wandered into these godforsaken crypts... I have no idea what place this is, and I sure as hell don't know the way out. Been fumbling around for ages trying to find the exit. How the hell did you get here?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="kat_unknown_stalker_dialog_9">
    <text>Got into a skirmish with bandits. Ran to the first place my legs took me... What is this place? Zombies with lab X-18 tags, strange voices... We need to get out of here. And who is the Master? Why do you call him that?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="kat_unknown_stalker_dialog_10">
    <text>All while I've been in this hell-hole, that creature's made it clear who's the master here. I named him appropriately. He's not letting me go. If he wanted to kill me, he'd have done it long ago, but it's like he's playing with me...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="kat_unknown_stalker_dialog_11">
    <text>What can we do?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="kat_unknown_stalker_dialog_12">
    <text>Listen. I stumbled upon the corpse of some stalker - seems he fell into this trap the same way we did. I found a note on his body, saying...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="kat_unknown_stalker_dialog_13">
    <text>On his body? What happened to him?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="kat_unknown_stalker_dialog_14">
    <text>He shot himself. Poor bastard couldn't take it anymore. Now, that note mentioned that the Master demanded some thing from him in exchange for his freedom, but he wasn't able to reach him for some reason. And that meant the end for him. I was also able to find out that the Master was once an ordinary man, just like us, living in these parts... though, just what kind of man could have such power?...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="kat_unknown_stalker_dialog_15">
    <text>What thing was it he needed?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="kat_unknown_stalker_dialog_16">
    <text>A tiny bag of some sort - the note didn't mention its contents. And it's right here in this damned tunnel. We need to find that bag, give it to him and get the hell out of here!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="kat_unknown_stalker_dialog_17">
    <text>Right, I understand. Where should we look?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="kat_unknown_stalker_dialog_18">
    <text>I've already given this place a look over. There's an area right next to us where part of the village surface is collapsed. I think what he wants is there.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="kat_unknown_stalker_dialog_19">
    <text>We going there, then?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="kat_unknown_stalker_dialog_20">
    <text>I can barely move. Need to rest up a bit, now that my wounds are bandaged. Plus, it's full of anomalies, and I've already had my fill of adventures today. If you don't feel like waiting... go by yourself.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="kat_unknown_stalker_dialog_21">
    <text>I don't plan on staying here any longer. Wait here until I get back.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="kat_unknown_stalker_wait_dialog_0">
    <text>So, did you get it?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="kat_unknown_stalker_wait_dialog_1_1">
    <text>I got it, and I couldn't resist... I read the note, and things are starting to come together.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="kat_unknown_stalker_wait_dialog_1_2">
    <text>Not yet.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="kat_unknown_stalker_wait_dialog_2">
    <text>You shouldn't have...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="kat_unknown_stalker_wait_dialog_3">
    <text>What?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="kat_unknown_stalker_final_dialog_0">
    <text>You should have never read the note.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="kat_unknown_stalker_final_dialog_1">
    <text>What happened?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="kat_unknown_stalker_final_dialog_2">
    <text>You still don't understand, do you?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="kat_unknown_stalker_final_dialog_3">
    <text>The hell... Are you the one who struck me?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="kat_unknown_stalker_final_dialog_4">
    <text>I would've let you free. But your curiousity has convinced me otherwise.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="kat_unknown_stalker_final_dialog_5">
    <text>I don't understand... So you... This is all your doing?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="kat_unknown_stalker_final_dialog_6">
    <text>Yes. I am the Master. And that means the fate of those who wander here are mine to decide.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="kat_unknown_stalker_final_dialog_7">
    <text>I brought you your possessions. That was our deal, wasn't it? Let me go.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="kat_unknown_stalker_final_dialog_8">
    <text>Never were you meant to know anything. And now you have forced my hand.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="kat_unknown_stalker_final_dialog_9">
    <text>So what will happen? What will you do? What happens to the stalker that shot himself, or the bandits that fell at the snap of your fingers? What are you? How can you resent those who've done you nothing?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="kat_unknown_stalker_final_dialog_10">
    <text>All you stalkers are, without exception, to blame for what I've become. You are the children of the Zone, feeding her day by day. She is what turned me into this - she and those greedy scientists, blinded to the world around them by their research.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="kat_unknown_stalker_final_dialog_11">
    <text>What happened to you?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="kat_unknown_stalker_final_dialog_12">
    <text>We lived here in peace until the appearance of the abominable state officials and their primal lust for research. They began constructing laboratories right on our doorstep, and the village populace began to disappear. We could not accept it.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="kat_unknown_stalker_final_dialog_13">
    <text>You lived here? I thought everyone was evacuated after eighty-six.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="kat_unknown_stalker_final_dialog_14">
    <text>Not everyone was prepared to leave their home, their lives and identities, behind... and so about a hundred of us remained. Our lives continued with no grief or regret, nor any regard for the radiation... until they, the alleged "great minds," arrived here. They lied to us all, creating a bunker for the "safety" of those who remained. Behind the curtain, they set out to construct an inhumane laboratory, and those who learned of it were never heard from again. The villagers had not a clue about their fate... but one day, the scientist dogs simply entered our homes and seized our people. It was a nightmare. Those that did not succumb to their wretched experiments or somehow manage to take their own lives were turned into monstrous beings beyond recognition... including myself.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="kat_unknown_stalker_final_dialog_15">
    <text>You look like an ordinary human...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="kat_unknown_stalker_final_dialog_16">
    <text>Don't fool yourself. My current form is just a figment of your imagination.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="kat_unknown_stalker_final_dialog_17">
    <text>I see. Is there perhaps anything else that can be done?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="kat_unknown_stalker_final_dialog_18">
    <text>There is nothing to be done. Beyond the damned walls of the laboratory, I had a wife and daughter. At this moment, I'd more than anything wish to see my daughter's photograph and her reply to me.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="kat_unknown_stalker_final_dialog_19">
    <text>I'm sorry... truly. I could go look for your daughter and hand you her reply. Is that okay?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="kat_unknown_stalker_final_dialog_20">
    <text>Hah! She is better off thinking that I'm dead, as giving her false hope would only worsen things. Nor will you be given any, for that matter... for you, vile stalker, are doomed to remain in these crypts. Were it not for your kind and the cursed intellectuals, everything would remain well. So, my puppet... I bid you a pleasant stay.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="kat_unknown_stalker_final_dialog_21">
    <text>Just you try!</text>
  </string>
</string_table>