<string_table>
  <string id="mkat_merc_leader_dialog_0">
    <text>So, we meet again.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mkat_merc_leader_dialog_1">
    <text>You stayed behind alone? Why didn't you kill me?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mkat_merc_leader_dialog_2">
    <text>I hate to say this, but I need you. What they said about cutting loose the last man is horseshit. I've heard about games like that before, thought it was a bunch of crap, but it's very real. In any case, no one's ever made it out alive, so right now, you and I need to kill those mercenaries or we're next.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mkat_merc_leader_dialog_3">
    <text>So you can stab me in the back later on? Sounds great!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mkat_merc_leader_dialog_4">
    <text>You know... I'll let you get away. Give up on following us and tell your brass that your professor was eaten by a boar, and you'll get to live another day. Cross the line and I can assure you your next breath will be your last.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mkat_merc_leader_dialog_5">
    <text>Who are you folks anyway?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mkat_merc_leader_dialog_6">
    <text>We're the good guys, God as my witness!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mkat_merc_leader_dialog_7">
    <text>"Good guys" wouldn't hang stalkers from the bridge.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mkat_merc_leader_dialog_8">
    <text>That unfortunate stalker is a message to everyone who crosses us. He already tried once, and got what he asked for. I never wanted any of this, all these hits and hangings... but folks around here are stubborn as mules, trying to be heroes when it's just not in their nature. No choice but to remind people like that where they belong: a grave. They had a choice, just like you do now, and they made it. So cut the chit-chat and let's get on with it, or these tunnels will be our grave.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mkat_merc_leader_dialog_9">
    <text>You got a plan? There's only one entrance, which I'm sure is crawling with them.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mkat_merc_leader_dialog_10">
    <text>I noticed a hole not far from here that some mutant dug up — must've smelled the dead bodies. Our best bet is to exit through there, and after that, it's all sleight of hand!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mkat_merc_leader_dialog_11">
    <text>Alright, let's get the hell out of here.</text>
  </string>
</string_table>
