<string_table>
  <string id="labx18_bandits_dialog_first_0">
    <text>We're here.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="labx18_bandits_dialog_first_1">
    <text>Everyone ready?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="labx18_bandits_dialog_first_2">
    <text>Ready. Just don't do anything stupid, 'cause this place has gotta be crawling with muties. We'll have a quick look around, then head outside — I ain't planning on staying for vacation.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="labx18_bandits_dialog_first_3">
    <text>Let's go, then.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="labx18_bandits_dialog_second_0">
    <text>What a mess...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="labx18_bandits_dialog_second_1">
    <text>I'd say we mopped 'em up pretty good! Let's move on.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="labx18_bandits_dialog_second_2">
    <text>Ladies first, comrade.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="labx18_bandits_dialog_second_3">
    <text>What are you talking about?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="labx18_bandits_dialog_second_4">
    <text>What part don't you get, genius? You go down there and check every single inch. Come back and let us know what you find... or at least fatten the muties up so they don't come here. We ain't about to go busting our balls with you.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="labx18_bandits_dialog_second_5">
    <text>Oh, so that's how it's gonna be? And what if I tell your boss you stayed on the top level and dumped me?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="labx18_bandits_dialog_second_6">
    <text>You wanna tell the boss, huh? What if we find a Fruit Punch and hold your face to it for a minute or two? Now, if you don't fancy lookin' like fresh boar roast, I'd suggest you go on ahead, capiche? We'll sit tight here.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="labx18_bandits_dialog_second_7">
    <text>You bastards! I help you clean the factory and this is how you repay me?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="labx18_bandits_dialog_second_8">
    <text>Now look who's talking! Just who in the hell did you "help" over there? We know you were on your ass twiddling your thumbs while our guys were dropping like flies. So don't be coming to me like some knight in shining armor, or I'll shove those plates where the sun don't shine on 'em no more.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="labx18_bandits_dialog_second_9">
    <text>Fine. Have it your way.</text>
  </string>
</string_table>
