<string_table>
  <string id="gar_mishgan_start_help_dialog_0">
    <text>Help me out, man!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_mishgan_start_help_dialog_1">
    <text>What is it? What happened?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_mishgan_start_help_dialog_2">
    <text>I'm in a pinch. Two of my friends were taken captive by bandits. I don't know what the hell they want, 'cause we're short on loot anyway. Help me free them, will you? They're held at the abandoned vehicle park.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_mishgan_start_help_dialog_3">
    <text>How many bandits are in the camp?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_mishgan_start_help_dialog_4">
    <text>Nine of 'em.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_mishgan_start_help_dialog_5">
    <text>You kidding? How do you plan on the two of us grabbing your friends?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_mishgan_start_help_dialog_6">
    <text>Through the element of surprise. I have a plan... two, in fact. So, you helping me? Quid pro quo — I'll pay you, don't worry.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_mishgan_start_help_dialog_7">
    <text>What are our options? Sorry, but if it's something phoney, count me out.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_mishgan_start_help_dialog_8">
    <text>We need to distract the bandits. They'll cause a commotion, and I'll drop 'em from behind. I've got a couple of options: either we enter through the hole in the fence and get 'em from the rear or we climb the hill and shoot down a couple of 'em from there. The rest is simple.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_mishgan_start_help_dialog_9">
    <text>So I'm supposed to distract them? How will I do that?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_mishgan_start_help_dialog_10">
    <text>They won't fire at you — they need stalkers alive for some reason. That's why you'll just go up and talk to them, and in that time, I'll pop a few. Sound good?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_mishgan_start_help_dialog_11">
    <text>"Sound good" my ass! You really think you can carry through with this plan?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_mishgan_start_help_dialog_12">
    <text>I'm sure — just trust me! And, you know... I've got money! I'll give you ten grand in advance. Deal?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_mishgan_start_help_dialog_13_1">
    <text>Alright, deal. Let's just decide first on how you'll be using your sneakiness.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_mishgan_start_help_dialog_13_2">
    <text>Sorry, but I'm not going up against nine bandits, much less as bait. Good luck to you.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_mishgan_start_help_dialog_14">
    <text>As I said, we could sneak through the bushes in the vehicle graveyard itself. Or we could take the hill, where everything is perfectly visible.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_mishgan_start_help_dialog_15_1">
    <text>Let's take the bushes. There's quite the distance between the hill and the bandits, and we don't need to go rambo.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_mishgan_start_help_dialog_15_2">
    <text>It's best we go on the hill. More visibility there.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_mishgan_start_help_dialog_15_3">
    <text>I changed my mind.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_mishgan_start_help_dialog_16">
    <text>Let's go, then!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_mishgan_start_help_dialog_17">
    <text>Let's move!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_mishgan_bandits_complete_0">
    <text>Looks like we did it...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_mishgan_bandits_complete_1">
    <text>He-ey, you're the man! We sure whooped some ass, didn't we?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_mishgan_bandits_complete_2">
    <text>You're not half bad either. Nice acting there!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_mishgan_bandits_complete_3_1">
    <text>And, uh... you can have your money back. I don't feel like taking it.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_mishgan_bandits_complete_3_2">
    <text>Glad to help.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_mishgan_bandits_complete_4_1">
    <text>Thanks, stalker! Maybe the Zone will have us cross paths again. And good deeds are always rewarded. Gotta give you this little present.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_mishgan_bandits_complete_4_2">
    <text>Thanks, stalker. So what made you come to the Garbage? I haven't seen you around here before — need help with anything?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_mishgan_bandits_complete_5_1">
    <text>Thanks! Could you tell me what's there to do in the Garbage? Where could I eat or earn some cash?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_mishgan_bandits_complete_5_2">
    <text>Yeah, it's my first time here. Could you tell me what's there to do in the Garbage? Where could I make a profit?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_mishgan_bandits_complete_6">
    <text>There's really not much to do in this place. My boys and I are thinking of going further, toward the Red Forest — dangerous, but well-paid. But that's for another time — gotta rest. Here, though, I suppose you could work for the local trader. Go see him — he's by the abandoned hangar.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_mishgan_bandits_complete_7">
    <text>Thanks, man. Later.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_mishgan_dialog_final_0">
    <text>God damn — we gotta beat it out of here! We're heading to the hangar, into our base. You with us?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_mishgan_dialog_final_1">
    <text>Yeah, let's move!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_mishgan_dialog_final_2">
    <text>I think I'll be going solo for a bit. Good luck, boys.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_mishgan_default_meet_0">
    <text>Thanks for the help, man. Won't forget it!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_ohrannik_no_dialog_0">
    <text>Who the hell are you? Get on out of here!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_ohrannik_no_dialog_1">
    <text>Well, someone's in a good mood today...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_ohrannik_start_dialog_0">
    <text>Stop right there! Where you headed?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_ohrannik_start_dialog_1">
    <text>Hey! I'd like to see the trader.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_ohrannik_start_dialog_2">
    <text>You can't see him right now. He's busy!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_ohrannik_start_dialog_3">
    <text>Is he gonna be busy for long?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_ohrannik_start_dialog_4">
    <text>Dunno. Crutch was having a visit from some important people. He ain't exactly in the talking mood after seeing them — told me not to let anyone in. So go do something else.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_ohrannik_start_dialog_5">
    <text>I see...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_ohrannik_wait_dialog_0">
    <text>What do you want now? I told you how it is!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_ohrannik_wait_dialog_1">
    <text>I'm leaving.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_ohrannik_dialog_0">
    <text>Where you heading?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_ohrannik_dialog_1">
    <text>To the trader. Is he free?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_ohrannik_dialog_2">
    <text>He's free. Go on in — just don't do anything stupid.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_ohrannik_dialog_3">
    <text>Just let me in, for Christ's sake.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_ohrannik_quest_dialog_0">
    <text>I hope Crutch didn't bite, huh, stalker?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_ohrannik_quest_dialog_1">
    <text>Cranky guy, for sure.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_ohrannik_quest_dialog_2">
    <text>He usually doesn't do business with people he doesn't know; add to that the fact that he's got some rather large problems on his hands, and you can understand why he's like that. Did you see the people who visited him? I heard they were making threats.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_ohrannik_quest_dialog_3">
    <text>Are they competitors?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_ohrannik_quest_dialog_4">
    <text>No damn clue... Hold up! I wanna make you an offer — we'll both come out ahead. We'll make some money together, and you'll get on the trader's good side. Want to hear?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_ohrannik_quest_dialog_5_1">
    <text>Sure. Tell me.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_ohrannik_quest_dialog_5_2">
    <text>I'll drop by later.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_ohrannik_quest_dialog_6">
    <text>There's this small stalker clan that's settled at Agroprom. They seem like they enjoy delving in tunnels underground, searching for all sorts of scrap. Usually, they don't come back with anything of interest, but they managed to dig up some unique documents during one of their last trips.\n \nAs you can understand, tons of potential buyers gathered up. Crutch also offered them some decent money, but they never made a deal... and he really wants those documents. I tried stealing 'em a while back, but they caught me, and now that place is off-limits to me.\n \nMaybe you could try? The trader will be well satisfied, we'll split the pay, and you'll have a good reputation in our camp too. What do you say?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_ohrannik_quest_dialog_7">
    <text>Interesting offer for sure, but how do you suppose I grab their case?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_ohrannik_quest_dialog_8">
    <text>As I said, I got nowhere with it, but I saw a lot while I was there. I'm thinking on how the documents could be stolen... First of all, they keep the case in a safe with a code lock. Second, I know a stalker who knew a bunch of guys from that clan. The clan partially broke up because of some conflict, and a part of the stalkers left — they were no pushovers but experienced stalkers.\n \nSee where I'm going? They must've known the code, and it just so happens that my buddy hangs out with some of them. I'm thinking those who left the clan wouldn't want for their former pals to make any decent sum out of selling the case. I'll take you to my guy and you discuss the rest. Deal?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_ohrannik_quest_dialog_9">
    <text>Sounds good. I'll try.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_ohrannik_quest_dialog_two_0">
    <text>Alright, I talked to him. I've sent you the coordinates to Myslav — go see him and discuss everything.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_ohrannik_quest_dialog_two_1">
    <text>Got it.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_ohrannik_quest_wait_dialog_0">
    <text>Anything new?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_ohrannik_quest_wait_dialog_1_1">
    <text>Not yet. I'm working on it.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_ohrannik_quest_wait_dialog_1_2">
    <text>You bet.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_ohrannik_quest_wait_dialog_2">
    <text>Really? Did you get it?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_ohrannik_quest_wait_dialog_3_1">
    <text>I got it. It went easier than I thought.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_ohrannik_quest_wait_dialog_3_2">
    <text>I got it and all, but they busted me and threw me out of their area. After that, I stole it anyway.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_ohrannik_quest_wait_dialog_3_3">
    <text>I had to drop several men. No idea whether it was worth it...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_ohrannik_quest_wait_dialog_4_1">
    <text>You're really something! High five!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_ohrannik_quest_wait_dialog_4_2">
    <text>Man, you're unbelievable... I knew you'd get it in the end. Great freakin' job!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_ohrannik_quest_wait_dialog_4_3">
    <text>For real? Man, you're an animal. 'Least you got the case...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_ohrannik_quest_wait_dialog_5_1">
    <text>I'm just scared they'll track me down later.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_ohrannik_quest_wait_dialog_5_2">
    <text>This doesn't feel good to me. They'll probably go looking for me.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_ohrannik_quest_wait_dialog_5_3">
    <text>Damn. What's gonna happen next?...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_ohrannik_quest_wait_dialog_6_1_and_2">
    <text>Doubt it. They won't go looking for you beyond Agroprom. Go run into the trader's office — he'll be glad to see your efforts. Don't forget about our mutual deal — the money.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_ohrannik_quest_wait_dialog_6_3">
    <text>Simmer down! Nothing's gonna happen. Bring the case to the trader — he'll be glad to see your efforts. Don't forget about our mutual deal. The money, that is.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_ohrannik_quest_wait_dialog_7">
    <text>I won't.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_desertir_start_dialog_0">
    <text>Stalker, help me out of here...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_desertir_start_dialog_1">
    <text>Hello! What are you doing here?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_desertir_start_dialog_2">
    <text>I didn't think I'd ever sink to this level... but I ran away! I deserted, damn it! Shame on me!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_desertir_start_dialog_3">
    <text>You must've had your reasons, right?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_desertir_start_dialog_4">
    <text>I did. Family problems. I need to go home, but the damn commander won't let me!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_desertir_start_dialog_5">
    <text>Well, you sure ran in the wrong direction!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_desertir_start_dialog_6">
    <text>I know, I know! I don't know my way around this place, so I got lost...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_desertir_start_dialog_7">
    <text>So what do you do now? What are your plans? You're done for once they find you!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_desertir_start_dialog_8">
    <text>I just need to get home, and then whatever happens, happens!... Will you help me?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_desertir_start_dialog_9">
    <text>So you'd just ask any random stranger for help?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_desertir_start_dialog_10">
    <text>But you stalkers help each other...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_desertir_start_dialog_11">
    <text>But you're not a stalker...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_desertir_start_dialog_12">
    <text>Ah, who knows how life will go... What do you say? Will you help me back to the outside?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_desertir_start_dialog_13">
    <text>No-ope! I'm still just a rookie. It's my first time going this far.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_desertir_start_dialog_14">
    <text>I'll pay you! Take everything I have!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_desertir_start_dialog_15_1">
    <text>Alright. I have an idea.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_desertir_start_dialog_15_2">
    <text>Sorry. No time.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_desertir_second_dialog_0">
    <text>Well?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_desertir_second_dialog_1">
    <text>There's a guide waiting for us at the big gate. You ready?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_desertir_second_dialog_2">
    <text>I'm ready!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_desertir_second_dialog_3">
    <text>Let's go, then!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_jurok_desertir_0">
    <text>Hey!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_jurok_desertir_1">
    <text>Hey there! Here's your customer!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_jurok_desertir_2">
    <text>A soldier? You sure about him, Axe?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_jurok_desertir_3">
    <text>Don't worry. He's a deserter and won't cause any trouble. Promised a handsome fee. I think you two could strike a deal.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_jurok_desertir_4">
    <text>I'll take him through the second route, through the pipes, not far from here. The people here just finished clearing out the blockage there, so the path is clear. I hope I don't regret this...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_jurok_desertir_5">
    <text>You won't. Later!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_ambush_dialog_0">
    <text>Listen, stalker, what's going on? Why's that soldier with you? Or are you with him?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_ambush_dialog_1_1">
    <text>Ease up, guys. It's just a buddy of mine — we snatched it from a soldier. Good armor, I tell you.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_ambush_dialog_1_2">
    <text>Are you two complete idiots? Stalkers are gonna shoot you first and ask questions later! Soon as they see an army uniform in their sight — bang, you're gone. Use your head, you morons!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_ambush_dialog_1_3">
    <text>Didn't think about that. Thanks, guys!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_ambush_dialog_1_4">
    <text>Wait... Something's off here. His armor's all new — no fighting traces!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_ambush_dialog_1_5">
    <text>You just gotta know where to shoot.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_ambush_dialog_1_6">
    <text>You're right about that.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_ambush_dialog_2_1">
    <text>None of your business, buster. Turn around and scram on out of here!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_ambush_dialog_2_2">
    <text>You got a lot of balls. What's the matter with you?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_ambush_dialog_2_3">
    <text>What's the matter with *me*? You're the ones who held us up and started hassling us! Why do you care why I'm with a soldier, and what even makes you think he is a soldier? Now, you get out of our way and stay out of our way, or else...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_ambush_dialog_2_4">
    <text>Alright, then. Let's back out of here, boys. Let 'em get what's coming to 'em.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_ambush_dialog_2_5">
    <text>Good riddance.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_ambush_dialog_3_1">
    <text>Stand down, guys — he's alright. He deserted his unit and asked me to lead him out of the Zone.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_ambush_dialog_3_2">
    <text>Who's alright? *He's* alright? I don't give two shits what you have to say about him! Those army dipshits rob us blind, and now we're supposed to forgive them? You crooked bastard!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_ambush_dialog_3_3">
    <text>Chill! He doesn't want us any trouble — he offered to pay!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_ambush_dialog_3_4">
    <text>Yeah? Then give us half!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_ambush_dialog_3_5">
    <text>Give you half? Were you dropped on your head or something?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_ambush_dialog_3_6">
    <text>You think? Then we'll just take it ourselves!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_ambush_dialog_3_7">
    <text>What's with you?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_ambush_dialog_4_1">
    <text>I'm a guide. That's what I do — lead people around.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_ambush_dialog_4_2">
    <text>This is a soldier we're talking about! Those asswipes grab our artifacts and money, and you're working for him!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_ambush_dialog_4_3">
    <text>I don't give a rat's ass who he is and what he's done. They pay, I lead — simple as that.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_ambush_dialog_4_4">
    <text>What if it's a setup so he can ice you for all the stalking you've done?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_ambush_dialog_4_5">
    <text>If it's like that and I feel something's not right, I'll put a bullet in his head myself. Either way, it doesn't concern you, so relax.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_ambush_dialog_4_6">
    <text>Your funeral, buddy. Just don't bring him anywhere near the camp. Got that?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_ambush_dialog_4_7">
    <text>Of course.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dyatlov_start_0">
    <text>Who the hell are you?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dyatlov_start_1">
    <text>No one. Just a stalker.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dyatlov_start_2">
    <text>Then I say: get out of here, stalker.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dyatlov_start_3">
    <text>You seem uptight... Is Duty always like that? I'm looking for work, and I thought you could help me...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dyatlov_start_4">
    <text>We have our own men to carry out our missions, so you're in the wrong place.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dyatlov_start_5">
    <text>That's unfortunate. Thanks anyway...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dyatlov_start_6">
    <text>Uh... Wait up! I do have something for you. There's this one problem that needs solving, and we need someone that's not from our camp.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dyatlov_start_7">
    <text>If it's dirty work, count me out.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dyatlov_start_8">
    <text>Trust me, that's not how we do things. It's something else.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dyatlov_start_9">
    <text>I'm listening.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dyatlov_start_10">
    <text>Don't take us for a bunch of lunatics, but every night, we have some strange things happening. The boys from the outpost are reporting sounds at night, as if someone's walking around the camp — sniffling, whispering, breathing down their necks... It's making them mighty uncomfortable.\n \nI didn't believe it either until I witnessed it myself. Happened a couple of days ago — I was taking a nap, and then I felt someone breathing behind me. Turned around — nothing... I was ready to shit myself right then and there. Nothing in the Zone's ever creeped me out like that, and it happens again and again every night. Everyone's feeling more and more uneasy by the day, and that gives cause to undue worry and conversation subjects in the outpost.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dyatlov_start_11">
    <text>I might've not been in the Zone for long, but I've learned anything could happen here! Anyway, how can I help?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dyatlov_start_12">
    <text>You're new around here. We need your second opinion: is there really something unnatural about this place or are we all just crazy? Or is it just one of the soldiers pranking us?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dyatlov_start_13">
    <text>I suppose I'll need to keep watch on the camp at night.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dyatlov_start_14">
    <text>Could you do it tonight? It's up to you, but I can guarantee you a reward and free entry to the Bar. You must've not been there yet; the Bar is a great place for resting up and finding work.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dyatlov_start_15_1">
    <text>Then tonight we'll see what happens.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dyatlov_start_15_2">
    <text>Let's do it later, commander.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dyatlov_start_two_0">
    <text>So, stalker, do you want to work with us?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dyatlov_start_two_1_1">
    <text>Let's see what's happening here, commander.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dyatlov_start_two_1_2">
    <text>I'll come by later.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_zastava_dolg_soldier_ghost_0">
    <text>What do you need, man?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_zastava_dolg_soldier_ghost_1">
    <text>Aren't you supposed to sleep? Are you guarding the fire?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_zastava_dolg_soldier_ghost_2">
    <text>Yeah, right, as if falling asleep here is a thing... When all this crap started, I forgot what a good night's sleep is. I'm scared of all this shit. I'm on edge from not sleeping, and I'm not the only one. I'm thinking of asking command to shift me to the Bar — it's a lot quieter there.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_zastava_dolg_soldier_ghost_3">
    <text>What do you think is happening here at night?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_zastava_dolg_soldier_ghost_4">
    <text>Beats me. Maybe our food was stuffed with psychotropic substances? Could be those Freedom jackasses, playing with us and waiting until we lose it. Drugs... It's just like them.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_zastava_dolg_soldier_ghost_5">
    <text>Forgive me, but that's just being paranoid.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_zastava_dolg_soldier_ghost_6">
    <text>I'm just laying down all options. There has to be some explanation to all of this.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_zastava_dolg_soldier_ghost_7">
    <text>When did these things last happen in the camp?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_zastava_dolg_soldier_ghost_8">
    <text>To be honest with you?... I don't know. Something definitely happened here a few times — it was hard not to notice. But I've been seeing this thing every single night. My gut tells me it's here right now.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_zastava_dolg_soldier_ghost_9">
    <text>Relax. There's no one here. I'll sit here with you, and we'll check whether you're out of your mind or if there really is something at play here.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dyatlov_smoke_relax_0">
    <text>What's going on?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dyatlov_smoke_relax_1">
    <text>Wake up!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dyatlov_smoke_relax_2">
    <text>What? What is it?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dyatlov_smoke_relax_3">
    <text>I heard it! I saw something! I don't know what's going on here, but I damn near had a heart attack!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dyatlov_smoke_relax_4">
    <text>Is it gone?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dyatlov_smoke_relax_5">
    <text>Yes. Can't hear it anymore. There's definitely nothing wrong with you, nor is it anyone's prank!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dyatlov_smoke_relax_6">
    <text>Well, shit... What is that thing, really?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dyatlov_smoke_relax_7">
    <text>No idea, but staying here gives me the creeps.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dyatlov_smoke_relax_8">
    <text>We need to deal with this... What do we do?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dyatlov_smoke_relax_9">
    <text>I'm gonna see the trader in the abandoned hangar first thing in the morning — I see the stalkers have themselves a nice camp there. I'll ask them about this and see whether they've experienced the same thing.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dyatlov_smoke_relax_10">
    <text>Good thinking! I'll ask my men for now. Maybe they have some details.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dyatlov_smoke_relax_11">
    <text>See you later.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_base_dialog_zastava_dolg_1_0">
    <text>What is it, stalker?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_base_dialog_zastava_dolg_1_1">
    <text>Hey! I want to ask you some questions about the Duty outpost.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_base_dialog_zastava_dolg_1_2">
    <text>What does that have to do with me? I'm just a stalker with no ties to Duty.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_base_dialog_zastava_dolg_1_3">
    <text>Have you heard anything strange about their outpost? Any talks or rumors you know of?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_base_dialog_zastava_dolg_1_4">
    <text>Don't think I've heard any talks or rumors. What's your interest in it? What happened there?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_base_dialog_zastava_dolg_1_5">
    <text>I want to know as much as you do... Right, bye!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_base_dialog_zastava_dolg_2_0">
    <text>Hello. What do you need?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_base_dialog_zastava_dolg_2_1">
    <text>Hey! Could I ask you about the Duty outpost at the Garbage?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_base_dialog_zastava_dolg_2_2">
    <text>Well, ask away. I don't get why you're turning to me, though...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_base_dialog_zastava_dolg_2_3">
    <text>There are lots of strange things happened there. I've been tasked with getting to the bottom of it.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_base_dialog_zastava_dolg_2_4">
    <text>Ah, yeah! I've heard about that! Isn't that just some made-up story?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_base_dialog_zastava_dolg_2_5">
    <text>I don't think that's the case...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_base_dialog_zastava_dolg_2_6">
    <text>Well, sucks for you. They played you like a fiddle and you fell for it!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_base_dialog_zastava_dolg_2_7">
    <text>Well, thanks...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_base_dialog_zastava_dolg_3_0">
    <text>Hello there.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_base_dialog_zastava_dolg_3_1">
    <text>Hey! Could I ask you something?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_base_dialog_zastava_dolg_3_2">
    <text>Shoot!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_base_dialog_zastava_dolg_3_3">
    <text>I've been entrusted with finding out what's happening at the Duty outpost. Some real strange stuff is happening there, so I'm asking everyone here. Maybe someone knows about it?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_base_dialog_zastava_dolg_3_4">
    <text>Anything can happen in the Zone! I've heard stories about the outpost, but they don't make much sense. They say all kinds of stuff happen there at night — strange stuff. We even try not to get too close there. I don't know if there's really anything behind it, though.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_base_dialog_zastava_dolg_3_5">
    <text>That's unfortunate...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_base_dialog_zastava_dolg_3_6">
    <text>I suggest you talk to Korvalol. He's been digging into it for some time, and he must've found out something.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_base_dialog_zastava_dolg_3_7">
    <text>Where can I find him?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_base_dialog_zastava_dolg_3_8">
    <text>He went off to find loot. He's gotta be somewhere in the Garbage. Look around the field by the flea market.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dyatlov_task_in_process_0">
    <text>Stalker, any news on what's going on?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dyatlov_task_in_process_1">
    <text>Not yet. I'm still on it.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_corvalol_dolg_zastava_0">
    <text>Well? What do you need?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_corvalol_dolg_zastava_1">
    <text>Hey there, artifact hunters!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_corvalol_dolg_zastava_2">
    <text>Hello, hello... Need anything?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_corvalol_dolg_zastava_3">
    <text>I do, to be honest. The folks in the camp told me you might know more about what's happening at the Duty outpost.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_corvalol_dolg_zastava_4">
    <text>What "happenings"?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_corvalol_dolg_zastava_5">
    <text>Well, you know, strange stuff happening... I think you know full well what I mean.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_corvalol_dolg_zastava_6">
    <text>Why do you want to know?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_corvalol_dolg_zastava_7">
    <text>Duty asked me to get to the bottom of it, so any clue might help. Any! Even just the littlest things.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_corvalol_dolg_zastava_8">
    <text>I don't get this! When I asked Duty about it, they damn near threatened me to keep my mouth shut and stay out of it.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_corvalol_dolg_zastava_9">
    <text>Really? Is that what they told you?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_corvalol_dolg_zastava_10">
    <text>Well, not exactly that. A rumor passed through our camp that all kinds of crazy stuff was happening at the outpost. Like they were seeing ghosts at night. Now, that kind of stuff really gets me hooked — maybe that's why I got into the Zone in the first place, 'cause I like mysteries. Dealing with them is frightening, sure, but also hella interesting.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_corvalol_dolg_zastava_11">
    <text>What happened next?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_corvalol_dolg_zastava_12">
    <text>I thought, "Is this real? I'm gonna find out." I arrived at their camp and asked them if I could sleep over under their protection. They allowed it... and after I went to sleep, I woke up at night feeling like someone was watching me. I open my eyes and see something in front of me, like a black smoke. Really thick. I stood up, and the smoke evaporated.\n \nI had no idea what that was, and it was clear there was something real mysterious going on. Maybe a new anomaly or some new type of poltergeist. Either way, it creeped me out. Even now, when I think about it, I get the chills.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_corvalol_dolg_zastava_13">
    <text>What did you do then?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_corvalol_dolg_zastava_14">
    <text>What could I do? In the morning, I went to talk to the Duty fighters, and many of them confirmed that something was wrong and that they were constantly being terrorized by something mysterious. It didn't cause any harm, but had them real frightened.\n \nI decided to delve into it. I managed to get one of them to talk, and he shared an interesting thought with me: apparently, it's the ghost of a missing fighter of theirs. Two months ago, he went missing, and that's when all of it started happening. His soul comes up to the camp he was stationed at. When I tried learning about his name or any details about his disappearance, naturally, everyone kept their mouth shut. So I left it.\n \nThat same night, I head back to the stalker camp after going after loot, and then this Duty guy stands there waiting for me. He said, "Listen here, buddy: mind your own business and keep your nose out of Duty's." So I backed off. I steer clear of that place — who knows what they'll do to me otherwise.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_corvalol_dolg_zastava_15">
    <text>Is that so?... Who was that Duty guy? Do you remember?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_corvalol_dolg_zastava_16">
    <text>He was wearing a black mask. Can't tell you for sure, but judging by how he spoke, he's got some experience under his belt — ain't his first day in Duty.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_corvalol_dolg_zastava_17">
    <text>Thanks, you've been a big help! Good hunting, stalker!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dolg_zastava_dyatlov_info_soldier_0">
    <text>Hello. How's the investigation going?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dolg_zastava_dyatlov_info_soldier_1">
    <text>Hello. I have a few leads, but I'll need your help.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dolg_zastava_dyatlov_info_soldier_2">
    <text>Say what you need.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dolg_zastava_dyatlov_info_soldier_3">
    <text>One of your men was threatening a stalker for him not to look into the truth behind what's happening here. I'd like to know who that was.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dolg_zastava_dyatlov_info_soldier_4">
    <text>Out of the question! None of my squadmates go behind my back. I've been through a lot with each and every one of them.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dolg_zastava_dyatlov_info_soldier_5">
    <text>Nevertheless, I think it has to do with the disappearance of one of your soldiers.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dolg_zastava_dyatlov_info_soldier_6">
    <text>So you know about that too? I commend you. Yes, one of my men did go missing: private Galushkin. He was a good, responsible fella — I had plans on making him my right hand. But I seem to be missing what it has to do with this.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dolg_zastava_dyatlov_info_soldier_7">
    <text>The stalker he was threatening asked questions about the soldier's disappearance. Could you tell me more about what happened?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dolg_zastava_dyatlov_info_soldier_8">
    <text>If only I had anything to tell you. I don't really know myself... We had intel on a Freedom stash hidden in the forest, and a three-man squad was assigned to check it. Only two of them returned.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dolg_zastava_dyatlov_info_soldier_9">
    <text>What happened?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dolg_zastava_dyatlov_info_soldier_10">
    <text>At some point, Galushkin fell out of sight and vanished into thin air. My men tried finding him, but without success. We have no clue where he went off too... Maybe he deserted us; I'm not ruling that out.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dolg_zastava_dyatlov_info_soldier_11">
    <text>Where are those other two men now?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dolg_zastava_dyatlov_info_soldier_12">
    <text>Stetsurin left us... He went back to the outside. Averyanov's with us here in the outpost — you can talk to him if necessary.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dolg_zastava_dyatlov_info_soldier_13">
    <text>I'll do that.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dolg_zastava_aver_dialog_0">
    <text>What is it?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dolg_zastava_aver_dialog_1">
    <text>Hello there! Your commander told me I could ask you a few questions.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dolg_zastava_aver_dialog_2">
    <text>Ah... You're that guy who decided to deal with our little "problem." I don't know how I can be of help, though — I'm not the best with anomalies.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dolg_zastava_aver_dialog_3">
    <text>You think it's an anomaly?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dolg_zastava_aver_dialog_4">
    <text>What else? I don't believe in ghosts, and I don't suggest you do either.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dolg_zastava_aver_dialog_5">
    <text>Well, anything can happen...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dolg_zastava_aver_dialog_6">
    <text>No need to shove that "Anything can happen in the Zone" stuff in my face. There's a reasonable explanation for everything.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dolg_zastava_aver_dialog_7">
    <text>You seem on edge today.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dolg_zastava_aver_dialog_8">
    <text>What do you want? Just ask your questions — I don't have the time for this.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dolg_zastava_aver_dialog_9">
    <text>Alright. Tell me what happened to Galushkin?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dolg_zastava_aver_dialog_10">
    <text>What does that have to do with this? I have nothing to tell you! I reported everything to the commander.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dolg_zastava_aver_dialog_11">
    <text>So you have nothing to add? What's your opinion on his disappearance?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dolg_zastava_aver_dialog_12">
    <text>He deserted us! There's no other option. He waited for the right moment and separated from us.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dolg_zastava_aver_dialog_13">
    <text>Anything else?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dolg_zastava_aver_dialog_14">
    <text>I've already told you everything!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dolg_zastava_aver_dialog_15">
    <text>Okay, then. You do your thing. Might want to take off that mask — it's hot today...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dolg_zastava_dyatlov_forest_scene_0">
    <text>So? Did you learn anything?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dolg_zastava_dyatlov_forest_scene_1_0">
    <text>Not yet.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dolg_zastava_dyatlov_forest_scene_1_1">
    <text>I think I have news for you.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dolg_zastava_dyatlov_forest_scene_2">
    <text>What is it? What did you learn?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dolg_zastava_dyatlov_forest_scene_3">
    <text>At this point, I'm positive your camp is haunted by the ghost of Galushkin, no matter how strange it sounds. I examined the area where he disappeared and found his body at the bottom of a well — your subordinates must've pushed him into it.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dolg_zastava_dyatlov_forest_scene_4">
    <text>Don't be stupid. How can you be so sure?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dolg_zastava_dyatlov_forest_scene_5">
    <text>When I was in the forest, by the well, something happened to me. I saw the ghost, and it made everything clear to me.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dolg_zastava_dyatlov_forest_scene_6">
    <text>Bullshit!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dolg_zastava_dyatlov_forest_scene_7">
    <text>Alright... Then think about it yourself: what kind of treatment did he face among his peers? If I had to guess, I don't think anyone took a liking to him — you trusted him more than the others, and many thought he didn't deserve it at all.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dolg_zastava_dyatlov_forest_scene_8">
    <text>Well, I find that hard to believe...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dolg_zastava_dyatlov_forest_scene_9">
    <text>Then ask Averyanov. When I talked to him, he clearly got nervous. He must be hiding something. Where is he now?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dolg_zastava_dyatlov_forest_scene_10">
    <text>I don't know. He should be here.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dolg_zastava_dyatlov_forest_scene_11">
    <text>So he ran off? I told you. And you're all like, "Bullshit! Bullshit!"</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dolg_zastava_dyatlov_forest_scene_12">
    <text>I still don't believe it! Is this really what happened? He was my right hand — he never let me or anyone down once. I don't believe it!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dolg_zastava_dyatlov_forest_scene_13">
    <text>An innocent man wouldn't hide.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dolg_zastava_dyatlov_forest_scene_14">
    <text>True. That explains why Stetsurin would leave Duty: his conscience got the better of him.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dolg_zastava_dyatlov_forest_scene_15">
    <text>He's not the only one. What will you do? You going to let that guy off like that too?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dolg_zastava_dyatlov_forest_scene_16">
    <text>No. This won't go unpunished... His PDA is still pinging! Find him — I guarantee you Duty's gratitude!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dolg_zastava_dyatlov_forest_scene_17">
    <text>I'll try.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dolg_zastava_dialog_final_0">
    <text>So? Where's Averyanov? Did you find him?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dolg_zastava_dialog_final_1_1">
    <text>It's over. Averyanov's dead. Or not... In any case, he's no longer part of our world. Your fighter got his revenge, despite already being dead. I can't really explain it.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dolg_zastava_dialog_final_1_2">
    <text>It's over. Averyanov's dead.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dolg_zastava_dialog_final_2_1">
    <text>Well, call me a whirligig and twist my guts! I can't even wrap my head around it... You're amazing, man. Thanks. I hope we'll stop seeing things at night? Whatever, let's forget about it.\n \nLet's settle your reward: I have an old Abakan with a few attachments, some weathered body armor — just gotta patch it up and it'll be as good as new — or just good old cash. What do you choose?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dolg_zastava_dialog_final_2_2">
    <text>Thanks, stalker. I hope we'll stop seeing things at night. So it really was Galushkin's ghost looking for revenge? Whatever, let's forget about it.\n \nLet's settle your reward. First off, you're free to enter the Bar at any time. I also have an old Abakan with a few attachments, some weathered body armor — just gotta patch it up and it'll be as good as new — or just good old cash. What do you choose?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dolg_zastava_dialog_final_3_1">
    <text>Give me the gun.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dolg_zastava_dialog_final_3_2">
    <text>Body armor? I'll take that!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dolg_zastava_dialog_final_3_3">
    <text>I'm fine with money, commander.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dolg_zastava_dialog_final_4_1">
    <text>Good choice. Here you go! Come by anytime, and godspeed to you.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dolg_zastava_dialog_final_4_2">
    <text>That's right — protection first! Come by when you feel like it, stalker. Good luck.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dolg_zastava_dialog_final_4_3">
    <text>Well, it's your loss, but also your choice. Thanks again for the help. Good luck to you.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dolg_zastava_dialog_final_5">
    <text>Bye, commander!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_trader_first_dialog_0">
    <text>Hm? What do you want?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_trader_first_dialog_1">
    <text>Hello there! I'm looking for work, and was hoping you could help.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_trader_first_dialog_2">
    <text>Ah, another one... Where do you people get the idea that I've got work just because I'm a trader? That's just what I am: a trader, not an HR manager. If you're interested in any wares, buy them. If not, I won't keep you here. I don't hand out work, especially to newcomers.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_trader_first_dialog_3">
    <text>I see you're not in the mood.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_trader_first_dialog_4">
    <text>I believe I made myself perfectly clear! Will you be buying anything?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_trader_first_dialog_5">
    <text>I'll get my supplies elsewhere. Have a nice day.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_trader_second_dialog_0">
    <text>I believe we've stated our intents, haven't we? What else do you need?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_trader_second_dialog_1">
    <text>Nothing. I'm leaving.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_task_kill_tonnel_bandits_1">
    <text>Got any more work?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_task_kill_tonnel_bandits_2">
    <text>I've got a simple task. There's a bunch of stinking bandits in the tunnel that needs taken care of. Will you do it?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_task_kill_tonnel_bandits_3">
    <text>I'll try.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_task_kill_tonnel_bandits_4">
    <text>No. I'm not killing anyone.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_task_kill_tonnel_bandits_reward_1">
    <text>The bandits won't be troubling you anymore.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_task_kill_tonnel_bandits_reward_2">
    <text>Attaboy! Here's your reward!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_task_kill_tonnel_bandits_reward_3">
    <text>If anything else comes up, let me know.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_trader_case_dialog_0">
    <text>What do you need?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_trader_case_dialog_1">
    <text>Hey there, Crutch!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_trader_case_dialog_2">
    <text>You again? What is it this time?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_trader_case_dialog_3">
    <text>I've got something for you. Have a look.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_trader_case_dialog_4">
    <text>Is that... No way!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_trader_case_dialog_5">
    <text>You're welcome, you're welcome.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_trader_case_dialog_6">
    <text>Well now, stalker... rarely am I this impressed! I've been looking for these documents for ages!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_trader_case_dialog_7">
    <text>They're yours now. Not only am I hoping for a reward, but also for good relations between us.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_trader_case_dialog_8">
    <text>No problem at all — I'll pay you ten thousand and give you a good backpack. I'm sorry, but that's all I can give you right now. I'm having difficult days, and I need every coin I can get right now.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_trader_case_dialog_9">
    <text>What happened?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_trader_case_dialog_10">
    <text>Doesn't matter. What matters is that you're gonna make money. I'll be able to throw you some work every now and then if I have any.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_trader_case_dialog_11">
    <text>Suits me.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_trader_case_dialog_12">
    <text>Come back later and I'll have something for you. In the meantime, go see our medic, Gamzat. I'll tell him you can be trusted.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_trader_case_dialog_13">
    <text>Got it.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_patron_money_dialog_0">
    <text>So, did the trader pay you?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_patron_money_dialog_1">
    <text>He paid me, but not much. As I understand it, he's got financial problems right now.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_patron_money_dialog_2">
    <text>So I've heard. The deal's still on, right? Got my cut?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_patron_money_dialog_3_1">
    <text>Yeah. Here.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_patron_money_dialog_3_2">
    <text>You know, I was just thinking... Why do both of us get paid when I'm the only one risking my ass? No, I'm keeping it for myself. So long.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_patron_money_dialog_3_3">
    <text>See, it just so happens I spent all the dough at the counter...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_patron_money_dialog_4_1">
    <text>Great job, stalker. Come by whenever you get the chance. Godspeed!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_patron_money_dialog_4_2">
    <text>Oh, so that's how it's gonna be! You'll pay for that sooner or later. Don't let the hangar door hit you in the ass.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_patron_money_dialog_5_1">
    <text>See you.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_patron_money_dialog_5_2">
    <text>I won't.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_medic_idle_dialog_0_1">
    <text>Hey there, stalker. How are you holding up?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_medic_idle_dialog_0_2">
    <text>Hi, stalker.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_medic_idle_dialog_0_3">
    <text>Come for medical assistance?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_drunk_medic_idle_dialog_0_1">
    <text>Hey, man.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_drunk_medic_idle_dialog_0_2">
    <text>Great to see ya.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_drunk_medic_idle_dialog_0_3">
    <text>Hey...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_medic_need_health_care_0">
    <text>I need medical help.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_medic_need_health_care_1">
    <text>Let's see what we've got...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_medic_need_health_care_2">
    <text>Everything's fine with you, stalker!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_medic_need_health_care_3">
    <text>[continue...]</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_medic_need_health_care_4">
    <text>Done. Take it easy, now!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_medic_job_dialog_0">
    <text>Hi! Crutch told me you could offer some work.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_medic_job_dialog_1">
    <text>He told me about you just now. Said you're a reliable guy, by all accounts, and that you can be trusted. Did he tell you what I do?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_medic_job_dialog_2">
    <text>You're a doctor, right?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_medic_job_dialog_3">
    <text>Kind of, but that's just my profession. My hobby, though, is something altogether different.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_medic_job_dialog_4">
    <text>I wonder where this is going...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_medic_job_dialog_5">
    <text>I'm interested in the study of mutations in the Zone. Specifically in mutants.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_medic_job_dialog_6">
    <text>And here I was thinking something else... What is it you do, exactly?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_medic_job_dialog_7">
    <text>I'll tell you everything, and I'll even give you a first-hand look... if you're trustworthy, of course. That's what we're gonna check.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_medic_job_dialog_8">
    <text>Is the sum appropriate?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_medic_job_dialog_9">
    <text>You won't regret it.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_medic_job_dialog_10">
    <text>Then I'm all ears.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_medic_job_dialog_11">
    <text>We need to lure an adult bloodsucker out of its lair. You'll distract it and make it come toward you, and I'll fire at with it a tranquilizer.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_medic_job_dialog_12">
    <text>You want to catch a live bloodsucker? That's one hell of a hobby, and I'm not liking my role in it! I've already been a decoy once, and it wasn't the most fun experience.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_medic_job_dialog_13">
    <text>Trust me when I say it's worth it. I'll have lots to share with you about mutants after it's done... Don't be afraid. Pretty much all you have to do is lure out the mutant and quickly run to the side. I won't miss with the dart, and I'll put it to sleep. The risks are minimal.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_medic_job_dialog_14">
    <text>Sorry, but I have to ask: how much are you paying?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_medic_job_dialog_15">
    <text>If you value money more than information and knowledge on mutants, I won't let you down: ten thousand. No one here in the Garbage is going to find you work that pays better.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_medic_job_dialog_16_1">
    <text>I'm in. Let's head off.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_medic_job_dialog_16_2">
    <text>Deal, but I have to finish up some things first. I'll return soon.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_medic_job_dialog_two_0">
    <text>I'm ready. Let's go.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_medic_hunt_dialog_0">
    <text>The bloodsucker was hanging around somewhere in the lowlands, behind my back. I'll climb up here while you bring it toward me. As soon as I see the thing, I'll knock it out at once. Just be careful — the Duty outpost is nearby, and the area around it is mined. Go!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_medic_hunt_dialog_1">
    <text>Well, cross your fingers!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_trader_good_idle_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello. Do you need anything?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_trader_bandits_job_0">
    <text>Hi! Got anything of interest for sale? Just don't make it too expensive.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_trader_bandits_job_1">
    <text>Anything your heart desires. Weapons, outfits, supplies... You want good, I give you good!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_trader_bandits_job_2">
    <text>Let me see. It's about time I update my equipment.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_trader_bandits_job_3">
    <text>By the way, I've got a little job for you. Gamzat told me you did good, so I'd like to trust you with this.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_trader_bandits_job_4">
    <text>Did he happen to tell you that a bloodsucker almost ripped my shoulder off?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_trader_bandits_job_5">
    <text>Oh, come on now. Just a few scrapes and bruises. In any case, either you take this job or I offer it to somebody else. You won't be unloading train cars, so don't worry about your pretty shoulder. Here, have some — it'll make you feel better.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_trader_bandits_job_6">
    <text>Alright. Tell me what's up.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_trader_bandits_job_7">
    <text>There's a small bandit base in the Dark Valley. We've established a profitable trading relationship: I buy artifacts from them, and it's time I have my next delivery of loot picked up. All you have to do is go there, talk to their leader Mongol, and pick up the artifact case.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_trader_bandits_job_8">
    <text>You're doing business with the bandits? They're as crazy as it gets!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_trader_bandits_job_9">
    <text>The people in the Dark Valley are mostly decent. They have their share of rabble and street garbage, but those types don't usually last long there, so don't worry your head about it. Still, be careful around them.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_trader_bandits_job_10">
    <text>Do I need to pay them for the case?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_trader_bandits_job_11">
    <text>Here. Take this and pay them, then get the artifacts. Be careful not to squander it, or you'll be paying up with your own cash.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_trader_bandits_job_12">
    <text>Got it. I'm off!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_messenger_dialog_0">
    <text>Thanks, man. I would've been mutant dinner by now!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_messenger_dialog_1">
    <text>Oh, please. Anyone would've done the same. Shooter sent me. What's this about the case?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_messenger_dialog_2">
    <text>He must've told you about the clan collapsing, right? I know some of the stalkers that left, and I think one of them knows the safe code.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_messenger_dialog_3">
    <text>Alright. Where do I look for them?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_messenger_dialog_4">
    <text>That's the hard part. I can't get you in direct touch, but I do know where they usually hang out.\n \nThe first one, Mitay, was a friend of my late brother — they were great buddies and I was introduced to Mitay by my brother, but when he passed, Mitay and I stopped seeing each other. Then we just so happened to end up in the Zone together. He joined up with that clan while I was working under Crutch. I was there not long ago, before the collapse, and he told me how they found the documents. That night, I got to know two other stalkers from their camp, and we all shared a few drinks. They were really nice folks. Now, those three along with some other people left the clan because of some disagreements. I'm sure one of them knows the safe code, and they'll definitely be glad to help you out. They had a big argument — it won't be profitable if their former "friends" get to sell the documents, which, by the way, are very highly priced.\n \nMitay hangs out somewhere at Agroprom. There are two more: Tail and Barin. Tail usually wanders around the Garbage, and Barin went off to the Cordon.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_messenger_dialog_5">
    <text>Woah... So I'm supposed to go looking for some completete strangers? What if they tell me to buzz off?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_messenger_dialog_6">
    <text>Don't worry — they won't. Just tell them I sent you and watch their expressions change.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_messenger_dialog_7">
    <text>Alright, thanks. I'm going.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_messenger_dialog_8">
    <text>Good luck. Thanks for not leaving me here!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_messenger_dialog_9">
    <text>Of course.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_messenger_dialog_thx_0">
    <text>Thanks, stalker!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_messenger_dialog_friends_1">
    <text>Tell me about those stalkers.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_messenger_dialog_friends_2">
    <text>Naturally. Who do you want to know about?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_messenger_dialog_friends_3_1">
    <text>Tell me about Mitay.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_messenger_dialog_friends_3_2">
    <text>Tell me about Tail.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_messenger_dialog_friends_3_3">
    <text>Tell me about Barin.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_messenger_dialog_friends_3_4">
    <text>Never mind.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_messenger_dialog_friends_4_1">
    <text>I've already mentioned that he was my late brother's friend. My brother's the one who introduced us, but that's besides the point. When we came to the Zone, we worked for Sidorovich for a long time — back then, there was nothing particularly interesting going on. Together we recovered artifacts and split the pay in half... The guy and I hit things off very well.\n \nNow, here's the thing: after the Scorcher was shut down, we made a move for it. I stayed at the Garbage, but Mitay went all the way to the area around Jupiter. After he returned, he told me he had some trouble with the bandits — even ending up in captivity — but he turned out fine in the end after he was rescued by a few stalkers. Oh, and get this: one of them was part of the military... from the USS, I think. What a twist that was!\n \nAnyway, he stuck around for a while and then went the opposite way toward the Zone's outskirts, after which he joined up with the diggers at Agroprom. That's the story of that stalker.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_messenger_dialog_friends_4_2">
    <text>Interesting guy for sure, though a bit of an oddball. Back then, I met up with them to talk to Mitay. As I told you, they found the documents that day and drank in celebration of their discovery, and Tail suggested I stay when I was getting ready to leave. We hung out and talked about the lives we've made in the Zone. He told me interesting stories about the many places he's seen — a travel-crazy guy for sure. To my surprise, though, he didn't tell me a lot about himself, so I don't know anything else about him. All in all, a good stalker, if a bit closed up...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_messenger_dialog_friends_4_3">
    <text>He used to be part of Duty. Not the most likeable type, actually. I suppose we had a good time drinking, but the vibes he gave off... bit too slithery to my liking. I heard he left Duty for unclear reasons, and he still had his service equipment, which he still carries around the Zone. After that, when Mitay told me about him, it turns out I was right: a very greedy and squeamish person who looks for profit around every corner... That's that about Barin. I only saw him once, so I can't tell you anything else.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_messenger_dialog_friends_5">
    <text>Thanks.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_messenger_dialog_friends_6">
    <text>I've already told you about each of them.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_messenger_dialog_base_1">
    <text>I need to tell you something.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_messenger_dialog_base_2">
    <text>Sure. What is it?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_messenger_dialog_base_3_1">
    <text>I found Mitay's body. I'm sorry.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_messenger_dialog_base_3_2">
    <text>Tail's dead. I found his body here at the Garbage.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_messenger_dialog_base_3_3">
    <text>Barin's dead. I found his body at the Cordon.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_messenger_dialog_base_4_1">
    <text>Mitay?! Man, how's that possible?... How did that happen?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_messenger_dialog_base_4_2">
    <text>You're serious? Christ... What happened to him?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_messenger_dialog_base_4_3">
    <text>Barin? Hm. After all he's done, can't say I'm that surprised.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_messenger_dialog_base_5_1">
    <text>Sorry, but I don't know.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_messenger_dialog_base_5_2">
    <text>No clue.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_messenger_dialog_base_5_3">
    <text>I didn't know him, so I can't say.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_messenger_dialog_base_6_1">
    <text>What a man he was! Now I'm alone in this stinking Zone! Thanks for telling me. Here's for you...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_messenger_dialog_base_6_2">
    <text>I didn't really know him at all, but it's still a shame.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_messenger_dialog_base_6_3">
    <text>Still, I feel sorry for the guy.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_ohrannik_quest_dialog_wait_1_0">
    <text>Well, stalker? Anything new to tell?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_ohrannik_quest_dialog_wait_1_1">
    <text>Not yet. I'm going to see Myslaw.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_ohrannik_quest_dialog_wait_1_2">
    <text>Well, hurry up!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_ohrannik_quest_dialog_wait_2_0">
    <text>Well, stalker? Did Myslaw tell you anything?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_ohrannik_quest_dialog_wait_2_1_1">
    <text>Yeah. He told me about a few stalkers that left the digger clan because of some conflict. He knows three of them personally and tipped me off on where to find them. According to Myslav, one of them is sure to know the safe code.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_ohrannik_quest_dialog_wait_2_1_2">
    <text>Great. I'll be waiting for news!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_ohrannik_quest_dialog_wait_2_1_3">
    <text>I'll come by first thing.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_ohrannik_quest_dialog_wait_2_2_1">
    <text>Myslaw's dead... I'm sorry. I retrieved info on three of his acquaintances from the digger clan. I believe one of them knows the safe code. I'll go look for them.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_ohrannik_quest_dialog_wait_2_2_2">
    <text>Shit! How could this happen to you, Myslaw?...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_ohrannik_quest_dialog_wait_2_2_3">
    <text>It just happened.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_ohrannik_quest_dialog_wait_3_0">
    <text>So, anything new?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_ohrannik_quest_dialog_wait_3_1">
    <text>Not so far. I'm working on it.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_ohrannik_quest_dialog_final_1_1">
    <text>Yes, I've got the case. Had to go through a whole lot of effort to get it without bloodshed...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_ohrannik_quest_dialog_final_1_2">
    <text>Yes, I've got the case, but bullets were fired in the process.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_ohrannik_quest_dialog_final_2_1">
    <text>That's the way to go! So they didn't even spot you?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_ohrannik_quest_dialog_final_2_2">
    <text>Holy shit, man. How'd you do that? They were alright people, I guess, yet you went that far... Whatever, enough about that. Go see the trader and watch him light up when you give him the stuff. And don't forget about our mutual deal — the money.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_ohrannik_quest_dialog_final_3_1">
    <text>As I was going away, they still noticed it was gone. I overheard their radio chatter. Shit, they'll be looking for me now!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_ohrannik_quest_dialog_final_4_1">
    <text>I doubt it — they won't leave Agroprom to find you. Go see the trader and watch him light up when you give him the stuff. Don't forget about our mutual deal — the money.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_ohrannik_quest_dialog_final_5">
    <text>I won't.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_trader_case_reward_dialog_0">
    <text>Finally!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_trader_case_reward_dialog_1">
    <text>Here I am!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_trader_case_reward_dialog_2">
    <text>Did you first walk to the power plant before going into the Dark Valley? Where were you? Did anything happen?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_trader_case_reward_dialog_3">
    <text>No, it's just that...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_trader_case_reward_dialog_4">
    <text>Let me guess: you lost a card game?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_trader_case_reward_dialog_5">
    <text>Yeah! I don't know what got into me, but it happened. I played with those cheats.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_trader_case_reward_dialog_6">
    <text>I hope you didn't lose the case, at least?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_trader_case_reward_dialog_7">
    <text>No, it's all here. Open it and see for yourself.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_trader_case_reward_dialog_8">
    <text>Alright. Not bad for your first time... though my customers aren't happy I kept them waiting. Remember this: I see the same tempo in the future, you're not getting any more work. If anything else comes up, I'll drop you a line. Now go.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_trader_case_reward_dialog_9">
    <text>Later.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_medic_after_case_wait_dialog_0">
    <text>Hey there, old friend! You got a moment?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_medic_after_case_wait_dialog_1">
    <text>I'm just gonna bring Crutch what he's been promised and then we'll talk.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_medic_after_case_dialog_0">
    <text>Hey there, old friend! Where've you been?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_medic_after_case_dialog_1">
    <text>Oh, hey, mutant hunter! I was in the Dark Valley on some important business.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_medic_after_case_dialog_2">
    <text>I see. So you're still eager for some jobs? Do you want to continue our line of work?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_medic_after_case_dialog_3">
    <text>Sorry, but if it's about running from mutants again, I can't. My shoulder was all screwed up after last time.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_medic_after_case_dialog_4">
    <text>Don't worry, you wouldn't have to do any more running. I could use your help with something else.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_medic_after_case_dialog_5">
    <text>I'm all ears.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_medic_after_case_dialog_6">
    <text>Let's head to my shelter. No one needs to hear.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_medic_after_case_dialog_7_1">
    <text>Let's go.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_medic_after_case_dialog_7_2">
    <text>We'll meet there.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_medic_new_job_dialog_0">
    <text>We're here.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_medic_new_job_dialog_1">
    <text>Can we talk now? What's with the secrecy?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_medic_new_job_dialog_2">
    <text>No one needs to know there's a bloodsucker living right next to the stalker base, even in its current state.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_medic_new_job_dialog_3">
    <text>Makes sense. How did you even calm it down?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_medic_new_job_dialog_4">
    <text>Long story. I worked on it back when I was in the science base, but after our superiors saw my project as too questionable and dangerous, it was shut down. I tried continuing the research in secret with a group of like-minded associates, but they found out. After that, I had to say my goodbyes to science and join with the stalkers in their base. The point of our research was to try eliminating aggression in mutants. Fight fire with fire, so to speak... by using artifacts.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_medic_new_job_dialog_5">
    <text>Interesting. Artifacts have always interested me.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_medic_new_job_dialog_6">
    <text>So, this one time, we discovered by sheer chance that we could use a Compass to affect mutant behavior... not to a large extent, but that made us reflect deeply. I started doing selective artifact breeding — basically frankensteining two artifacts to make something new — and one day, I was able to achieve a set of artifact properties that have a positive effect on mutant behavior.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_medic_new_job_dialog_7">
    <text>So that's the artifact I saw on your table! I always thought selective artifact breeding was just made up. I remember seeing this one guy throwing dog tails and vodka into an anomaly to get a Gravi.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_medic_new_job_dialog_8">
    <text>Hehe. Did it work out for him?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_medic_new_job_dialog_9">
    <text>Well, what do you think? The guys in the village were left with no artifact and no vodka.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_medic_new_job_dialog_10">
    <text>Well, it's not that simple. There are a lot of factors at play, and good equipment helps too. Unfortunately, working away from the scientific facility made everything tougher for me. If I didn't have those colleagues that helped me, things would've been rough.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_medic_new_job_dialog_11">
    <text>So, you transmuted an artifact, and now you can control the bloodsucker?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_medic_new_job_dialog_12">
    <text>I wish. Only thing I can do right now is pacify it by putting it to sleep. I have to carry out additional tests in order to stop one — or even several — mutants with an artifact in hand. I wouldn't want to invite any more people to the project. If they hear about the bloodsucker, it won't be pretty. My role as their medic won't matter anymore.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_medic_new_job_dialog_13">
    <text>What are we gonna do?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_medic_new_job_dialog_14">
    <text>I carried out a new artifact selection that I believe is ready for testing. You and I will head out to the field where there's been a pack of dogs these past few days, and we'll try to pacify them. You'll walk behind me with the artifact, and I'll cover you with my rifle just in case. Sound good?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_medic_new_job_dialog_15">
    <text>Yeah. So I carry the artifact while you keep me covered?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_medic_new_job_dialog_16">
    <text>Yep. If anything goes wrong, we'll just run away, but everything should be fine. The dogs shouldn't even bite through our suits.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_medic_new_job_dialog_17">
    <text>Let's go, then.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_medic_final_dialog_0">
    <text>How are you doing?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_medic_final_dialog_1">
    <text>Hey, stay with me! Let's get you patched up, ???</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_new_medic_start_dialog_0">
    <text>Well, look who it is! How are you? How's your head?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_new_medic_start_dialog_1">
    <text>Hey! It's fine, I'll live. How are *you* doing? Did you get settled in?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_new_medic_start_dialog_2">
    <text>I sure did, alright. While these stalkers were short of a medic, they started healing themselves. All the medical bags are used up — everything's used up! Not a single bandage left either. What am I supposed to use to patch them up?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_new_medic_start_dialog_3">
    <text>The trader, Crutch, manages everything here. Maybe ask him?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_new_medic_start_dialog_4">
    <text>I've already asked him. He gave me money for medical supplies, but where do I get them? "Ain't my problem," he says.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_new_medic_start_dialog_5_1">
    <text>Maybe I can help? Duty has an outpost nearby — maybe they have medical supplies to spare.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_new_medic_start_dialog_5_2">
    <text>I can't help you. Sorry.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_new_medic_start_dialog_6_1">
    <text>Really? You can? It'd be great!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_new_medic_start_dialog_6_2">
    <text>Don't worry. I'll manage somehow.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_new_medic_start_dialog_7_1">
    <text>I'll try.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_new_medic_start_dialog_7_2">
    <text>Good luck to you.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_new_medic_start_reversed_dialog_0">
    <text>I think there's a chance I could help you with your medical supplies.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_new_medic_start_reversed_dialog_1">
    <text>Really? Got any ideas?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_new_medic_start_reversed_dialog_2">
    <text>I'll try visiting the Duty outpost and asking their man in charge.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_new_medic_start_reversed_dialog_3">
    <text>That'd be great!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_new_medic_start_reversed_dialog_4">
    <text>Wait for me.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dolg_zastava_dyatlov_drugs_dialog_0">
    <text>What's your business?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dolg_zastava_dyatlov_drugs_dialog_1">
    <text>Hello. Do you have any medical kits to spare? It's for the local stalker base. I'll pay if necessary.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dolg_zastava_dyatlov_drugs_dialog_2">
    <text>Funny. You think I'm going to sell medical supplies handed out to us under the radar?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dolg_zastava_dyatlov_drugs_dialog_3">
    <text>I thought we could make a deal.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dolg_zastava_dyatlov_drugs_dialog_4">
    <text>Hm. Perhaps. But it's not money we need... well, everyone needs money, but we have more important things at hand. If you can provide us assistance, we'll hand out a few medical bags.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dolg_zastava_dyatlov_drugs_dialog_5">
    <text>What do you need?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dolg_zastava_dyatlov_drugs_dialog_6">
    <text>There's a pack of boars that turned up not far from here. If that place isn't cleaned out right now, they'll be heading toward the outpost sooner or later. Deal with them and you'll get your supplies.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dolg_zastava_dyatlov_drugs_dialog_7">
    <text>Alright. I'll do it.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dolg_zastava_dyatlov_drugs_final_dialog_0">
    <text>Did you do it?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dolg_zastava_dyatlov_drugs_final_dialog_1_1">
    <text>Yep. No idea why you didn't do it yourselves. So much for protecting the world from the expanding Zone.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dolg_zastava_dyatlov_drugs_final_dialog_1_2">
    <text>Not yet.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dolg_zastava_dyatlov_drugs_final_dialog_2">
    <text>We've got more important things to deal with right now. Here's what you asked for. If you want more mutants to shoot down, come see me.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_dolg_zastava_dyatlov_drugs_final_dialog_3">
    <text>Thanks. See you.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_new_medic_second_dialog_0">
    <text>So, did you get the medical supplies?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_new_medic_second_dialog_1_1">
    <text>Yeah. It's not much, but it should suffice for some time.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_new_medic_second_dialog_1_2">
    <text>Not yet. Wait.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_new_medic_second_dialog_2">
    <text>Well, thank you kindly! You're not walking out of here unrewarded — I know a place with some real juicy loot. You interested?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_new_medic_second_dialog_3">
    <text>Of course!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_new_medic_second_dialog_4">
    <text>Just recently, the scientists from our facility made a trip to the Garbage to research an anomaly. I know for sure that anomaly was an Electro. They stood there and gathered their data until a wave of mutants came at 'em. The soldiers tried to fend them off, but... they had to make it out of there. Dropped all their things and went on the run. If the locals haven't found that place and grabbed those supplies yet, they should still be there. Unfortunately, I can't pinpoint the exact spot, but look around the big Electro.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_new_medic_second_dialog_5">
    <text>Thanks. I'll look for it when I get the chance.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_ambush_leader_idle_dialog_0_1">
    <text>You again... What do you want?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_ambush_leader_idle_dialog_0_2">
    <text>I'm listening.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_ambush_leader_idle_dialog_0_3">
    <text>What do you want, stalker?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_ambush_leader_idle_dialog_0_4">
    <text>Speak up.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_ambush_leader_idle_dialog_0_5">
    <text>Well, I'm all ears.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_ambush_stalkers_idle_dialog_0_1">
    <text>What is it?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_ambush_stalkers_idle_dialog_0_2">
    <text>What do you need?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_ambush_stalkers_idle_dialog_0_3">
    <text>What are you looking at?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_ambush_stalkers_idle_dialog_0_4">
    <text>Spill it.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_ambush_stalkers_idle_dialog_0_5">
    <text>I'm listening.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_ambush_stalkers_idle_dialog_0_6">
    <text>Go on. Say what you've got to say.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_ambush_stalkers_idle_dialog_0_7">
    <text>Say your words.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_ambush_stalkers_idle_dialog_0_8">
    <text>Go ahead. Say it.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_ambush_stalkers_idle_dialog_0_9">
    <text>Shoot.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_ambush_stalkers_idle_dialog_0_10">
    <text>Got any questions?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_corvalol_present_start_dialog_0">
    <text>Glad to see you in one piece again! Coming onto a group of bandits in the Bar... You're something else!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_corvalol_present_start_dialog_1">
    <text>I've been having terrible luck lately — not my first time getting hit in the head. Good thing I'm still alive.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_corvalol_present_start_dialog_2">
    <text>Yep. Anyway, about the sergeant: I wanted to bring him a little something, his old badge that he lost after drinking with me. I had amazing luck recently — bought it off the locals. And give him this artifact too so he can give it to the scientists when he gets the chance.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_corvalol_present_start_dialog_3">
    <text>Deal. I'll hand it to him when I'm in the Bar.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_corvalol_present_start_dialog_4">
    <text>Good luck to you. If you get the time, come see me — I could give you artifact orders.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_corvalol_present_start_dialog_5">
    <text>Alright. Until next time.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_corvalol_base_idle_dialog_1_1">
    <text>Goodbye.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_corvalol_base_idle_dialog_1_2">
    <text>Bye.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_corvalol_base_idle_dialog_1_3">
    <text>I'm going.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_corvalol_base_idle_dialog_0_1">
    <text>Heya.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_corvalol_base_idle_dialog_0_2">
    <text>Hey there.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_corvalol_base_idle_dialog_0_3">
    <text>What've you got?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_corvalol_base_second_actor_idle_dialog_0_1">
    <text>Hm? What is it? Haven't seen you here before...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_corvalol_base_second_actor_idle_dialog_0_2">
    <text>What do you need, man?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_corvalol_base_second_actor_idle_dialog_0_3">
    <text>What do you want?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_corvalol_base_second_actor_idle_dialog_1_1">
    <text>I'm going.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_corvalol_base_second_actor_idle_dialog_1_2">
    <text>Bye.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_corvalol_base_second_actor_idle_dialog_1_3">
    <text>Goodbye.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_drunk_medic_second_actor_idle_dialog_0_1">
    <text>Need a patch-up, wanderer?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_drunk_medic_second_actor_idle_dialog_0_2">
    <text>Did you take one? Need medical assistance?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_drunk_medic_second_actor_idle_dialog_0_3">
    <text>What do you need, buddy?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_messenger_second_hero_dialog_0_1">
    <text>Yeah? What do you need?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_messenger_second_hero_dialog_0_2">
    <text>Tell me what you need?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_messenger_second_hero_dialog_0_3">
    <text>What is it?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_mishgan_default_second_hero_meet_0">
    <text>Stay out of the way, pal.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_koval_after_help_dialog_0">
    <text>Thanks for helping me! The colonel would've killed me for that detector!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_koval_after_help_dialog_1">
    <text>You shut your mouth! I'm not even going to ask what you were doing here. I know about you and the colonel's relations, and I don't give two shits about it as long as I have nothing to do with it. I hope you and I are on clear terms and that you won't drag me into your business. Better yet, stay out of my squad's way.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_koval_after_help_dialog_2">
    <text>But the colonel assigned me to your squad...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_koval_after_help_dialog_3">
    <text>Oh, right. He did. So, your role in the squad is to stay out of our sight. Go do your own thing. Go bring your artifacts to your daddy colonel, and say hi to him for me.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_koval_after_help_dialog_4">
    <text>How's the investigation going, then? Need any help?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_koval_after_help_dialog_5">
    <text>The last thing I want to do is involve you. Go hunt some artifacts, stalker.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_koval_after_help_dialog_6">
    <text>So you don't need any information? I didn't join up with your squad for nothing — I haven't been sitting idly by.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_koval_after_help_dialog_7">
    <text>Really now? What information could that be?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_koval_after_help_dialog_8">
    <text>A couple of days ago, a group of stalkers I know came across some armed soldiers. Judging by what I heard, they really look like the ones that were seen at Agroprom the day the professor disappeared.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_koval_after_help_dialog_9">
    <text>Where did this happen? Did the stalkers come out alive?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_koval_after_help_dialog_10">
    <text>They ran away. It happened in the area around the abandoned army warehouses. We could go verify it — we'll arrive in a few hours if we move.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_koval_after_help_dialog_11">
    <text>Thanks for the information, but I'll be acting alone as before. Where do I find these stalkers so I can question them?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_koval_after_help_dialog_12">
    <text>They didn't make any more radio contact... Ask the local trader about them — I'll give you his coordinates. If I were you, I wouldn't turn down any help — the safest route to the warehouses is through the Bar, and if anyone finds out you're no stalker...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_koval_after_help_dialog_13">
    <text>I'll deal with it. And remember, if this info's just made-up and I waste my time, your head's gonna roll.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_koval_after_help_dialog_14">
    <text>I know those stalkers well. They've always shared useful information with me...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_koval_after_help_dialog_15">
    <text>What are their names?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_koval_after_help_dialog_16">
    <text>I only know one personally: Chord.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_koval_after_help_dialog_17">
    <text>Right. Get back to Agroprom. Try not to stain yourself.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_koval_after_help_idle_dialog_0_1">
    <text>Commander?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_koval_after_help_idle_dialog_0_2">
    <text>Glad to see you, boss?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_koval_after_help_idle_dialog_0_3">
    <text>Anything else?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_koval_after_help_idle_dialog_1_1">
    <text>Bye.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_koval_after_help_idle_dialog_1_2">
    <text>Watch yourself.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_koval_after_help_idle_dialog_1_3">
    <text>Later.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_duty_bandits_kill_task_reward_dialog_0">
    <text>The bandits on the farm won't bother your men any more.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_duty_bandits_kill_task_reward_dialog_1">
    <text>That's great news, stalker. Thanks! I'll let our superiors know they can send a squad there.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_duty_bandits_kill_task_reward_dialog_2">
    <text>What's in it for me?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_duty_bandits_kill_task_reward_dialog_3">
    <text>Something in return, eh? Here you go. Honest reward for honest work.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_duty_bandits_kill_task_reward_dialog_4">
    <text>Now we're talking. 'Til next time!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_composer_task_bandit_savior_treasure_start_dialog_0">
    <text>What're you staring at? Get the PDA out of the stash and read it. I'll cover you.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_composer_task_bandit_savior_treasure_start_dialog_1">
    <text>The stash is in the stump?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_composer_task_bandit_savior_treasure_start_dialog_2">
    <text>What did you expect? I didn't have time to think.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_composer_task_bandit_savior_treasure_start_dialog_3">
    <text>Let's see.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_composer_task_bandit_savior_treasure_second_dialog_0">
    <text>It says one of the people who died after the events punched in the coordinates of his buddy's PDA into his own so that "he wouldn't get lost." Here's his location.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_composer_task_bandit_savior_treasure_second_dialog_1">
    <text>Maybe his pal's got the info and goods?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_composer_task_bandit_savior_treasure_second_dialog_2">
    <text>I doubt the goods would vanish like that. Survivors must've taken it. Let's head to the coordinates.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_composer_task_bandit_savior_treasure_second_dialog_3">
    <text>Let's go.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_nimble_start_dialog_0">
    <text>Why, hello, good sir. New here? Who might you be?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_nimble_start_dialog_1">
    <text>Hi! Yeah, haven't been here long. Name's Axe, regular stalker. What do you do here?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_nimble_start_dialog_2">
    <text>I'm Vitka. I trade custom weapons and armor. I also buy any other goods at a cheap price, whether it be weapons or armored suits.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_nimble_start_dialog_3">
    <text>So I can talk to you if I need anything?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_nimble_start_dialog_4">
    <text>Of course. You can take a look at my assortment. It's not an instant delivery, but it won't take me more than forty-eight hours. Name any rare shooters or armor and it's yours!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_nimble_start_dialog_5">
    <text>I'll keep that in mind.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_nimble_idle_dialog_0_1">
    <text>Hi! Need anything?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_nimble_idle_dialog_0_2">
    <text>Hello, stalker.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_nimble_idle_dialog_0_3">
    <text>I'm all ears.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_nimble_order_dialog_0">
    <text>I'd like to make an order.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_nimble_order_dialog_1">
    <text>Of course! Weapons or armor?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_nimble_order_dialog_2_1">
    <text>Weapons.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_nimble_order_dialog_2_2">
    <text>Armor.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_nimble_order_dialog_2_3">
    <text>Changed my mind.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_nimble_order_dialog_weapons">
    <text>Excellent. What arms are you looking for?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_nimble_order_dialog_outfits">
    <text>What kind of protection would you like?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_nimble_order_dialog_weapons_pistols">
    <text>Pistols.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_nimble_order_dialog_weapons_shotguns">
    <text>Shotguns.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_nimble_order_dialog_weapons_submachine_guns">
    <text>Submachine guns.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_nimble_order_dialog_weapons_assault_rifles">
    <text>Assault rifles.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_nimble_order_dialog_weapons_sniper_rifles">
    <text>Sniper rifles.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_nimble_order_dialog_show_assortment">
    <text>Here's what I can offer you:\n \n</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_nimble_order_dialog_outfits_helmets">
    <text>Headgear.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_nimble_order_dialog_outfits_communities_outfits">
    <text>Faction suits.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_nimble_order_dialog_outfits_light_outfits">
    <text>Light armor.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_nimble_order_dialog_outfits_scientific_outfits">
    <text>Scientific suits.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_nimble_order_dialog_outfits_heavy_outfits">
    <text>Heavy armor.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_nimble_order_dialog_outfits_exo_outfits">
    <text>Exoskeletons.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_nimble_order_dialog_actor_have_money_1">
    <text>I'll go with that.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_nimble_order_dialog_actor_have_money_2">
    <text>I'll take it!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_nimble_order_dialog_actor_have_money_3">
    <text>That's a deal.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_nimble_order_dialog_actor_dont_have_money_1">
    <text>I can't afford that right now.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_nimble_order_dialog_actor_dont_have_money_2">
    <text>That's a bit on the expensive side.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_nimble_order_dialog_actor_dont_have_money_3">
    <text>I don't have that much...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_nimble_order_dialog_cancel_1">
    <text>I'll come by another time.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_nimble_order_dialog_cancel_2">
    <text>I've changed my mind.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_nimble_order_dialog_cancel_3">
    <text>I'll give it some thought.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_nimble_order_dialog_actor_select_complete_1">
    <text>An excellent choice! That'll be</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_nimble_order_dialog_actor_select_complete_2">
    <text>A deal it is. That'll cost you</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_nimble_order_dialog_actor_select_complete_3">
    <text>Not a bad choice. That's</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_nimble_order_dialog_wait_one_day">
    <text>The goods will arrive in around twenty-four hours. I'll message you then.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_nimble_order_dialog_wait_two_days">
    <text>The goods will be here in about two days. You can go about your business until then, and I'll notify you.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_nimble_order_dialog_actor_final_phrase_1">
    <text>See you later, then.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_nimble_order_dialog_actor_final_phrase_2">
    <text>Thank you. Bye.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_nimble_order_dialog_actor_final_phrase_3">
    <text>Superb. I'll see you around.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_nimble_wait_order_dialog_0_1">
    <text>The order's not here yet, stalker. If you want, we can trade in the meantime.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_nimble_wait_order_dialog_0_2">
    <text>Come by later. Your order isn't ready yet.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_nimble_wait_order_dialog_0_3">
    <text>Order's not ready yet. I'll message you when you can come by.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_nimble_order_complete_dialog_0_1">
    <text>Welcome back! The goods have arrived.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_nimble_order_complete_dialog_0_2">
    <text>Just in time! Your order's here, stalker. Here you go.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_nimble_order_complete_dialog_0_3">
    <text>Stalker, your order's here. You're very much welcome!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_nimble_order_complete_dialog_1_1">
    <text>Thanks! I'm off to try this out.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_nimble_order_complete_dialog_1_2">
    <text>Thanks! I'd say it was worth it.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_stalker_nimble_order_complete_dialog_1_3">
    <text>A fine product. I'll drop by some other time. Thanks!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_zastava_dolg_soldier_after_ghost_dialog_0">
    <text>Hey! Did you see that too? I'm not imagining it, am I?!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_zastava_dolg_soldier_after_ghost_dialog_1">
    <text>Yeah... hell knows what it was, but life certainly didn't prepare me for this.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_zastava_dolg_soldier_after_ghost_dialog_2">
    <text>How are we supposed to live with that?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_zastava_dolg_soldier_after_ghost_dialog_3">
    <text>Same as before. I guess...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_trader_primary_task_start_dialog_0">
    <text>What's up? What kind of urgent business were you having?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_trader_primary_task_start_dialog_1">
    <text>A group of stalkers I personally know asked me to find a man for some urgent work. I tried contacting them recently — but nothing from their end.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_trader_primary_task_start_dialog_2">
    <text>What did they need help with?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_trader_primary_task_start_dialog_3">
    <text>That you can go figure out yourself. But first — we need to figure out why they are not answering.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_trader_primary_task_start_dialog_4">
    <text>Give me their location, I'll go look for them.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_trader_primary_task_start_dialog_5">
    <text>Last time we spoke they said that they stopped near the village houses at the swamp... Well, what are you waiting here for? Go.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_trader_primary_task_start_dialog_6">
    <text>I'll see you later.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_trader_radio_dialog_1">
    <text>I hear you've got old Soviet songs on your radio too?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_trader_radio_dialog_2">
    <text>Just like everywhere else! There's only one radio station in the Zone, the one you're listening to right now. That's where they play these songs. Some say that there is a man in the Zone who organised the radio broadcast, and others believe that the signal comes from the past. Whatever, I don't care. Music and music. It's more fun than the jokes and songs of failed guitarists coming from the camp behind the wall!</text>
  </string>
</string_table>
