<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252" ?>
<string_table>
  <string id="mutant_boar_leg">
    <text>Boar's hoof</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mutant_boar_leg_description">
    <text>Boar's hooves can be used to produce a number of drugs, including an antiradiation serum.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mutant_dog_tail">
    <text>Dog tail</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mutant_dog_tail_description">
    <text>The resistance of mutant dogs' skin to electricity and chemical agents has long been the subject of scientific attention. Since the animal's tail is almost completely free of fat tissue, it is especially suited for lab examination.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mutant_cat_tail">
    <text>Bayun cat tail</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mutant_cat_tail_description">
    <text>Bayun cats are famous for their ability to lull their victim to sleep. Scientists are just as interested in studying these creatures as anyone else.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mutant_flesh_eye">
    <text>Flesh eye</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mutant_flesh_eye_description">
    <text>The mutated, swollen eye of the flesh acquired a number of strange characteristics, the most useful of which is the ability to regenerate the lens. The specifics of the process are hitherto unknown, although such discovery would most certainly revolutionize modern medicine. You can play your part in scientific development by selling Flesh eyes to scientists for their experiments.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mutant_krovosos_jaw">
    <text>Bloodsucker tentacles</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mutant_krovosos_jaw_description">
    <text>Bloodsucker tentacles contain a special gland producing a ferment capable of dissolving the skin and simultaneously preventing blood from clotting. Discovering the ferment's composition could be the cornerstone of a whole series of great medical advances.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mutant_psevdodog_tail">
    <text>Pseudodog tail</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mutant_psevdodog_tail_description">
    <text>The resistance of mutant dogs' skin to electricity and chemical agents has long been the subject of scientific attention. Since the animal's tail is almost completely free of fat tissue, it is especially suited for lab examination.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mutant_snork_leg">
    <text>Snork foot</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mutant_snork_leg_description">
    <text>Snork feet contain a huge number of highly elastic tendons. This explains the beast's ability to make those unbelievably long jumps.</text>
  </string>
</string_table>