<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252" ?>
<string_table>
  <string id="mlab_stalker_fate_task">
    <text>FATE OF THE STALKER</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_stalker_fate_task_name">
    <text>Talk to Termite</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_stalker_fate_task_text">
    <text>Kalinski tells me that Termit allegedly killed a stalker by the name of Axe after he helped us carry out an artifact selection. This has left me outraged; we cannot squander such valuable personnel. I will head to security to deal with this matter.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_trials_task">
    <text>TESTS</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_trials_task_start_name">
    <text>Start the equipment</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_trials_task_start_text">
    <text>The superiors of our laboratory has set a goal to study the possibility of reversing mutations in the Zones. Several civilian zombies who have wandered the Chornobyl Zone for several years have been found and placed as test subjects. Perhaps they will be able to at least partially return to normal life; however, today, we are only conducting the first days. The work ahead of us will demand painstaking efforts.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_trials_task_wait_name">
    <text>Wait for the test to end</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_trials_task_wait_text">
    <text>The equipment has been started. We should wait for the tests to end and then receive long-awaited results.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_trials_task_talk_name">
    <text>Talk to the assistant</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_trials_task_talk_text">
    <text>The tests are finished. I should talk to my assistant about the results.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_trials_task_final_name">
    <text>Answer call in office</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_trials_task_final_text">
    <text>I've received a call, likely from our superiors regarding the tests. I should go to my office and pick up the phone.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_final_task">
    <text>BREAKTHROUGH</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_final_task_start_name">
    <text>Move into the laboratory</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_final_task_start_text">
    <text>I've broken into the underground area where the stalkers have settled. Apparently, they've organized a laboratory here. This place is probably filled with traps, so I should be on my guard as I move deeper. My task here is to find Dubinin and figure out what kind of place this is.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_final_task_scientist_boss_sprint_name">
    <text>Catch up with the professor</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_final_task_scientist_boss_sprint_text">
    <text>Professor Dubinin refused to submit. I must catch up and arrest him.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_final_task_search_merc_leader_name">
    <text>Find Termite</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_final_task_search_merc_leader_text">
    <text>The professor is dead. I don't know whether I' made the right choice, but he clearly never intended to turn himself in. Now I need to finish my inspection of the laboratory and, if possible, find Termite.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_final_task_follow_scientist_laborant_name">
    <text>Follow the scientist</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_final_task_follow_scientist_laborant_text">
    <text>The laboratory assistant said that Dubinin and the rest of the staff are planning to leave the laboratory via teleporter. I need to follow him and he'll show me how to turn off the laboratory power.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_final_task_teleport_off_name">
    <text>Cut power to the teleporter</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_final_task_teleport_off_text">
    <text>The scientist showed me how to turn off the electricity in the laboratory. Dubinin won't escape so easily without it.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_final_task_talk_final_name">
    <text>Talk to Dubinin</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_final_task_talk_final_text">
    <text>There is no more electricity in the laboratory. The professor shouldn't be going anywhere anymore.</text>
  </string>
</string_table>