<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252" ?>
<string_table>
  <string id="agr_treasure_1_name">
    <text>Rotten stump</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_treasure_1_descr">
    <text>Found a stump with good space on a hill with anomalies. About time I drop off some loot.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_treasure_2_name">
    <text>Barracks</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_treasure_2_descr">
    <text>I saw a box with different kinds of supplies in the milstalker barracks. Can't just walk in there in broad daylight, but damn if I'm not tempted...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_treasure_3_name">
    <text>Box under power line</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_treasure_3_descr">
    <text>An iron box within a field of electroanomalies? Perfect spot for a stash.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_treasure_4_name">
    <text>Supplies</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_treasure_4_descr">
    <text>I found a nice space for extra loot in a box that was once used for chemical substances. I'll leave it here for now and retrieve it later if nothing rots.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_treasure_5_name">
    <text>Forgotten grave</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_treasure_5_descr">
    <text>Near the old passage to Yantar, I saw a stalker stuff some things into an abandoned grave. Guy's got no heart!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_treasure_6_name">
    <text>Cross on the outskirts</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_treasure_6_descr">
    <text>I decided to bring my friend's things to his grave. Can't just keep it around forever. Let him have them.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_treasure_7_name">
    <text>Stump by trail</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_treasure_7_descr">
    <text>I had to drop off my heaviest gear near the gate to the Garbage while running from boars. I hope I can get back to the stash later and that no one touches it.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_treasure_8_name">
    <text>Inconspicuous stash</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_treasure_8_descr">
    <text>I saw a case by the unhinged door in the helipad building where an egghead looked to be hiding stuff. Maybe he's stealing surplus materials?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_treasure_9_name">
    <text>Army stash</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_treasure_9_descr">
    <text>I just overheard a conversation between two COs. One was boasting about a cache with some big-time loot... which, as it turns out, was snatched from stalker corpses.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_treasure_10_name">
    <text>High-rise cache</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_treasure_10_descr">
    <text>While climbing the roofs, I saw a guy on a tower rummaging around something for at least ten minutes. Looks like I know his hiding place.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_treasure_11_name">
    <text>Stump by hillside</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_treasure_11_descr">
    <text>I'll be keeping the goods in a rotten swump on the way to the tunnel. Once I tie up all loose ends, I'll be back for it.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_treasure_12_name">
    <text>Official transport</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_treasure_12_descr">
    <text>I'll leave a case with my stuff in this old rusty Niva. Can't carry this junk around all the time.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_treasure_13_name">
    <text>Small case</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_treasure_13_descr">
    <text>I stashed some loot by the tunnel that I won't be needing anytime soon. Just hope no one snoops around.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_treasure_14_name">
    <text>Pipe in hole</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_treasure_14_descr">
    <text>Found an old pipe in a hole once dug up by snorks. I'd say this'll be a nice place for my stuff.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_treasure_15_name">
    <text>Stash in thicket</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_treasure_15_descr">
    <text>Hid part of my loot in the thick bushes under the heating main. Think I'll come back for it on a rainy day.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_treasure_16_name">
    <text>Blockage</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_treasure_16_descr">
    <text>Found a sizeable pipe in the rubble blocking the stairwell to the underground. Could be useful for hiding stuff.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_treasure_17_name">
    <text>Worn backpack</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_treasure_17_descr">
    <text>I found a backpack with all sorts of goods near a soldier's corpse. Area's wide open, so I didn't stick my neck out. People could chase me.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_treasure_18_name">
    <text>Hill</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_treasure_18_descr">
    <text>I found a backpack with loot in a tent near the digger camp. Will come back here in a couple of days and grab it if the owner doesn't show up.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_treasure_19_name">
    <text>In the ashes</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_treasure_19_descr">
    <text>Saw a stalker through my binoculars as he threw his backpack on top of the anomalous protrusions. Didn't get what that was all about, and then he got detained by the military for some reason.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_treasure_20_name">
    <text>Sunken transport</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_treasure_20_descr">
    <text>The front part of the sunken UAZ is still intact. Guess I'll leave my backpack there. Wouldn't want it with me if I get put under pressure by the bandit shits at the Garbage.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_treasure_21_name">
    <text>Under the vent</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_treasure_21_descr">
    <text>Fat chance anyone will try getting into the center of a chemical anomaly. I found a ventilation spot where I'll drop off some of my loot.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_treasure_22_name">
    <text>Covered by foliage</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_treasure_22_descr">
    <text>Made a stash on the roof of the building, nicely covered by a nearby growing tree. I'll be back for it in a week if I get the chance.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_treasure_23_name">
    <text>Middle of the forest</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_treasure_23_descr">
    <text>Found a big log in the forest on the outskirts. Should leave excess gear in it, or else my backpack will tear open.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_treasure_24_name">
    <text>Hidden safe</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_treasure_24_descr">
    <text>Caught a soldier rummaging in some safe by the scientific complex. Probably bringing something from the base. I either clear out his stuff or tell his commander... gotta give it some thought.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_treasure_25_name">
    <text>Safe in bins</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_treasure_25_descr">
    <text>Was visiting my friend in the digger area. Found an empty safe in a container that no one's using. They allowed me leave my things there for a small fee.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_quest_treasure_1_name">
    <text>Log by the road</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_quest_treasure_1_descr">
    <text>There's an obscure place near the exit to the Garbage with good loot.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_quest_treasure_2_name">
    <text>Unreachable backpack</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_quest_treasure_2_descr">
    <text>There's this little spot in the digger base where a guy'd dropped off his loot. He's left the Zone by now, and never decided to retrieve his stuff.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_quest_treasure_3_name">
    <text>Under wagon</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_quest_treasure_3_descr">
    <text>I know a place where a pretty rich stalker hides his stuff. Happened to overhear his conversation with a pal.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_quest_treasure_4_name">
    <text>On the roof</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_quest_treasure_4_descr">
    <text>There's this stash that's literally close by. Just make sure the soldiers don't see you.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_quest_treasure_5_name">
    <text>Don't enter - you'll die</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_quest_treasure_5_descr">
    <text>Here are the coordinates to my hiding place, as thanks for helping me with those dogs. If it weren't for you, they'd have me for dinner by now.</text>
  </string>
</string_table>