<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252" ?>
<string_table>
  <string id="nsp_treasure_1_name">
    <text>Backpack in tent</text>
  </string>
  <string id="nsp_treasure_1_descr">
    <text>I've had my eye on this one hunter's tent, and he's been gone for a week. If he doesn't return from his trip, I don't think he'll be needing it anymore.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="nsp_treasure_2_name">
    <text>Abandoned toilet</text>
  </string>
  <string id="nsp_treasure_2_descr">
    <text>I've been hanging around the local village for a week now, and I've never seen anyone go to the outskirts for a number two. Might be a good site for a temporary stash.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="nsp_treasure_3_name">
    <text>House ruins</text>
  </string>
  <string id="nsp_treasure_3_descr">
    <text>Found a dead stalker. Poor guy must've run into bandits. They forgot his PDA, and I found the coordinates to his stash on it. Worth checking out.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="nsp_treasure_4_name">
    <text>Zaporozhets in village</text>
  </string>
  <string id="nsp_treasure_4_descr">
    <text>It's been two weeks, and one of the locals is still trying to bring a rusty Zaporozhets car back to life. It's like the thing is his new home! I even saw him store stuff under the hood.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="nsp_treasure_5_name">
    <text>Crooked cross</text>
  </string>
  <string id="nsp_treasure_5_descr">
    <text>The guys buried the dead stalker along with his belongings. I mean, why? You think loot dies too? Idiots. Soon as everything calms down, it's all mine.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="nsp_treasure_6_name">
    <text>Steel box</text>
  </string>
  <string id="nsp_treasure_6_descr">
    <text>Two months, and the electrical anomalies are still going rampant at the military base. I could try hiding some things nearby. No one will stick their nose there, I hope.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="nsp_treasure_7_name">
    <text>Stash in safe</text>
  </string>
  <string id="nsp_treasure_7_descr">
    <text>Got some info on a guy on one of his stashes. Hope the contents are useful.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="nsp_treasure_8_name">
    <text>Dutyer backpack</text>
  </string>
  <string id="nsp_treasure_8_descr">
    <text>Found the mangled corpse of a Dutyer at the Garbage. While his friends go looking for him, I'll see what's inside his backpack. Should hide it somewhere just in case.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="nsp_treasure_9_name">
    <text>Deserter's little secret</text>
  </string>
  <string id="nsp_treasure_9_descr">
    <text>I ran into an army deserter who offered solid money and info about a stash in exchange for help crossing the perimeter. I got the money, but I still have to get to the stash.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="nsp_treasure_10_name">
    <text>Cemetery</text>
  </string>
  <string id="nsp_treasure_10_descr">
    <text>I found someone's backpack in the local cemetery, full of different loot. I'll let it lay there. If the owner doesn't show up, I'll take it.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="nsp_treasure_11_name">
    <text>For when things go south</text>
  </string>
  <string id="nsp_treasure_11_descr">
    <text>If your backpack's starting to tear from all the loot, you really should start thinking about making a stash. I managed to find a suitable place at the oil terminal.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="nsp_treasure_12_name">
    <text>Hunters' stash</text>
  </string>
  <string id="nsp_treasure_12_descr">
    <text>Not the first time I see hunters enter a certain booth before they head out. It's to the left before turning to the pool. I think I know whose stash I'll be clearing out soon!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="nsp_treasure_13_name">
    <text>Amidst the woods</text>
  </string>
  <string id="nsp_treasure_13_descr">
    <text>I wandered into the denser part of the local forest to hide some loot. Gotta remember this place. Look for a lone log on the edge of the forest.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="nsp_treasure_14_name">
    <text>Stump at the tunnel</text>
  </string>
  <string id="nsp_treasure_14_descr">
    <text>We pinned down this one bastard for stealing. Guy coughed up info on where he stores his stuff. Soon as I have the time, I'll go grab what's ours.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="nsp_treasure_15_name">
    <text>Bandit stash</text>
  </string>
  <string id="nsp_treasure_15_descr">
    <text>I overheard two suckers talking about a cool stash near the tunnel. Kinda far away from here, but if I find myself nearby, I'll be sure to check it out.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="nsp_treasure_16_name">
    <text>Safe in booth</text>
  </string>
  <string id="nsp_treasure_16_descr">
    <text>I was about to rip my hair out while trying to get this safe open. Is it stuck or something? I'll come back later and try again.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="nsp_treasure_17_name">
    <text>Under the bridge</text>
  </string>
  <string id="nsp_treasure_17_descr">
    <text>Found a good place for hiding some of my things near the campsite. My backpack's about to burst from all this stuff.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="nsp_treasure_18_name">
    <text>Forgotten ship</text>
  </string>
  <string id="nsp_treasure_18_descr">
    <text>Recently, I saw a stalker rummaging in his backpack on the abandoned ship. Seems to me like he's got a stash there. Dunno if it's worth going there. What if he goes looking for me?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="nsp_treasure_19_name">
    <text>Boat at the shore</text>
  </string>
  <string id="nsp_treasure_19_descr">
    <text>I found this backpack on the middle of the road, full of loot! I'll grab the lightest and most precious stuff for myself and leave the rest in the boat. Gonna let it stay there until it comes in handy.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="nsp_treasure_20_name">
    <text>In the swamp</text>
  </string>
  <string id="nsp_treasure_20_descr">
    <text>I dunno if this is a good idea, but this backpack is getting too heavy for me. Gonna have to leave some of the stuff. This log in the middle of the swamp should be secret enough.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="nsp_quest_treasure_1_name">
    <text>Unreachable stash</text>
  </string>
  <string id="nsp_quest_treasure_1_descr">
    <text>There's this stash in the area jam packed with stuff. The owner's long dead, and his stuff is just gathering dust.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="nsp_quest_treasure_2_name">
    <text>Hunter stash</text>
  </string>
  <string id="nsp_quest_treasure_2_descr">
    <text>This hunter shared some info on his stash. Didn't tell me what inside, but he himself doesn't look poor, so there should be something valuable in there.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="nsp_quest_treasure_3_name">
    <text>Fuse box</text>
  </string>
  <string id="nsp_quest_treasure_3_descr">
    <text>On behalf of our hunting community, I'm giving you the coordinates to one of our stashes. You've been a great help to us and we rarely go to that area, so take whatever you find.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="nsp_quest_treasure_4_name">
    <text>Stump by BTR</text>
  </string>
  <string id="nsp_quest_treasure_4_descr">
    <text>There's a well-hidden place with good loot near the army base. You can't argue that buying a stash in these areas is a great investment! There's always something to be found.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="nsp_quest_treasure_5_name">
    <text>Stalker stash</text>
  </string>
  <string id="nsp_quest_treasure_5_descr">
    <text>Played cards with a stalker and won, so I had him give up his stash coordinates. I'm sure he didn't have time to clean it out, 'cause the guy drank himself into a grave the very next day.</text>
  </string>
</string_table>