<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<string_table>
  <string id="mil_trader_start_dialog_0_1">
    <text>Come here, don't be shy!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_trader_start_dialog_0_2">
    <text>Come here, stalker! Take your pick!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_trader_start_dialog_0_3">
    <text>Take your pick from my goods, stalker!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_trader_start_dialog_1_1">
    <text>Oh, you're back! What've you got? Brought the cash?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_trader_start_dialog_1_2">
    <text>Hi there. Haven't seen you here before — got anything to share?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_trader_actor_break_dialog_0_1">
    <text>See you.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_trader_actor_break_dialog_0_2">
    <text>Until next time.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_trader_actor_break_dialog_0_3">
    <text>Bye.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_trader_second_actor_first_dialog_0">
    <text>Got any info to trade?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_trader_second_actor_first_dialog_1">
    <text>Come on in, stalker! Take your pick! Or do have something you want to unload and sell?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_trader_second_actor_first_dialog_2">
    <text>I'm looking for a stalker named Chord. You know him?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_trader_second_actor_first_dialog_3">
    <text>'Course I know the guy — he's in debt to me! I happen to be looking for him myself. He borrowed three ammo boxes from me and went off to god knows where!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_trader_second_actor_first_dialog_4">
    <text>I see we're rowing in the same direction. Tell me where I can find him, and I'll be your loan shark.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_trader_second_actor_first_dialog_5">
    <text>Alright then, let's give it a shot! He and his group made a small shelter here in the vicinity. Once you exit the village, cross the road and you'll see a wagon. That's where they might be. Go on, and give his ass a friendly reminder about his debt!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_trader_second_actor_first_dialog_6">
    <text>Roger that!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_merc_leader_start_dialog_0">
    <text>Why, hello, detective! I'm surprised you found the trail so quickly.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_merc_leader_start_dialog_1">
    <text>Is that you? You're one of those who were seen at the science facility...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_merc_leader_start_dialog_2">
    <text>Correct. Ever so diligently did you seek me, and here I am before you. What do you next?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_merc_leader_start_dialog_3">
    <text>Where's the professor?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_merc_leader_start_dialog_4">
    <text>The professor? Somewhere much better than in that sleazy joint of yours! You too had better choose the right side while you still have the chance.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_merc_leader_start_dialog_5">
    <text>The right side? You're a murderer! You killed people in this camp and the stalker at the Cordon. And the professor... you kidnapped him, didn't you?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_merc_leader_start_dialog_6">
    <text>Kidnapped? Ha-ha! He scurried away from you at the speed of light. He knew how thankless it is to be working for the government.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_merc_leader_start_dialog_7">
    <text>Who are you people?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_merc_leader_after_katakomb_dialog_0">
    <text>How are you doing, commander?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_merc_leader_after_katakomb_dialog_1">
    <text>Don't you "commander" me. We never finished our conversation. Who are you, and where's professor Dubinin?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_merc_leader_after_katakomb_dialog_2">
    <text>Explaining that would take too long for my liking, so let's put that aside while the bastards behind this are still breathing. You still need your things, don't you?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_merc_leader_after_katakomb_dialog_3">
    <text>What are you suggesting?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_merc_leader_after_katakomb_dialog_4">
    <text>We go find the assholes and throw a little reunion party. Come on, move your legs.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_merc_leader_after_katakomb_dialog_5">
    <text>You're in my sights, just so you know.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_trader_second_actor_after_katakomb_dialog_1_1">
    <text>I'm afraid he's not coming back. Chord and his group are dead.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_trader_second_actor_after_katakomb_dialog_1_2">
    <text>I was in Chord's camp. It would seem you know him... or, rather, *knew* him. Chord and his group are dead.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_trader_second_actor_after_katakomb_dialog_2">
    <text>Damn it!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_trader_second_actor_after_katakomb_dialog_3">
    <text>They killed them. Quick and silent. They had no idea what was coming.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_trader_second_actor_after_katakomb_dialog_4">
    <text>Why would they do that? What a pity about the boys... They helped me carry out my work and bring in loot. Shit, may they rest in peace with all the artifacts in the Zone...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_trader_second_actor_after_katakomb_dialog_5">
    <text>Just so happens I don't know jack about these parts. What's with those mercs nearby? They sure got some nerve.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_trader_second_actor_after_katakomb_dialog_6">
    <text>Ah, yeah, the mercs... You said it, they've got quite a pair! Here, you see my hand? Me neither! That's their doing, those bastards!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_trader_second_actor_after_katakomb_dialog_7">
    <text>Really? What happened?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_trader_second_actor_after_katakomb_dialog_8">
    <text>They came up to me some time ago to check my goods, and we had some disagreements on the price. They thought I was gonna cheat 'em! But I have nothing to hide, my business is fair and square... Then I see they have no shortage of cash, so I throw on another couple of grand. Then, all of a sudden, they pin down my hand and chop! Now they have it hanging in their camp like a souvenir...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_trader_second_actor_after_katakomb_dialog_9">
    <text>Have you heard about their "games"?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_trader_second_actor_after_katakomb_dialog_10">
    <text>Yup, I've heard all there is to know. For your information, they were quick to tell me that more of my body parts would be hanging in their camp if I tell anyone. Ah, shoot, I've already told you enough as it is...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_trader_second_actor_after_katakomb_dialog_11">
    <text>Don't fret. You won't be seeing them in the camp anymore. They picked the wrong man to play with.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_trader_second_actor_after_katakomb_dialog_12">
    <text>You're kidding? Well, I'll be! You made this old trader happy! It's no good thing getting your spirits up after people die, but it'd be a shame not to raise a drink to that! What do you say?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_trader_second_actor_after_katakomb_dialog_13">
    <text>That'd sure hit the spot.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_trader_second_actor_after_katakomb_dialog_14">
    <text>Also, what did you want from Chord's group? Aren't you the one who did them in?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_trader_second_actor_after_katakomb_dialog_15">
    <text>Me? No way. Do I look like a terminator to you?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_trader_second_actor_after_katakomb_dialog_16">
    <text>Then what happened to them?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_trader_second_actor_after_katakomb_dialog_17">
    <text>They were killed by the people I came here for in the first place. Haven't you seen groups of people armed to the teeth in these areas? Their uniforms are like nothing on this earth.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_trader_second_actor_after_katakomb_dialog_18">
    <text>I haven't seen them personally, but the locals have been talking about it. Then again, you see all kinds of people around here. What did Chord do to get on their bad side?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_trader_second_actor_after_katakomb_dialog_19">
    <text>They're in hiding, and Chord saw them and reported it. Shame he paid for it with his life. Where could they be? Maybe they've broken camp somewhere?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_trader_second_actor_after_katakomb_dialog_20">
    <text>Here? Doubt it. You have Freedom on the Barrier, the warehouses have been abandoned for who knows how long and the village is inhabited by bloodsuckers. You don't really have more secluded places than that. They're not from around here, that's for sure.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_trader_second_actor_after_katakomb_dialog_21">
    <text>What's up with the warehouses? Freedom used to have their base there, didn't they?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_trader_second_actor_after_katakomb_dialog_22">
    <text>They consolidated their forces on the Barrier, and that's where all of them have hunkered down. Regarding the warehouses, something really strange started appearing there. I don't know myself, but stalkers do their best to steer clear of that place. First of all, they have no business there, and second, folks have been seeing things there... ghosts or phantoms or whatever. Might be a controller — who knows.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_trader_second_actor_after_katakomb_dialog_23">
    <text>Alright, thanks for the info!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_trader_second_actor_after_katakomb_dialog_24">
    <text>Hold up a second. Who are *you*? What business do you have with those soldier boys?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_trader_second_actor_after_katakomb_dialog_25">
    <text>Just a guy with a job. On a mission to find them, and I aim to complete it.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_trader_second_actor_after_katakomb_dialog_26">
    <text>I see... a freelancer. Well, if you're looking for more work in my shop, just let me know. Your abilities would be very appreciated.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_trader_second_actor_after_katakomb_dialog_27">
    <text>Noted. But first I need finish my own business. Got any place I could doze off? I'm dead on my feet right now.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_trader_second_actor_after_katakomb_dialog_28">
    <text>No problem at all. There are a couple of spots here in the village where you can lay down. The sentries will keep you guarded.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_trader_second_actor_after_katakomb_dialog_29">
    <text>Thanks!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_soldier_sky_first_dialog_0">
    <text>How are you feeling? You look tired.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_soldier_sky_first_dialog_1">
    <text>It's nothing, I'm fine. Did you have any trouble on the way here?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_soldier_sky_first_dialog_2">
    <text>Everything went all right. We decided to avoid the Bar, though. So this means you've been all the talk on the stalker network? Shame about Koval.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_soldier_sky_first_dialog_3">
    <text>Without him, my dead body would've been all the talk and we likely wouldn't have tracked down the professor.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_soldier_sky_first_dialog_4">
    <text>What'd you find out?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_soldier_sky_first_dialog_5">
    <text>Not a whole lot. They killed the stalker that worked unofficially with the professor. He must've either known something important or crossed them. A few hours back, I had the opportunity of meeting with one of those people, and he told me we're better off giving up... or we'll end up just like him.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_soldier_sky_first_dialog_6">
    <text>And what are your thoughts?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_soldier_sky_first_dialog_7">
    <text>Our mission is to find professor Dubinin. We don't know who's threatening us or what their numbers are, nor do we know whether their threats are credible, but our objective stands.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_soldier_sky_first_dialog_8">
    <text>What do we know about Dubinin? Was he abducted?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_soldier_sky_first_dialog_9">
    <text>I highly doubt that. There's the chance that he left the facility willingly. We just have to find out why...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_soldier_sky_first_dialog_10">
    <text>What's the plan?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_soldier_sky_first_dialog_11">
    <text>We're close to our targets. We just have to find the area where they might've set up camp.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_soldier_sky_first_dialog_12">
    <text>I might just know how. They must have some radio frequency. I have equipment that might let us eavesdrop on them — just gotta find the right signal and track down its source. Though, we do need to find a high point to maximize the radius.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_soldier_sky_first_dialog_13">
    <text>There's an abandoned military base not far from here. Inside are watchtowers. Will that do?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_soldier_sky_first_dialog_14">
    <text>Worth a shot. Are we moving out?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_soldier_sky_first_dialog_15">
    <text>We're moving out, but be careful there. Not that long ago, the warehouses were held by fighters from Freedom, but they left the base in a hurry. Not only that, but the local stalkers also do their best to stay away. There's something not right there, so stay alert.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_soldier_sky_army_base_tower_dialog_0">
    <text>Phew. Looks like we made it through!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_soldier_sky_army_base_tower_dialog_1">
    <text>We need to hurry up before those ghosts give us more than we bargained for.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_soldier_sky_army_base_tower_dialog_2">
    <text>This device right here needs to be placed on a tower. I'll pick up the signal from below while our boys cover us, okay?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_soldier_sky_army_base_tower_dialog_3">
    <text>Sounds like a plan.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_soldier_sky_after_army_base_dialog_0">
    <text>We made it!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_soldier_sky_after_army_base_dialog_1">
    <text>Thank god. Any news? I heard some numbers while I was on the tower.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_soldier_sky_after_army_base_dialog_2">
    <text>The device did manage to intercept a few signals! Some of them obviously belong to the locals, but one of them — a really strong one — is being transmitted through an encrypted channel. Its source is somewhere around the crashed helicopter close to the trader's village.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_soldier_sky_after_army_base_dialog_3">
    <text>So there is use in going there! What about the numbers in the radio signals? Can we crack their meaning?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_soldier_sky_after_army_base_dialog_4">
    <text>I don't know yet. Seems like a numbers station — I have some experience with it from when I was a student. It'll definitely take me some time.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_soldier_sky_after_army_base_dialog_5">
    <text>Alright, we'll save it for later. Let's move out.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_soldier_sky_helicopter_psy_zone_dialog_0">
    <text>Here it is. There's enough psy-emissions here to give brain damage to my dead grandfather!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_soldier_sky_helicopter_psy_zone_dialog_1">
    <text>I see something in the helicopter. Looks like a well covered-up entrance.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_soldier_sky_helicopter_psy_zone_dialog_2">
    <text>Definitely. But our devices are going haywire from psy-emissions, so there's no way we're getting there. A few more steps toward that chopper and our brains are mush.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_soldier_sky_helicopter_psy_zone_dialog_3">
    <text>Any ideas?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_soldier_sky_helicopter_psy_zone_dialog_4">
    <text>Well, we're sure as hell not getting anywhere near there... at least without special protection.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_soldier_sky_helicopter_psy_zone_dialog_5">
    <text>Maybe Bison, the trader, can give us a hint, since he lives right next to that place. To the village!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_trader_after_army_base_dialog_0">
    <text>Hi there. I'm in urgent need of information.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_trader_after_army_base_dialog_1">
    <text>Oh, you again! Any luck with the needle in your haystack?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_trader_after_army_base_dialog_2">
    <text>That needle's not as tiny as you might think. As for the haystack, I hoped you might help me find out more about it.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_trader_after_army_base_dialog_3">
    <text>I'd rather not lose my other hand if I open my mouth about that. These people killed Chord and his group, and this is far from their first day in the Zone. No chance I'm risking my life by playing your games — I'm just a trader.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_trader_after_army_base_dialog_4">
    <text>If you're just a trader, why are you selling supplies in the Zone instead of selling melons on the market? You're undocumented, just like many others here. Provide me assistance and you can trade here as much as you want — the military won't harm a hair on your head.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_trader_after_army_base_dialog_5">
    <text>I knew it — you're with the army! Anyone could tell from a mile away. Should I be scared of you? I'm all set up — I knew who to pay for you to look the other way.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_trader_after_army_base_dialog_6">
    <text>Whoever you paid, I can guarantee you that refusing to cooperate with me will revoke all agreements. Everything you tell me stays between us.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_trader_after_army_base_dialog_7">
    <text>So what is it you're after?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_trader_after_army_base_dialog_8">
    <text>The helicopter near the village. What do you know about it?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_trader_after_army_base_dialog_9">
    <text>Just a regular helicopter that crashed to the ground. It's been there for ages. And don't even think about going there, or your head might just turn into a tea maker.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_trader_after_army_base_dialog_10">
    <text>Have any stalkers tried getting close to it?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_trader_after_army_base_dialog_11">
    <text>Why would they? The less clever ones here are culled way down at the Cordon or the Garbage. The ones who've made it this far have the brains not to wander into a psy-source.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_trader_after_army_base_dialog_12">
    <text>We need to examine that area. Maybe the emissions subside from time to time?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_trader_after_army_base_dialog_13">
    <text>Never heard about anything like that.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_trader_after_army_base_dialog_14">
    <text>Well, do you at least have any ideas? You'll get a fair compensation, hustler.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_trader_after_army_base_dialog_15">
    <text>Got no ideas, but I'll tell you about someone who's real interested in things like that. He's handy and a real brainiac, but boy, is he easily offended! He used to hang out with us in the village, fixing up equipment and electronics for the stalkers. After that, we had a little falling out, and now he exiled himself from our community. How about this: I'll give you his PDA ID number, and you convince him to return to the village. Tell him I'm ready to make an agreeable deal. Sound good?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_trader_after_army_base_dialog_16">
    <text>Sounds good.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_trader_after_army_base_dialog_17">
    <text>We have a deal, then! The ID number is in your PDA. Good luck!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_trader_after_army_base_dialog_18">
    <text>Thanks. I'm off.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_soldier_sky_stalker_technic_info_dialog_0">
    <text>What's new?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_soldier_sky_stalker_technic_info_dialog_1">
    <text>There's a man we need to find who will help us reach the helicopter. I have the his PDA's ID number. Can you track him down?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_soldier_sky_stalker_technic_info_dialog_2">
    <text>Sure thing. Give it here.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_soldier_sky_stalker_technic_info_dialog_3">
    <text>Excellent. Here's what we'll do: you stay in the village and try to decrypt the signals. If you intercept anything else, radio me. Vuslych will stay with you while Hottab heads off to watch over the helicopter — we need to keep track of any movements around it.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_soldier_sky_stalker_technic_info_dialog_4">
    <text>What about you? Are you heading out alone?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_soldier_sky_stalker_technic_info_dialog_5">
    <text>Having our entire squad move around the area is too risky. We've made enough noise already, and soon everyone will know we're here. That's why I'll go by myself.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_soldier_sky_stalker_technic_info_dialog_6">
    <text>Alright. I'm picking up his PDA signal. It's in the abandoned village across the road... the same one locals say is infested with bloodsuckers! You sure you'll be fine?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_soldier_sky_stalker_technic_info_dialog_7">
    <text>I'll be fine. What matters is finding that stalker in one piece. I better get moving.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_village_bloodsuckers_alive_first_dialog_0">
    <text>At least someone's alive!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_village_bloodsuckers_alive_first_dialog_1">
    <text>What are you doing there?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_village_bloodsuckers_alive_first_dialog_2">
    <text>Yeah, see, I climbed down this basement to clear it of loot! Kidding. I got stuck here while running from a bloodsucker!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_village_bloodsuckers_alive_first_dialog_3">
    <text>Alright. Sit tight while I deal with the bloodsuckers, or they'll give me a hard time getting you back up. I need to think of something.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_village_bloodsuckers_alive_second_dialog_0_1">
    <text>You done with the bloodsuckers yet?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_village_bloodsuckers_alive_second_dialog_0_2">
    <text>Did ya get 'em? The bloodsuckers?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_village_bloodsuckers_alive_second_dialog_0_3">
    <text>Are the bloodsuckers dead?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_village_bloodsuckers_alive_second_dialog_1_1">
    <text>Not yet. Wait a bit.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_village_bloodsuckers_alive_second_dialog_1_2">
    <text>Not all of them. Wait.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_village_bloodsuckers_alive_second_dialog_1_3">
    <text>Not yet. Sit tight just a bit longer.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_village_bloodsuckers_compl_first_dialog_0">
    <text>Finally, another soul around here!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_village_bloodsuckers_compl_first_dialog_1">
    <text>What are you doing there?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_village_bloodsuckers_compl_first_dialog_2">
    <text>Yeah, see, I climbed down this basement to clear it of loot! Kidding. I got stuck here while running from a bloodsucker!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_village_bloodsuckers_compl_first_dialog_3">
    <text>Just how do I get you out of there...?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_village_bloodsuckers_compl_second_dialog_0">
    <text>So, did you kill those monsters?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_village_bloodsuckers_compl_second_dialog_1">
    <text>Looks like I did. How am I getting you out of there?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_village_wait_ladder_dialog_0_1">
    <text>Where's the ladder, my friend?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_village_wait_ladder_dialog_0_2">
    <text>I'm already starting to feel off, man. Bring the ladder!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_village_wait_ladder_dialog_0_3">
    <text>Where's the ladder, stalker? Please, get me out of here!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_village_wait_ladder_dialog_1_1">
    <text>Don't worry. I'm about to get it.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_village_wait_ladder_dialog_1_2">
    <text>Calm down. I'll find it.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_village_wait_ladder_dialog_1_3">
    <text>Don't panic. I'll find you the ladder now.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_village_ladder_compl_dialog_0">
    <text>Finally, give it here!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_village_ladder_compl_dialog_1">
    <text>Step back. I'm dropping it.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_village_after_under_dialog_0">
    <text>Thanks, stalker! I thought I was done for without food in there. Rarely does anyone walk into this village.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_village_after_under_dialog_1">
    <text>What brought *you* here?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_village_after_under_dialog_2">
    <text>You see that? See the light that's shining, the fridge that's running, the radio that's sizzling?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_village_after_under_dialog_3">
    <text>Hard not to notice! There's a light flashing over the whole village.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_village_after_under_dialog_4">
    <text>Exactly, and I'm here to find out how. That equipment's been laying around here for who knows how long, and it recently started operating all of a sudden.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_village_after_under_dialog_5">
    <text>With all the bloodsuckers here, this isn't quite the place for science experiments! One of them seemed to conduct electricity.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_village_after_under_dialog_6">
    <text>Yup, that's the one I was running from when I went into the house. Is it safe outside? Did you get 'em all?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_village_after_under_dialog_7">
    <text>I dispatched some of them, but I'm sure there's more nearby.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_village_after_under_dialog_8">
    <text>I saw a sparkling transformer in the yard, and I think that's what's generating the energy. Will you help me get through to it? I'll make it worth your while!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_village_after_under_dialog_9">
    <text>What's your name?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_village_after_under_dialog_10">
    <text>Marmot.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_village_after_under_dialog_11">
    <text>Alright, Marmot, you've convinced me. Lead on.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_village_final_dialog_0">
    <text>Now that was really something! Ever seen anything like that?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_village_final_dialog_1">
    <text>I sure haven't. This artifact powered all the electronics in the village?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_village_final_dialog_2">
    <text>As you saw yourself, everything went dark when I brought it out. Now I won't be having any electricity problems in my shack!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_village_final_dialog_3">
    <text>You have a shack?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_village_final_dialog_4">
    <text>'Course I do! I'm not staying around on the farm with that swindler!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_village_final_dialog_5">
    <text>You mean the trader?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_village_final_dialog_6">
    <text>That's right. So, let's get out of here, huh? The locals are gonna get suspicious about the power going out again... Let's head over to my place, 'cause your gear is just screaming for repairs. Let's call that my token of appreciation!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_village_final_dialog_7">
    <text>You're right about that. Let's go.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_hut_start_dialog_0">
    <text>And here we are!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_hut_start_dialog_1">
    <text>What were you thinking making shelter here of all places?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_hut_start_dialog_2">
    <text>What? It's a good spot! Sure, the marsh is stinky and all, but there are plenty of mines around to keep the mutants away.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_hut_start_dialog_3">
    <text>Aren't you afraid of other stalkers?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_hut_start_dialog_4">
    <text>On the contrary: nobody goes snooping around here. They're afraid of what's started happening in the military base.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_hut_start_dialog_5">
    <text>And you *aren't* afraid?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_hut_start_dialog_6">
    <text>I never even go there. Sometimes, I'm tempted to... There must be all kinds of useful stuff there after the military and Freedom left, but just the thought of going there gives me the creeps! Anyway, who are you? I haven't seen you here before.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_hut_start_dialog_7">
    <text>I'm a stalker. Sparrow's the name.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_hut_start_dialog_8">
    <text>You don't really look like a stalker.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_hut_start_dialog_9">
    <text>How come?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_hut_start_dialog_10">
    <text>Any stalker would've had their eyes lit up after seeing the artifact we found in the village, but you don't even seem to care!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_hut_start_dialog_11">
    <text>I'm here on other business. I need to get inside the cabin of the helicopter that crashed not far from here, but there are psy-emissions there. There's no way through, and I have no idea how to get past them.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_hut_start_dialog_12">
    <text>And here I thought you came across me in the village by sheer chance. What, were you looking for me?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_hut_start_dialog_13">
    <text>What are you, a mind-reader? Can't hide anything from you!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_hut_start_dialog_14">
    <text>No, it's just that this all seems a bit too convenient. I needed your help, you needed mine.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_hut_start_dialog_15">
    <text>Well, I just helped you. Will you help me now?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_hut_start_dialog_16">
    <text>What's your business with that helicopter, anyway?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_hut_start_dialog_17">
    <text>I need to find the black box that was inside.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_hut_start_dialog_18">
    <text>Hah. And what black box is that? That helicopter crashed here in the past century. It's long since been dismantled.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_hut_start_dialog_19">
    <text>To me, it's worth the risk. Will you help?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_hut_start_dialog_20">
    <text>You need protection. I can make it — even have some experience.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_hut_start_dialog_21">
    <text>Yeah? From where?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_hut_start_dialog_22">
    <text>Back when the Scorcher was still operational, stalkers used to come to me. We'd assemble these special helmets to break through to Pripyat.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_hut_start_dialog_23">
    <text>Did it work?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_hut_start_dialog_24">
    <text>No. They died near the Radar.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_hut_start_dialog_25">
    <text>That's very encouraging.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_hut_start_dialog_26">
    <text>They died, but they made it a lot further than anyone without protection. The psy-emissions around the helicopter aren't that strong, so it might just be enough. There's just one thing...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_hut_start_dialog_27">
    <text>What's that?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_hut_start_dialog_28">
    <text>My resources are finite. For me to assemble a helmet again, I'll need spare parts... and right now, I'm all out of those.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_hut_start_dialog_29">
    <text>Where can we find them?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_hut_start_dialog_30">
    <text>Technically, we can find them some three hundred meters away from us.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_hut_start_dialog_31">
    <text>The military base?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_hut_start_dialog_32">
    <text>Bingo! I've had my eyes on it for a long time, but I've been dreading going there alone, and no one's wanted to keep me company.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_hut_start_dialog_33">
    <text>I take it you have a special interest in it?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_hut_start_dialog_34">
    <text>Of course I do: think about all the useful toys you could find in their warehouse. I also need something to help me climb the stalker ladder. Gotta fix up the house in the marsh, plant a few more mines around the edges, set up a strong signal... The only place where I can find all of that is the military base.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_hut_start_dialog_35">
    <text>So, we're heading in the same direction. But I'd rather carry out the search ASAP.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_hut_start_dialog_36">
    <text>We could head out right now.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_hut_start_dialog_37">
    <text>Great. Let's move!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_army_base_warehouse_vodka_dialog_0">
    <text>That phantom seems miserable without his drink. C'mon, give him a bottle and something might just happen.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_army_base_warehouse_vodka_dialog_1">
    <text>I'll give it a shot.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_army_base_warehouse_final_dialog_0">
    <text>Everything clear? That phantom in front of the warehouse is making my skin crawl...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_army_base_warehouse_final_dialog_1">
    <text>Clear. What've you got?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_army_base_warehouse_final_dialog_2">
    <text>I think the materials we found will be enough to assemble a helm.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_army_base_warehouse_final_dialog_3">
    <text>Just one helm?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_army_base_warehouse_final_dialog_4">
    <text>Just one. What, you need more?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_army_base_warehouse_final_dialog_5">
    <text>That would come in very handy.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_army_base_warehouse_final_dialog_6">
    <text>If you know of any other haunted military base in the vicinity, let me know and we'll go there together. Then we'll make another pair of helmets!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_army_base_warehouse_final_dialog_7">
    <text>Fine, one's enough... Now let's get the hell out of here.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_psy_helm_final_dialog_0">
    <text>Pretty sure my hands remember what to do. I'll try to assemble it now...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_psy_helm_final_dialog_1">
    <text>Will it take long?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_psy_helm_final_dialog_2">
    <text>Where are you hurrying off to? Your helicopter's not going anywhere, don't worry about it!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_psy_helm_final_dialog_3">
    <text>Still.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_psy_helm_final_dialog_4">
    <text>About an hour. I've made five pieces like this before. Got the schematics — the rest is just technique.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_psy_helm_final_dialog_5">
    <text>You sure it'll work? I'd rather not have my brains scorched like your other pals.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_psy_helm_final_dialog_6">
    <text>Hey, now you're just hurting my feelings! Do you think I'd let down the man who saved me? By the way, thanks again for that!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_psy_helm_final_dialog_7">
    <text>Likewise. How did you get into tech work?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_psy_helm_final_dialog_8">
    <text>When I came to the Zone, I didn't know a wrench from a screwdriver. After that, I met a man in the swamps. Back then, I went there with a few stalkers to go looking for artifacts, and we all ended up in some trouble.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_psy_helm_final_dialog_9">
    <text>You sure talking won't distract you?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_psy_helm_final_dialog_10">
    <text>Nah. I like having a conversation.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_psy_helm_final_dialog_11">
    <text>If you say so. You went to the swamps, then what?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_psy_helm_final_dialog_12">
    <text>Well, at that point, our backpacks were stuffed with artifacts. I mean, the Swamps aren't as well-charted as the Cordon, so we were real lucky to get the good stuff.\n \nWe were walking, silence all around. Then our PDAs blow up with messages that an emission's coming! We looked around — spotted some abandoned farm, then made our way there to wait out the emission. We almost made it, but then something came out storming from the reeds... a pack of some thirty boars, swept us like a damn tidal wave! We opened fire on them, but you can imagine it was as good as useless. I have no idea how many of those hogs stampeded over me, but I was down on the ground and couldn't feel a thing, and then I passed out.\n \nWhen I woke up, I was in a bed. Legs, hands, ribs — everything was broken, my whole body was aching all over, bruises from head to toe. Just breathing hurt. I later found out I was saved by one of the local stalkers, who lived alone on the edge of the swamps.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_psy_helm_final_dialog_13">
    <text>The Swamp Doctor?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_psy_helm_final_dialog_14">
    <text>I thought the same when I came to, but no. He introduced himself as Ivan, though something tells me that's not his real name. Said he found me half-dead on the bank of the swamp. Brought me to his camp, patched up my wounds, and splinted my fractures. He tells me, "You'll have to lay here for a month, whether that's to your liking or not."</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_psy_helm_final_dialog_15">
    <text>What about the rest?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_psy_helm_final_dialog_16">
    <text>Nothing and no one around. The others were gone, my backpack with the loot was gone... Even my weapons were gone. They left me there at the Zone's mercy.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_psy_helm_final_dialog_17">
    <text>Some real friends you had there.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_psy_helm_final_dialog_18">
    <text>They were never my friends. We met in the village and agreed to go after loot together, nothing more.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_psy_helm_final_dialog_19">
    <text>But they must've had some humanity in them. Just leaving you in the swamps to die, that's...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_psy_helm_final_dialog_20">
    <text>While I was recovering, I thought about that too. Every day I thought, "Soon as I'm on my feet, I'm gonna find them and fill them with lead!" But Ivan knocked some sense into me. Told me that, when he found me, I looked like fresh kill... not to mention the emission was getting closer every second. Had they tried to save me, we'd all be goners. Point is, Ivan taught me a lot of things, like cleaning your weapon or patching up your suit, even taught me a thing or two about radio electronics. Everything I know? It's thanks to Ivan. I didn't spend one month in that camp, as he initially thought, but ten... but for one man to teach me so much was by far worth the wounds I received.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_psy_helm_final_dialog_21">
    <text>What happened after that?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_psy_helm_final_dialog_22">
    <text>After that, I went back to the Cordon, to live the normal stalker life again. A couple of months after that, I wanted to pay Ivan a visit, bring him some vodka and snacks, give him a proper thank you... but, when I arrived, his home was empty. He left. I never managed to see him again. I hope he's alive and well. If it wasn't for him, you and I wouldn't be having this conversation.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_psy_helm_final_dialog_23">
    <text>How did you end up near the warehouses, then?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_psy_helm_final_dialog_24">
    <text>The local trader, Bison, decided to open up shop here. He invited me over and told me, "I'll give you a few percentages if you help fix stalkers' equipment." He pretty much wanted to have his own little Bar, but way up north in the Zone, for stalkers to fix their things and buy supplies. Not long after, though, it's like he went off the handle: he used to be quite generous with money, but eventually went as far as to demand it from me. "Don't go making a business out of your repairs. You're leaving me with nothing!" I said, "screw this," and left them.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_psy_helm_final_dialog_25">
    <text>That's fair. He did ask me to talk to you about returning.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_psy_helm_final_dialog_26">
    <text>Oh, so you know him? You can tell him there's no way I'm going back there!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_psy_helm_final_dialog_27">
    <text>He promised to work with you on mutually beneficial terms.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_psy_helm_final_dialog_28">
    <text>I'm fine right where I am.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_psy_helm_final_dialog_29">
    <text>But you're all alone here. There are stalkers in the camp to help you if anything happens.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_psy_helm_final_dialog_30">
    <text>See, that's why I went to the warehouses: I found a few mines there. Tomorrow I'm setting it all up, and nobody's getting on my property without my consent. Only after that will I tell the stalkers I can fix their equipment. There will always be a client in these parts.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_psy_helm_final_dialog_31">
    <text>Suit yourself. How's it going with the assembly?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_psy_helm_final_dialog_32">
    <text>Just a little more! Who are you, anyway? I must've bored you out of your mind going on about myself.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_psy_helm_final_dialog_33">
    <text>Not at all. I'll tell you if you promise to keep your lips sealed.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_psy_helm_final_dialog_34">
    <text>I'm no snitch. Don't worry your head about it.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_psy_helm_final_dialog_35">
    <text>I'm a military stalker. I'm on a mission here.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_psy_helm_final_dialog_36">
    <text>Hold up... You're a soldier?!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_psy_helm_final_dialog_37">
    <text>Not quite. A military stalker, just like any other stalker, but on more formal footing. Don't worry, my responsibilities don't include searching and capturing undocumented stalkers.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_psy_helm_final_dialog_38">
    <text>So what is it that you do?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_psy_helm_final_dialog_39">
    <text>Ordinary soldiers rarely venture beyond the Cordon or science facilities, and that's where we come in. I must say, you seem like quite the clever fellow — just the type of man we need. Think about it: the salary's handsome. You'll get to do your thing while being out of harm's way.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_psy_helm_final_dialog_40">
    <text>Hm. I appreciate the offer, but...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_psy_helm_final_dialog_41">
    <text>Whatever the case, nice to meet you. I hope we'll see each other again.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_psy_helm_final_dialog_42">
    <text>I hope so too. Now, here's what you've been waiting for — take it!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_psy_helm_final_dialog_43">
    <text>Does it work?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_psy_helm_final_dialog_44">
    <text>It works! Just keep in mind that the helm heats up rapidly, so don't spend too much time inside the psy-emissions. If you start feeling a headache, get out of there in an instant. I'm no master at my craft, but it should give you the time you need to figure out what's what about the helicopter cabin.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_psy_helm_final_dialog_45">
    <text>Thanks. Time for me to go. Stay safe, Marmot!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_soldier_sky_helicopter_final_dialog_0">
    <text>Any news?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_soldier_sky_helicopter_final_dialog_1">
    <text>A local craftsman assembled a psy-helm for me. I need to climb down while they're still there and end this once and for all.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_soldier_sky_helicopter_final_dialog_2">
    <text>Just one? What about us? Going there alone is suicide. We don't even know their numbers!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_soldier_sky_helicopter_final_dialog_3">
    <text>Do we have a choice? You heard everything yourself. They already know we're here, and they're already preparing to cut and run. It's now or never. You stay here, watch the area, and keep me in touch if you manage to intercept any more talks.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_soldier_sky_helicopter_final_dialog_4">
    <text>Well, alright... Are you really sure about this?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_soldier_sky_helicopter_final_dialog_5">
    <text>Yes. I didn't wait months for a real mission only to back out in the last moment.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_soldier_sky_helicopter_final_dialog_6">
    <text>Just don't get yourself killed if you start smelling something burning. If they leave, we'll track 'em down again. Just make sure you don't get your ass shot to hell!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_soldier_sky_helicopter_final_dialog_7">
    <text>Look who's talking. Who was it that wanted to continue when we stormed the power plant, in spite of my orders?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_soldier_sky_helicopter_final_dialog_8">
    <text>Hah. Back then, I was the one listening to you... and now I'm asking you to listen to me. If you feel outgunned, pull back.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_soldier_sky_helicopter_final_dialog_9">
    <text>I won't go Rambo, but you and the other men are to keep your eyes open. I was attacked several hours ago, and they could show up here too. We'll talk later!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_idle_dialog_0_1">
    <text>Glad to see you!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_idle_dialog_0_2">
    <text>Hey there!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_idle_dialog_0_3">
    <text>Go on. What've you got?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_idle_dialog_0_1">
    <text>Glad to see you!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_idle_dialog_0_2">
    <text>Let's hear it, stalker!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_idle_dialog_0_3">
    <text>I'm listening, friend.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_idle_dialog_1_1">
    <text>Bye.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_idle_dialog_1_2">
    <text>I'm going.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mil_stalker_technic_idle_dialog_1_3">
    <text>'Til next time.</text>
  </string>
</string_table>
