<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<string_table>
  <string id="bar_staff_barman_idle_dialog_0_1">
    <text>Hey, man.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_staff_barman_idle_dialog_0_2">
    <text>Come to rest, traveler?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_staff_barman_idle_dialog_0_3">
    <text>Need anything? I don't bite.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_staff_barman_idle_dialog_0_4">
    <text>So, how's it going?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_staff_barman_idle_dialog_0_5">
    <text>Hey, stalker.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_staff_barman_idle_dialog_0_6">
    <text>In need of equipment?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_staff_barman_idle_dialog_0_7">
    <text>You here on business, or?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_staff_barman_idle_dialog_0_8">
    <text>Come to drink or buy something?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_staff_barman_idle_dialog_0_9">
    <text>Got questions? I'm listening.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_staff_barman_idle_dialog_0_10">
    <text>Go ahead. Ask me questions if you have any.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_arena_man_job_0">
    <text>Go on...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_arena_man_job_11">
    <text>Your opponent for the first fight is cut from the same meat as you. The man has health problems, and he decided to spend the last of his energy in the arena. Both of you will fight with pistols — for now, neither of you are worthy of anything more. Right, now go get him or die. Move out!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_arena_man_job_111">
    <text>I'll try.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_arena_man_job_112">
    <text>Not now.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_arena_man_job_12">
    <text>Your last fight didn't mean shit. You're still the same old piece of meat, so not a lot of people will bet on you. If you want to earn decently, you'll have to step onto the arena more than just this once. Your opponent also got through the first round, and with ease. Ready to show once more what you're made of? After this fight, the stakes will start rising — all you have to do is survive. Ready?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_arena_man_job_121">
    <text>Let's go.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_arena_man_job_122">
    <text>Not ready yet.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_arena_man_job_13">
    <text>The first two fights are done. From our first meeting, all I could see was bark, but you've shown your bite. It's time we test you in a real fight. You'll be facing two bandits that should already be familiar to you — the very same ones who caught you near the Bar! Imagine that those degenerates were practically on their knees begging for mercy before us. The Duty boys gave it some thought and decided to throw them onto the arena. Ready to bring back justice and hand the bandits their own asses?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_arena_man_job_131">
    <text>Let's get this over with!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_arena_man_job_132">
    <text>I'll come back later.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_arena_man_job_14">
    <text>I can now confidently say that you are a fighter. It's time for you to meet an opponent no less serious than the ones you've faced before. This one is a seasoned stalker who's seen a lot in his lifetime, so keep your eyes peeled. We doing this?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_arena_man_job_141">
    <text>Let's do this.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_arena_man_job_142">
    <text>I'll drop by later.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_arena_man_job_15">
    <text>This next fight promises to be interesting... if, of course, you agree to it. You'll be facing four meat chunks that have never once seen battle. It'll be tough, but I believe you'll handle it. You'll be handed good equipment. Now, go out and kick their slimy asses!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_arena_man_job_151">
    <text>They're dead meat!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_arena_man_job_152">
    <text>Another time.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_arena_man_job_16">
    <text>It'll be tough this time around. You'll have to defeat three slobs from Freedom who were heading to the Bar, likely to sabotage. As you can see, didn't work out for them. Ready to give out an ass-kicking?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_arena_man_job_161">
    <text>Ready.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_arena_man_job_162">
    <text>Not now.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_arena_man_job_17">
    <text>There's one fight left for you to overcome before entering the final. Ready for this? Three highly experienced stalkers will be facing you, all armed to the teeth. I suggest you think things through before you go on this.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_arena_man_job_171">
    <text>Let's get on with it.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_arena_man_job_172">
    <text>Not ready yet.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_arena_man_job_18">
    <text>The last fight awaits you. Don't rush into this one — you won't know the specifics of the fight until you step onto the arena. It could end very badly for you, but if you win, believe me when I say the whole Zone will know about you. So, will you back out before it's too late?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_arena_man_job_181">
    <text>Let's do this. I finish what I start.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_arena_man_job_182">
    <text>I'll need some time for this.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_arena_man_start_11">
    <text>Yo! I've got a new fight for you.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_arena_man_start_21">
    <text>Go have a drink or something. The arena ain't ready yet.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_arena_man_start_31">
    <text>You've already become a pro!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_arena_man_start_41">
    <text>You won! Here's your reward.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_arena_man_start_51">
    <text>You're not experienced enough for this fight.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_arena_manager_reward_dialog_0_1">
    <text>Your first fight wasn't that tough, but there'll be more in store for you. Come by in a day, 'cause we'll need time to clean up the body from the arena... that, and time to relax some.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_arena_manager_reward_dialog_1_1">
    <text>See you.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_arena_manager_reward_dialog_0_2">
    <text>Well, what a fight! Here, you deserve this. If you decide you want more, come by in twenty-four hours.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_arena_manager_reward_dialog_1_2">
    <text>Thanks. See you.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_arena_manager_reward_dialog_0_3">
    <text>You really showed them, kid! Congratulations on winning — here's your prize. Get ready for the next fight!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_arena_manager_reward_dialog_1_3">
    <text>Thank you.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_arena_manager_reward_dialog_0_4">
    <text>You've crossed the season half. With your achievements, you have a chance of reaching the finals. Here's your reward.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_arena_manager_reward_dialog_1_4">
    <text>Thank you. See you later.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_arena_manager_reward_dialog_0_5">
    <text>Man, you never cease to impress the crowd. You have a huge potential! Take your reward.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_arena_manager_reward_dialog_1_5">
    <text>Thanks. I hope it'll continue like this.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_arena_manager_reward_dialog_0_6">
    <text>Congratulations, stalker! Here's your reward, fair and square.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_arena_manager_reward_dialog_1_6">
    <text>Thank you.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_arena_manager_reward_dialog_0_7">
    <text>You're just one step away from the title of master! Here's your reward. Come back again for the final fight!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_arena_manager_reward_dialog_1_7">
    <text>You bet.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_arena_manager_reward_dialog_0_8">
    <text>Congratulations on the magnificent title of Master of the Arena, you living legend! Here's your modest reward. And that's not all: soon, everyone will know your name!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_arena_manager_reward_dialog_1_8">
    <text>Thanks, Arnie! I'll need to come to my senses after a fight like that.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_arena_manager_wait_fight_dialog_0_1">
    <text>Hold on, gladiator. The arena needs to be sparkling clean for the next fight.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_arena_manager_wait_fight_dialog_0_2">
    <text>The Arena's closed right now. Come back later.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_arena_manager_wait_fight_dialog_0_3">
    <text>We're not hosting any fights right now. Go hang out somewhere else for a while.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_duty_base_main_post_soldier_boss_start_dialog_0_1">
    <text>Hold your horses. Entrance is restricted to our list of authorized personnel... and you, stalker, are not on that list. So make a one-eighty right back to where you came.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_duty_base_main_post_soldier_boss_start_dialog_0_2">
    <text>Our territory's closed at the moment. Turn back, stalker.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_duty_base_main_post_soldier_boss_start_dialog_1_1">
    <text>And how does one get on that list?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_duty_base_main_post_soldier_boss_start_dialog_1_2">
    <text>Closed? Like, closed closed?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_duty_base_main_post_soldier_boss_start_dialog_2_1_1">
    <text>Prove yourself among the locals. Start with some work from the Barkeep, and then we'll see if you can hold your weight.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_duty_base_main_post_soldier_boss_start_dialog_2_1_2">
    <text>Closed closed. Now, please don't bother me. Duty calls.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_duty_base_main_post_soldier_boss_start_dialog_2_2">
    <text>Prove yourself among the loc... Wait, aren't you Axe? Sergeant Lyubeznov told me about you. Go on ahead, but don't do anything stupid.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_duty_base_main_post_soldier_boss_start_dialog_3_1_1">
    <text>Bye then, commander.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_duty_base_main_post_soldier_boss_start_dialog_3_1_2">
    <text>I understand, sir.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_duty_base_main_post_soldier_boss_start_dialog_3_2">
    <text>Thank you, commander! Don't worry, I don't make trouble.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_duty_base_main_post_soldier_boss_second_dialog_0_1">
    <text>Do I need to repeat myself? This area is off-limits.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_duty_base_main_post_soldier_boss_second_dialog_0_2">
    <text>Did I not make myself clear? This territory is off-limits, stalker, so get going!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_duty_base_main_post_soldier_boss_second_dialog_1_1_1">
    <text>I'm going, commander.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_duty_base_main_post_soldier_boss_second_dialog_1_1_2">
    <text>My bad, sir. I'm going.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_duty_base_main_post_soldier_boss_second_dialog_1_2">
    <text>Why the fuss, commander?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_duty_base_main_post_soldier_boss_second_dialog_2">
    <text>Wait, aren't you Axe? Sergeant Lyubeznov told me about you. Go on ahead, but don't do anything stupid.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_duty_base_main_post_soldier_boss_second_dialog_3">
    <text>Thank you! Don't worry, commander, I'm no troublemaker.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_asshole_start_dialog_0">
    <text>Hold on, stalker. I need urgent help with something. Got a moment?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_asshole_start_dialog_1_1">
    <text>What needs doing?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_asshole_start_dialog_1_2">
    <text>I'll come by later.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_asshole_start_dialog_2">
    <text>I sent a couple of my boys to search for artifacts at the chemical anomaly at the Garbage. They radioed in, said they got what they needed, but at the very last minute, bandits turned up from the nearby farm and started shaking them down. That was the last I heard from them. They didn't have a lot on them... but the bandits demand a ransom regardless.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_asshole_start_dialog_3_1">
    <text>Sad to hear. The bandits have gone far off the rails — I did rescue a stalker's lucky friend not along ago. What do you need help with?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_asshole_start_dialog_3_2">
    <text>Sad to hear. The bandits have gone far off the rails. I saw a stalker not long ago — his own comrades were nearly taken as slaves. What do you need help with?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_asshole_start_dialog_4">
    <text>We need to save them. While I'm better at trading info than holding a gun, I need my comrades alive. The locals won't help me; I only know a couple of people from the Garbage. If you're up for it, you could meet up with them, then show up at the bandits' doorstep and let 'em have it.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_asshole_start_dialog_5_1">
    <text>Not much of a combatant myself. Don't suppose you have someone to send to help me?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_asshole_start_dialog_5_2">
    <text>Perhaps there are other options? They did ask for a ransom. How much?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_asshole_start_dialog_6_1">
    <text>I'll drop a line to the Garbage stalkers. Take these coords; you'll meet up near the bandit camp and make swiss cheese out of those bastards. Don't worry — I'll make it worth your while.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_asshole_start_dialog_6_2">
    <text>Look, I can't afford that ransom, and the locals are just as broke, which puts loans out of the question. We'll have to deal with the bandits the hard way... I'll drop a line to the Garbage stalkers so you can meet up with them near the bandit camp. Don't worry — you'll still get a proper reward.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_asshole_start_dialog_7_1">
    <text>Alright. Let's see what we can do.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_asshole_start_dialog_7_2">
    <text>To be honest with you, I don't like this. Go find someone else.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_asshole_second_dialog_0">
    <text>Man, help me free my boys. These Bar bastards won't!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_asshole_second_dialog_1_1">
    <text>I'll see what I can do... Send me the coordinates to the meeting place.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_asshole_second_dialog_1_2">
    <text>Count me out of it.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_asshole_second_dialog_2">
    <text>Here. They'll be waiting for you near the bandit camp. I'll make it worth your while!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_asshole_second_dialog_3">
    <text>Alright. I'll help you save your comrades.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_asshole_task_wait_dialog_0">
    <text>So, how's it coming along?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_asshole_task_wait_dialog_1">
    <text>Don't worry. We'll save your comrades.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_robbery_bandit_dialog_0">
    <text>Ugh, stalker... Don't just stand there, give me a medkit!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_robbery_bandit_dialog_1">
    <text>Just how did you end up near the Bar, scum?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_robbery_bandit_dialog_2">
    <text>What damn difference does it make?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_robbery_bandit_dialog_3">
    <text>Who did this to you?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_robbery_bandit_dialog_4">
    <text>Duty and their stalker pals... Just give me a medkit already!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_robbery_bandit_dialog_5">
    <text>I don't quite believe you.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_staff_barman_after_robbery_dialog_0">
    <text>Rise and shine, stalker.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_staff_barman_after_robbery_dialog_1">
    <text>Where am I, and who are you?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_staff_barman_after_robbery_dialog_2">
    <text>I'm Barkeep. You're in the area around the Rostok factory, in the Bar. The Duty boys brought you in here — said they rescued you from some bandits. I don't know the details, so you'd better ask them yourself. They hang out nearby.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_staff_barman_after_robbery_dialog_3_1">
    <text>How long was I out for? Where's my stuff?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_staff_barman_after_robbery_dialog_3_2">
    <text>How long was I out for?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_staff_barman_after_robbery_dialog_4_1">
    <text>Almost twenty-four hours. Your wounds weren't all that serious, and I looked after you in between orders. I've got your stuff, take it.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_staff_barman_after_robbery_dialog_4_2">
    <text>Almost twenty-four hours. Your wounds weren't all that serious, and I looked after you in between orders. Your belongings are here, in the blue box, as you must've noticed.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_staff_barman_after_robbery_dialog_5">
    <text>I owe you folks my life. Is there anything I can do for you?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_staff_barman_after_robbery_dialog_6">
    <text>Right now, I don't need anything. You'd better go and talk to your saviors. I need to get back to the counter.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_staff_barman_after_robbery_dialog_7">
    <text>Deal. If you need anything, I'll be glad to help.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_duty_help_soldier_after_robbery_dialog_0">
    <text>Well, look who pulled through! How are you holding up?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_duty_help_soldier_after_robbery_dialog_1">
    <text>Feeling better. Thanks for saving me.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_duty_help_soldier_after_robbery_dialog_2">
    <text>Believe it or not, it all happened by accident. I went behind the hangar to leak and overheard the bandits talking — you know the rest.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_duty_help_soldier_after_robbery_dialog_3">
    <text>Hell, I'll take it. What happens now to those scumbags? Are they still alive?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_duty_help_soldier_after_robbery_dialog_4">
    <text>Alive and kicking... in our base, behind bars. Still haven't figured out what to do with 'em. If they don't face the firing squad, they'll face each other in the Arena. We'll be selling tickets at a discount for that one.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_duty_help_soldier_after_robbery_dialog_5">
    <text>I see... The Arena, you say? The one where participants fight to the death for money?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_duty_help_soldier_after_robbery_dialog_6">
    <text>That's the one. If you're up for it, you could try it yourself. Don't worry, your first opponent will be a piece of cake.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_duty_help_soldier_after_robbery_dialog_7">
    <text>I'll keep that in mind. How can I return your favor? If not for you, they'd already have dug my grave.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_duty_help_soldier_after_robbery_dialog_8">
    <text>Well, I do have a couple things that I'd deal with... if I had the time. I only get two hours a day to rest up at the fire — Duty always calls, hah! So, could you rush off to the Garbage when you have a moment? I was gonna get a birthday present from a friend among the stalkers, but he got suspended here after causing trouble at the checkpoint.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_duty_help_soldier_after_robbery_dialog_9">
    <text>Well, happy late birthday, then! I think I know exactly who he is, and what he's been up to. Is it Korvalol?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_duty_help_soldier_after_robbery_dialog_10">
    <text>That's him, alright. That boy runs his mouth more than a Monolith preacher... I saved his ass once, which is how we got to know each other, but that's a different story. I'll tell him you're on the way.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_duty_help_soldier_after_robbery_dialog_11">
    <text>Sure thing. I'll go get his present for you. Where's he at?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_duty_help_soldier_after_robbery_dialog_12">
    <text>He's hanging with the stalkers, squandering artifacts on drinks... as usual.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_duty_help_soldier_after_robbery_dialog_13">
    <text>Right then. I'll head to the Garbage. Got some business there anyway.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_duty_help_soldier_idle_dialog_0_1">
    <text>So, how's it going?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_duty_help_soldier_idle_dialog_0_2">
    <text>Hey.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_duty_help_soldier_idle_dialog_0_3">
    <text>Glad to see ya.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_duty_help_soldier_idle_dialog_1_1">
    <text>Bye.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_duty_help_soldier_idle_dialog_1_2">
    <text>I'll be going.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_duty_help_soldier_idle_dialog_1_3">
    <text>See you.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_duty_help_soldier_present_dialog_0">
    <text>How's your shift, sergeant? I brought you a little something from Korvalol.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_duty_help_soldier_present_dialog_1">
    <text>No biggie, I'll survive! What've you got?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_duty_help_soldier_present_dialog_2_1">
    <text>He asked me to give you this lost dog tag and this artifact.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_duty_help_soldier_present_dialog_2_2">
    <text>He asked me to give you this dog tag.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_duty_help_soldier_present_dialog_3_1">
    <text>Woah! That's it, that's the one! I lost this dog tag in the Garbage a while back when we got drunk off our asses. Man... Big thanks to you! It belongs to my comrade-in-arms — he's been on the outside for a long time now, recovering from some disease. Hope he's still okay... And look at this artifact! Never have I seen or held the likes of it before. Thank you so much, man!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_duty_help_soldier_present_dialog_3_2">
    <text>Woah! That's it, that's the one! I lost this dog tag in the Garbage a while back when we got drunk off our asses. Man... Big thanks to you! It belongs to my comrade-in-arms — he's been on the outside for a long time now, recovering from some disease. Hope he's still okay...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_duty_help_soldier_present_dialog_4_1">
    <text>I'm glad I could help. And again, happy birthday. Let me know if you need anything.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_duty_help_soldier_present_dialog_4_2">
    <text>I'm glad I could help. And again, happy birthday. Tell me if you need anything.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_duty_help_soldier_present_dialog_5_1">
    <text>Hold up. While we were shaking down the bandits to take them away, we found this key — said to open a stash of theirs. I haven't had the time to use it, so I suppose I'll give it to you. Besides, we're not too interested in junk stalkers pilfer up in the Zone, and Duty's always well supplied. So here you go. As for me, it's about time I unglue my ass and get to my post.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_duty_help_soldier_present_dialog_5_2">
    <text>Alright. See you soon.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_duty_help_soldier_present_dialog_6_1">
    <text>Well, thanks. I'll definitely check it out. See you later!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_duty_help_soldier_present_dialog_6_2">
    <text>Bye, sergeant.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_master_prisoner_reward_dialog_0">
    <text>Hey, stalker! Fancy meeting you here!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_master_prisoner_reward_dialog_1">
    <text>Likewise, wanderer. Back on your feet, I see?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_master_prisoner_reward_dialog_2">
    <text>Sure as hell am! They'd have gone through with their plan and whacked me by now if it wasn't for you, so thanks again. That is something I'll be remembering for life, so take this and maybe you'll remember too.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_master_prisoner_reward_dialog_3">
    <text>Oh, please. Any stalker brother would've done the same. As for the gun, I could imagine it anywhere but in my own hands... so thanks!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_master_prisoner_reward_dialog_4">
    <text>Don't thank us just yet, stalker.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_master_prisoner_reward_dialog_5">
    <text>What do you mean?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_master_leader_reward_dialog_0">
    <text>I mean that you're still due for something else. Here's some body armor, plus a very rare and useful artifact.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_master_leader_reward_dialog_1">
    <text>Boys, have you lost your minds?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_master_leader_reward_dialog_2">
    <text>No need to say anything — all of this is your rightful property! One more thing: if you end up in any trouble, let us know, and we'll take the stalkers and deal with it than you can say "bloodsucker".</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_master_leader_reward_dialog_3">
    <text>Thanks for everything, guys. Guess this gets me more credibility on the list!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_master_leader_reward_dialog_4">
    <text>Just watch yourself, buddy, 'cause falling off that list is even easier.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_master_leader_reward_dialog_5">
    <text>Then I won't take up your time. I'll go about my business.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_master_leader_reward_dialog_6">
    <text>You're always welcome around here. Safe travels!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_master_leader_reward_dialog_7">
    <text>Likewise.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_green_stalker_leader_start_dialog_0">
    <text>Hey, stalker, come help us out!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_green_stalker_leader_start_dialog_1">
    <text>How can I help?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_green_stalker_leader_start_dialog_2">
    <text>We can't get through to the Bar — the place is crawling with psy-dogs! One of us already got mauled to death...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_green_stalker_leader_start_dialog_3">
    <text>How in the world did you make it here with your third-rate equipment? All you have are old shotties and pistols!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_green_stalker_leader_start_dialog_4">
    <text>Everything went just fine along the way. We started seeing the factory take shape and thought, "Right, there should be a safe place nearby." Those thoughts were quickly interrupted...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_green_stalker_leader_start_dialog_5">
    <text>Duty should be nearby. Haven't they arrived to help?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_green_stalker_leader_start_dialog_6">
    <text>Nope! We sent an SOS, but they must be busy.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_green_stalker_leader_start_dialog_7">
    <text>Damn it, greenhorns... You just had to come to these parts!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_green_stalker_leader_start_dialog_8">
    <text>What else can we do? The old fart Sidorovich pays us next to nothing, Crutch won't give jobs to people like us, so we set off to here. I hear there's an arena here, plus other good work.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_green_stalker_leader_start_dialog_9">
    <text>Guys, forget about arenas — you can't even deal with a pack of dogs!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_green_stalker_leader_start_dialog_10">
    <text>Yeah, right... Try it yourself, then! I haven't met anyone here who can do better!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_green_stalker_leader_start_dialog_11">
    <text>Alright, sit tight. I'll deal with the dogs, since we're going the same way.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_prisoner_leader_angry_dialog_0">
    <text>Boy, oh boy! Look who it is!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_prisoner_leader_angry_dialog_1_1">
    <text>I'll be damned. You made it out!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_prisoner_leader_angry_dialog_1_2">
    <text>Do I know you?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_prisoner_leader_angry_dialog_2_1">
    <text>Of course I made it out! And thanks to you, you son of a bitch, the jarheads shot down my brother! Now you'll pay for that!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_prisoner_leader_angry_dialog_2_2">
    <text>You could say that. Before I got locked up by your pals, I saw you hop off a helicopter. You understand that good men die because of two-faced bastards like you? *I* may have made it out, but my brother got smoked... and now you're gonna pay!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_prisoner_leader_angry_dialog_3">
    <text>It's not my fault you got caught by the military.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_prisoner_leader_angry_dialog_4_1">
    <text>But we had a deal: you'd help me if I gave you the info!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_prisoner_leader_angry_dialog_4_2">
    <text>You could've saved us, you bastard!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_prisoner_leader_angry_dialog_5_1">
    <text>Your info wasn't significant enough for me to exceed my authority and save outlaws, especially ones that don't have the sense to avoid soldiers. You have no one to blame but yourselves, so don't pin it on me.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_prisoner_leader_angry_dialog_5_2">
    <text>I'm not about to exceed my authority and save outlaws, especially ones that don't have the sense to avoid soldiers. You have no one to blame but yourselves, so don't pin it on me.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_prisoner_leader_angry_dialog_6">
    <text>Shut your trap, you love child!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_prisoner_leader_angry_dialog_7">
    <text>Knock it off!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_duty_base_prison_boss_relax_dialog_0">
    <text>You awake yet?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_duty_base_prison_boss_relax_dialog_1">
    <text>What am I doing here?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_duty_base_prison_boss_relax_dialog_2">
    <text>We have word from a stalker that you're from the military and got his brother killed. He was about to thrash you on the spot, but our men intervened to save your sorry ass. Now, listen up, soldier boy: all stalkers in the Bar have turned against you. If you disobey our orders, there might even be mob justice in store for you. Your kind is normally shot on sight, so consider yourself lucky. In any event, you'll be dealt with appropriately in the morning.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_duty_base_prison_boss_relax_dialog_3">
    <text>I had no part in anyone's death. They themselves crossed paths with the army — they knew what they were in for when they entered the Zone!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_duty_base_prison_boss_relax_dialog_4">
    <text>I don't give two shits what you did. You're a soldier who's encroached on Duty territory — the military aren't exactly our friends, in case you forgot, so you can forget about any special treatment after your little infiltration. Now, sit down and keep your mouth shut. Try anything and you'll just get yourself shot.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_duty_base_prison_boss_relax_dialog_5">
    <text>I understand.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_koval_prison_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello there!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_koval_prison_dialog_1">
    <text>What are *you* doing here?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_koval_prison_dialog_2">
    <text>I came to get you out. What, aren't you glad to see me?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_koval_prison_dialog_3">
    <text>Not really.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_koval_prison_dialog_4">
    <text>Well, you should be! I just came from the bar. Those people want your head on a pike, and that's what they'll get if you stay here any longer. Duty won't be able to stop them... and to tell you the truth, they probably wouldn't even try. Here's your gear, now let's get the hell out... qui-et-ly!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_koval_prison_dialog_5">
    <text>Let's go.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_fireball_start_dialog_0">
    <text>Ey!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_fireball_start_dialog_1">
    <text>Hey there. Want something?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_fireball_start_dialog_2">
    <text>Well, I thought you could help me. From what I can tell, you seem alright.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_fireball_start_dialog_3">
    <text>That depends on what you mean by "help."</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_fireball_start_dialog_4">
    <text>Okay, so, some of my boys were feeling extra stupid one day and decided to see what happens when you throw a Fireball into a campfire.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_fireball_start_dialog_5">
    <text>Hahaha! And?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_fireball_start_dialog_6">
    <text>Hey, don't laugh, you idiot! I lost three of my friends! In the blink of an eye! You understand me?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_fireball_start_dialog_7">
    <text>Sorry, man, I didn't realize. But it does sound really entertaining... What happened in the end?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_fireball_start_dialog_8">
    <text>No, you forgive me; I'm a bit on edge right now. Anyway, they threw the artie into the fire, and then this incredible heat swept them — they turned into ash in a split second. It's like they were hit by a flamethrower burst at point-blank. You wouldn't wish that on your worst enemy, let alone on your friends...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_fireball_start_dialog_9">
    <text>My condolences, uh... Gena, right? I'm sorry, Gen. So what was it that got them? Was it just the artifact reacting to high temperatures, or did they happen to throw some incendiary ammo into the mix?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_fireball_start_dialog_10">
    <text>Neither. It was a poltergeist. And not an ordinary one, but a freaking fire poltergeist! Can you believe it? Now, as soon as this flamey piece of donkey dung burns my friends to a crisp, it rushes at me, so I took off to the Bar. This happened by the road to the Army Warehouses. Please, get rid of that thing for me.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_fireball_start_dialog_11">
    <text>If I find myself there, I'll do what I can.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_fireball_start_dialog_12">
    <text>Just one more thing: according to a Duty recon squad, that poltergeist is no ordinary fire poltergeist. It must have something to do with the artifact it somehow managed to come out of, but that thing can multiply, so at that place where it was last seen, there might not just be one but at least two of them. You watch yourself — I don't want another innocent soul to die because of that bastard.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_fireball_start_dialog_13">
    <text>I'll try my luck.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_fireball_wait_dialog_0">
    <text>So, you put those freaks down?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_fireball_wait_dialog_1_1">
    <text>Put them out, more like. With fire. Fire poltergeists. Good morning, laws of physics.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_fireball_wait_dialog_1_2">
    <text>Not yet.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_fireball_wait_dialog_2">
    <text>That's a good one, brother! Thank you; now I'll be able to sleep soundly. Well, not really, but at least I feel a bit better... Here, for your efforts. Just don't throw it into a fire, god damn it!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_fireball_wait_dialog_3">
    <text>Don't worry, I won't. And keep your head up — at least you found a new friend.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_fireball_idle_dialog_0">
    <text>What's up?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_fireball_idle_dialog_1">
    <text>Eh, nothing, really.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_drunk_idle_dialog_0_1">
    <text>My head... I need something for my hangover...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_drunk_idle_dialog_0_2">
    <text>Shit, I'm woozy... Wanna share a hair of the dog?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_drunk_idle_dialog_0_3">
    <text>Let's drink together... buddy...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_drunk_start_dialog_0">
    <text>Hey, buddy, you alright? You're looking pale.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_drunk_start_dialog_1">
    <text>Nah, man, I'm not alright... I spent all my cash on vodka, but it ain't enough... Listen, would you buy a bottle for a fellow stalker? Like a brother... and I'll tell you a really inter... intrist... intir... I mean, uh, I'll tell you a really cool story...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_drunk_task_dialog_0">
    <text>Here's your bottle. Tell me your little story.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_drunk_task_dialog_1">
    <text>Okay, I'll just drink up and tell you everything. What do they call you?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_drunk_task_dialog_2">
    <text>Axe.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_drunk_task_dialog_3">
    <text>I'm Sanya... but here, they call me Bottleman. Now that we know each other, let's drink to it!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_drunk_task_dialog_4">
    <text>Pour up!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_drunk_task_dialog_5">
    <text>Ah, yeah, the story. So, you heard the story about Boozy?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_drunk_task_dialog_6">
    <text>Never heard it.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_drunk_task_dialog_7">
    <text>Yeah? Then let's have another shot, alright?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_drunk_task_dialog_8">
    <text>Let's.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_drunk_task_dialog_9">
    <text>Basically, Boozy was this guy who loved vodka his whole life and really wanted to get to the Wish Giver... Wish Banker... uh, Wish Granter, to wish for the taste of vodka in his mouth. He had a friend who was god awful at shooting and wanted to wish for accuracy. Then, when he got there, he wished for the taste of vodka in his mouth, and the Wish Granter made him wasted for the rest of his life. Then his friend came and wished for "the best possible accuracy" and... well, how do you think it ended up?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_drunk_task_dialog_10">
    <text>He started shooting good?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_drunk_task_dialog_11">
    <text>Hah, yeah, right. He didn't clarify who he wanted to get that accuracy, so the Granter made Boozy more accurate. When he got back, that's when they started calling him Boozy. He fired like a champ, went to the center of the Zone and there's your happy ending. Let's have one more!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_drunk_task_dialog_12">
    <text>Woah. You know any other cool stories?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_drunk_task_dialog_13">
    <text>Well, they say that somewhere nearby, near the Rostok factory, Boozy keeps his stash hidden somewhere. They say it's got, uh... tons of vodka and artifacts of some kind... I guess.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_drunk_task_dialog_14">
    <text>You know where it might be?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_drunk_task_dialog_15">
    <text>I think it's somewhere near the passage to the Army Warehouses, but no way am I going there. That place is creepy!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_drunk_task_dialog_16">
    <text>I see. I'll be right back...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_drunk_final_dialog_0">
    <text>Brother, help me...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_drunk_final_dialog_1">
    <text>Who are you calling "brother"? What the hell was that?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_drunk_final_dialog_2">
    <text>I'll tell you everything. Just promise me you'll help out.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_drunk_final_dialog_3">
    <text>I can't promise you anything. You don't have a choice anyway.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_drunk_final_dialog_4">
    <text>Fine then. My friend and I, Sickle, make our living tricking people. I share different stories with them and tell them about a secret stash. The stalkers get interested, they go to the place to check the loot, and then Sickle comes and shakes them down on the spot.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_drunk_final_dialog_5">
    <text>So you've been shaking down people in the Bar and no one's caught you yet?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_drunk_final_dialog_6">
    <text>It's our first time in the Bar. Before that, we did the same thing in the Dark Valley, at the Garbage, at Agroprom...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_drunk_final_dialog_7">
    <text>Why's your friend dead?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_drunk_final_dialog_8">
    <text>We had a little fight. He wounded me, wanted to take everything we stole from you and leave me here, but I took a shot at him... and he fell to the ground.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_drunk_final_dialog_9">
    <text>You got lucky there.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_drunk_final_dialog_10">
    <text>Yeah, but it hurts like shit! Listen, gimme a medkit, please... and I'll tell you where I hid a Jellyfish artifact.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_drunk_final_dialog_11">
    <text>I'll think about it.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_drunk_medkit_dialog_0">
    <text>Medkit... Please...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_drunk_medkit_dialog_1_1">
    <text>Here. Keep on tricking stalkers and you'll end up in a hole with a bullet in your head.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_drunk_medkit_dialog_1_2">
    <text>I haven't decided what to do with you yet.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_drunk_medkit_dialog_2">
    <text>Thanks, stalker! I've marked where I hid the Jellyfish — I'm never going back to that place! I'll just rest up a bit first.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_drunk_medkit_dialog_3">
    <text>Get out of here already.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_start_dialog_0">
    <text>Yeah?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_start_dialog_1">
    <text>What happened to you, stalker?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_start_dialog_2">
    <text>Happened? What makes you think something happened? I'm doing great, except I've run out of snacks for my drink. You get me some, we can share a few glasses.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_start_dialog_3">
    <text>You must've had a reason for that "rest in peace." What's up?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_start_dialog_4">
    <text>Ah, that's what you meant. Hm...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_start_dialog_5">
    <text>Exactly. Today is the only day people in the bar are so generous! At least you have one caring conversation partner. So, tell me.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_start_dialog_6">
    <text>Okay, we had this one fella. We called him Goose 'cause of the length of his neck, which reminded us of... well, you know. The guy needed money — seems like he had some trouble making ends meet on the outside. He told us one of his folks ended up in the hospital.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_start_dialog_7">
    <text>Go on.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_start_dialog_8">
    <text>He started asking people to loan him a sum. But nobody believed him; you know, with lots of tricksters around as of late and all. Even if someone were to believe him, how would they know he won't be a goner before he pays his debt back?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_start_dialog_9">
    <text>That makes sense.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_start_dialog_10">
    <text>It also makes sense not to interrupt people, you get me? I wasn't done yet. Anyway, this one time, Goose was contacted by a certain Cobra, who offered to help him find his way around anomalies in an artifact hunt. After that, he promised to take Goose's cut to the scientists at Yantar, 'cause Goose would never make it that far on his own. So, they went on a hunt, got some nice arties; Goose got them out of the anomaly himself, meaning he gained some experience and he's not a complete dimwit, and he could've made a good stalker.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_start_dialog_11">
    <text>And then that Cobra left Goose hanging?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_start_dialog_12">
    <text>Bingo. It soon turned out that the guy from the outside who Goose was collecting money for died.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_start_dialog_13">
    <text>Sad tale.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_start_dialog_14">
    <text>You said it. Had the money been collected on time, Goose's relative would've made it... though, honestly, I wouldn't be so sure about that. Knowing our medicine and considering there's some new virus on the outside, I don't think he would've had much of a chance.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_start_dialog_15">
    <text>That's true. Virus is mutating quickly, and there's no vaccine yet. You can't keep the population in their homes for long to keep it from spreading, because then the whole world comes to a stop. And that means worldwide problems with the entire economy, industry, production...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_start_dialog_16">
    <text>Okay, well, you know more about that. Anyway, Goose was in deep shit: he was damn close to depression and was left dry without money. He's in terrible shape now: can't get any money on his own, because he's barely keeping himself from ending it as it is. He has no more stashes, because he put his earnings into equipment for that hunt. He's broke now.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_start_dialog_17">
    <text>And you call yourself fellow stalkers? Nobody's giving him a helping hand?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_start_dialog_18">
    <text>This isn't a charity. This is the Zone. Here, people's trust go out only to their closest friends, and sometimes only to themselves.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_start_dialog_19">
    <text>I see how it is with you. Who is this Cobra guy? Maybe I could talk him into giving Goose his share back.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_start_dialog_20">
    <text>Hah, no. Don't even think about it. Cobra's a cold, dangerous stalker who doesn't think twice about dealing with anyone who gets in his way. With his qualities, he got together a circle of similar scumbags who literally dance around him just to stay on his good side. You won't come to terms with him.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_start_dialog_21">
    <text>Aren't you afraid of speaking that way about that stalker? If that's true, he could, uh...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_start_dialog_22">
    <text>End me? I don't think so. I'm not as simple as you might think. Plus, I never said anything bad. What kind of leader is he if he gets insulted by a loner like me?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_start_dialog_23">
    <text>And Duty just lets everything slide like that? They don't care about Cobra's circle of gangbangers and that he stiffs stalkers? They gotta know about this stuff.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_start_dialog_24">
    <text>You'll just have to let it slide too. You see, Cobra's as dangerous as he is useful. Artifact hunts are his hobby to relax and unwind. Besides that, he takes impossible contract on people Duty has their sights on, and he gets them done alone — smooth and seamless. That's why they call him Cobra. Removing him means removing a valuable asset who does the dirty work for Duty. It'd never be that easy, 'cause Cobra is worth ten of their specops troops. That's why many Dutyers turn a blind eye to unpleasant things involving Cobra. As long as he's beneficial to them, nothing can touch him.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_start_dialog_25">
    <text>Why, then, did he decide to talk to Goose? He doesn't have an ounce of experience, judging by what you're saying. It'd be easier to just take someone battle-tested.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_start_dialog_26">
    <text>Purely for his own entertainment. Had Goose simply died in an anomaly, Cobra would've left it at that. Cobra's got experienced artifact hunters who would've done all the work. As for Goose... He asked literally everyone in the Bar to lend him money, hence Cobra decided to keep watch on him through one of his thugs. He found out about Goose's problem even before Goose turned to him. They say he even checked his sources to see what exactly it was. So when Goose came to him, Cobra started pressuring him by saying he had little time and needed much money, and that only Cobra can help him.\n \nGoose was very worried, started doubting himself, because Cobra is the last person Goose would go to for help — the rumors surrounding him would put you off from cooperating. But, apparently, something really serious happened to him. In the end, Goose agreed, and... you know the rest. I hear that when Cobra told him they were pretty much even, Goose started protesting, and then they swarmed him, beat him up and threw him onto the street. He got picked up and taken to the local doctor. I guess he'll live.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_start_dialog_27">
    <text>That son of a bitch...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_start_dialog_28">
    <text>And *you* should be careful with what you say. I doubt there's anyone influential looking after you. No one will miss you if you suddenly appear.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_start_dialog_29">
    <text>So where's Goose now?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_start_dialog_30">
    <text>Well, I don't know where you could find him, but I do know he decided to step onto the arena. He decided it was the only quick way of earning at least something... but personally, I think it'll be a one-way ticket for Goose. Tonight, he's having his first fight against Koschei. A dangerous opponent, resilient and uncompromising. They say he went on a long raid with his buddies where everybody died except him, and he alone, without any supplies, made it on his own to the Duty outpost. When they saw him, they couldn't believe it: it was like a living skeleton was standing before them — that's how much weight he had lost. And nobody knows how. One take is that it's stress. Sounds like the truth, but I don't think that's all to it. Say, some artifacts feed on their owner's body in exchange for their properties... Anyway, I already bet that Goose will lose. There's pretty much no payout in it at all, but it'll be enough for a beer and a small dinner.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_start_dialog_31">
    <text>So Goose is still alive, but you're already drinking to his dead soul? Why'd you decide to bet against him?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_start_dialog_32">
    <text>Why are you surprised? He's a useless fighter — shoots so-so. The fact that he made a decent earning on his artifact hunt doesn't make him a terminator. Today is obviously the last day of his life, and I'm drinking because I feel sorry for him. I just feel sorry.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_start_dialog_33">
    <text>Then why don't you help him if you're feeling sorry? You're no greenie if not even Cobra can touch you.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_start_dialog_34">
    <text>Is that a dare? You're lucky I'm not in shape right now, or I'd bop you one for running your mouth like that. Say, hero, why don't you try saving his ass yourself? I mean, what do you suggest I do, give him all my savings just because he's so miserable? Or maybe step onto the arena in his place? Buddy, even though I feel sorry for him, he's no one to me. I'm not about to stick my neck out for him.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_start_dialog_35">
    <text>Yeah, thanks for nothing.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_staff_barman_stalker_goose_dialog_0">
    <text>Barkeep, do you know a stalker named Goose?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_staff_barman_stalker_goose_dialog_1">
    <text>Yeah. He's got a name around here, though he would've been better off without it. Why do you need him?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_staff_barman_stalker_goose_dialog_2">
    <text>A personal matter.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_staff_barman_stalker_goose_dialog_3">
    <text>I don't believe it. First, nobody even notices the guy — as if he never even existed — and now everybody and their dog wants him!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_staff_barman_stalker_goose_dialog_4">
    <text>So, what do you say?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_staff_barman_stalker_goose_dialog_5">
    <text>I haven't seen him here in about two days.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_staff_barman_stalker_goose_dialog_6">
    <text>You know where he might be? Or maybe you know where he last went?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_staff_barman_stalker_goose_dialog_7">
    <text>I don't know any of that. I manage this stand all day, and I have no time to keep track of all the tramps coming in here. Though... I do know where he is right now.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_staff_barman_stalker_goose_dialog_8">
    <text>Where? Spill the beans.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_staff_barman_stalker_goose_dialog_9">
    <text>He's standing behind you, stalker.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_staff_barman_stalker_goose_dialog_10">
    <text>You sly dog...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_goose_start_dialog_0">
    <text>You looking for me or something?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_goose_start_dialog_1">
    <text>Well, hello, Goose.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_goose_start_dialog_2">
    <text>Hi to you to. How do you know me?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_goose_start_dialog_3">
    <text>You're quite notorious in 100 Rads.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_goose_start_dialog_4">
    <text>Unfortunately. If you came to mock me, here's your chance.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_goose_start_dialog_5">
    <text>I'm actually taking the chance to help you.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_goose_start_dialog_6">
    <text>I'm afraid you can't. Nobody can. My mom suddenly got sick with some virus and died. The doctors couldn't do anything. I don't know if she would've had a chance had I been there... I shouldn't have gone into the Zone, damn it! Maybe if I'd have been there, I could've done something. I remember my last meeting with her; we had a big fight... I said I don't want to see her again.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_goose_start_dialog_7">
    <text>Sorry to hear.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_goose_start_dialog_8">
    <text>Now I don't even have money for food. None of the stalkers want to help me, but I get them: who wants to deal with a loser like me, right? As for that Cobra guy... he doesn't even want to talk to me. He says he already helped me a lot. Now my only option is to fight in the arena. Maybe I'll get lucky. Though, I've never even really held a gun in my hands, let alone taken someone's life.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_goose_start_dialog_9">
    <text>That's crazy. You're no veteran!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_goose_start_dialog_10">
    <text>I know. And you know what? It doesn't matter anymore. I don't care if I die today or not. I've lost everything. Now, please leave me.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_goose_start_dialog_11">
    <text>I understand.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_second_dialog_0">
    <text>It's me again.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_second_dialog_1">
    <text>Oh, there you are. What is it, stalker?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_second_dialog_2">
    <text>How do I find Cobra?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_second_dialog_3">
    <text>You serious? You got a death wish?!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_second_dialog_4">
    <text>No. I got a life wish, and that is meeting this Cobra fellow.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_second_dialog_5">
    <text>Funny. Well, I warned you. I won't cry for you, just so you know, okay?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_second_dialog_6">
    <text>I'll live with that.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_second_dialog_7">
    <text>He's housed in the space next to the arena. You go see him while I drink to the peace of a second soul today, you madman.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_second_dialog_8">
    <text>Just don't overdo it. Don't want the bottleache.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_pribluda_start_dialog_0">
    <text>Where are you headed?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_pribluda_start_dialog_1">
    <text>I've got a word to share with Cobra. It's about Goose.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_pribluda_start_dialog_2">
    <text>Oh, that's rich! Not even a hello. Where'd you come from, sucker?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_pribluda_start_dialog_3">
    <text>I'm looking for Cobra. You're not Cobra, are you? Then please, let me through.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_pribluda_start_dialog_4">
    <text>And what if I don't let you through? Am I supposed to let through every clown just because they ask nicely? That's how how things work around here.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_pribluda_start_dialog_5">
    <text>How do they work? Am I supposed to be the big brute guy, like you are? Well, I'm not here to pick a fight. All I want is to see Cobra.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_pribluda_start_dialog_6">
    <text>Who are you calling a brute? Think you can walk through any doors just like that? I'll let you through since it's about Goose. You try anything and you'll end up like swiss cheese. Oh, and... I'll remember you, bozo. Keep your eyes sharp, 'cos I might show up at any moment.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_pribluda_start_dialog_7">
    <text>Finally.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_snake_start_dialog_0">
    <text>I'm all ears.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_snake_start_dialog_1">
    <text>I've got business with you.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_snake_start_dialog_2">
    <text>Ever heard of manners? Though, what can you expect from a stalker... What's it about?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_snake_start_dialog_3">
    <text>I'm here about Goose.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_snake_start_dialog_4">
    <text>He sent you?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_snake_start_dialog_5">
    <text>No. I heard about him from a stalker in the bar.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_snake_start_dialog_6">
    <text>Who, if I might ask?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_snake_start_dialog_7">
    <text>That's not important.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_snake_start_dialog_8">
    <text>I suppose it isn't. Then I'll add to what you already know. So, his mother was taken into an ordinary hospital, where nobody really helped her. I pulled a few strings and found a private clinic with more experienced doctors and modern equipment. This was big money: every day of treatment there costs three grand. I hired Goose to do the checking for me when we were hunting for artifacts. He would've gotten his own cut had everything gone well; it would've been enough for him for the short haul.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_snake_start_dialog_9">
    <text>What made you go the extra mile for him?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_snake_start_dialog_10">
    <text>When I was at rock bottom in a similar situation, I was selflessly given help. I'm no philanthropist, far from it, but it made me decide to help the guy and give him a chance.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_snake_start_dialog_11">
    <text>So why'd you rip him off?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_snake_start_dialog_12">
    <text>In what way?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_snake_start_dialog_13">
    <text>You owe him money for his participation in the hunt.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_snake_start_dialog_14">
    <text>You don't see the picture, stalker. Goose is the one who owes me. His share in the hunt wasn't big enough to cover his debt to me. I put a lot of money into his mother's treatment. I wasn't even sure — and I'm still not sure — whether he'll return every last coin to me.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_snake_start_dialog_15">
    <text>So when stalkers from the bar won't even offer him a loaf of bread, you show up, solve the big money problem of someone you don't even know and expect him to pay it back just like that? I mean, everyone else is indifferent to the fact that he can barely even feed himself, but only you, a heartless headhunter, decide to support him. What else are you gonna tell me? That you and your boys didn't beat him to a pulp when he came for his cut? Not only did you rip him off, you're also lying to my face.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_snake_start_dialog_16">
    <text>You dare step into my home and accuse me of lies and betrayal? I tire of our conversation. You should get some sleep.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_snake_start_dialog_17">
    <text>Huh?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_pribluda_kill_dialog_0">
    <text>I told you, punk, keep your eyes open. You shouldn't have called me a brute. And you should've watched yourself around Cobra, too.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_pribluda_kill_dialog_1">
    <text>Oh, come on! Where do you people come from?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_pribluda_kill_dialog_2">
    <text>What was that? Staring down a barrel and you're still talking like that? Maybe you'll sing a different tone with a bullet in your kneecap.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_pribluda_kill_dialog_3">
    <text>Tell me, airhead, how's it feel with a barrel pointing at the back of your head? You feel that itch?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_salvation_dialog_0">
    <text>You okay?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_salvation_dialog_1">
    <text>Oh, it's you. Thanks, just in time.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_salvation_dialog_2">
    <text>We'll settle up later. Now we need to deal with Cobra.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_salvation_dialog_3">
    <text>About him... Why wasn't he as you described? And why did he start denying that he ripped off Goose? On the contrary, he seemed to help him a lot.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_salvation_dialog_4">
    <text>Oh, I didn't tell you he's an experienced manipulator? Otherwise Duty wouldn't treat him as an equal and he wouldn't be able to lay down his own terms if something didn't fit him about a contract.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_salvation_dialog_5">
    <text>I see.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_arena_manager_goose_dialog_0">
    <text>Hi. I want to know about a stalker, his name's Goose.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_arena_manager_goose_dialog_1">
    <text>Ah, the neck guy? Well, he died in the first round. He was given a fight against Koschei. By the way, the latter's soon fighting in the finale for the main prize... I'm sorry, but your guy had no chance to begin with.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_arena_manager_goose_dialog_2">
    <text>We only talked once, though I feel sorry for the guy. He had a hard time as of late.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_arena_manager_goose_dialog_3">
    <text>I'm sorry, but he knew what he was getting himself into. By the way, he left a note for you. Told me to hand it to you personally.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_arena_manager_goose_dialog_4">
    <text>Give it here.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_goose_death_dialog_0">
    <text>Goose is dead.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_goose_death_dialog_1">
    <text>I couldn't help both of you even if I wanted to. I had to choose.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_goose_death_dialog_2">
    <text>Goose left me a note where he explained everything... Why'd you have to lie about Cobra? He didn't do anything like how you described him in the Bar.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_goose_death_dialog_3">
    <text>Okay, I'll explain, and I hope you'll understand. Because you're a new face here, getting to Cobra was easier for you. He never lets anyone he doesn't know near him just like that. And this was a golden opportunity: a stalker comes to guarantee for a green kid who owes Cobra a ton of money. I lied to you to ensure you'd go to him. You asked who I was drinking to, and that meant you had to be a decent guy who doesn't just leave people. I was right! And that's why I kept motivating you to get justice.\n \nTell me, would you have gone to Cobra if you'd have known that he helped Goose, and Goose was forced to fight on the arena because he wasn't able to pay up? It's commendable to take on another man's problems, but having that favor returned is a different story.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_goose_death_dialog_4">
    <text>I guess you're right. Goose himself agreed to such conditions, even though he had no choice.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_goose_death_dialog_5">
    <text>Indeed. Anyway, everything turned out as I anticipated: things got rough, he knocked you out and then he intended to kill you for insulting his name. But he wouldn't do that in the Bar, which is why he instructed his boys to deal with you somewhere quiet.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_goose_death_dialog_6">
    <text>After this, I bet you're gonna tell me I owe you for saving me? I was bait for you!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_goose_death_dialog_7">
    <text>You were. And now you're my partner. Don't worry, I won't leave you without a reward — considering the slight risk of that whole ordeal. It'll also serve you as as a lesson not to trust strangers so much.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_goose_death_dialog_8">
    <text>Slight risk? I almost got shot at point-blank!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_goose_death_dialog_9">
    <text>Don't get hysterical. You're safe and almost sound.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_goose_death_dialog_10">
    <text>You bastard. So why'd we go to such lengths?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_goose_death_dialog_11">
    <text>I'll pretend I didn't hear that. The thing is that Cobra left his little premise in the Bar earlier than he planned to. He doesn't want to draw suspicion to the fact that he was involved in your disappearance. Duty keeps an eagle eye on law and order on their territory and doesn't allow mob rule. Cobra might be a top-tier stalker, but even he's a disposable asset to Duty if it means them keeping their reputation of having the only punitive system in this place. Cobra's got some important meeting right now, so he had to make things quick with you so he wouldn't be late.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_goose_death_dialog_12">
    <text>You son of a gun. You told me Duty turns a blind eye to Cobra and his actions...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_goose_death_dialog_13">
    <text>I ought to take that as a compliment, since you believed me. Cobra already lost one of his henchmen thanks to me, meaning he's that much weaker. Right now, he's heading with his gang to the Dark Valley, where he has his meeting. We can catch him on the way.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_goose_death_dialog_14">
    <text>Couldn't you have done it yourself before?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_goose_death_dialog_15">
    <text>There's two of us now, meaning our chances are twice as big. In addition, he's hard to catch when he's on his own, but when he's with his gang, they're only as fast as their slowest member.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_goose_death_dialog_16">
    <text>What beef do you have with Cobra? What did he ever do to you?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_goose_death_dialog_17">
    <text>He killed a friend of mine. Let's go get your stuff; it's most likely at Cobra's place in the Bar. Then we follow him. You're coming with me, right?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_goose_death_dialog_18">
    <text>Yeah. Lead the way.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_goose_death_dialog_19">
    <text>Actually, no. You go grab it yourself while I wait by the southern checkpoint. I also need to prepare.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_goose_death_dialog_20">
    <text>Deal.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_to_garbage_dialog_0_1">
    <text>So, you ready? I've already tracked them down. Fresh trails — they can't be far. No time to lose.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_to_garbage_dialog_0_2">
    <text>Listen, those bastards are out of sight for now. Come by later and do your own thing in the meantime.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_to_garbage_dialog_1_1">
    <text>Lead the way.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_to_garbage_dialog_1_2_1">
    <text>I'm not ready.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_to_garbage_dialog_1_2_2">
    <text>Got it.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_to_garbage_dialog_1_3">
    <text>Understood.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_prepare_attack_dialog_0">
    <text>We're here. They're nearby, in the lowlands. They stopped to rest before going into the Valley.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_prepare_attack_dialog_1">
    <text>How many are there?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_prepare_attack_dialog_2">
    <text>There were only six of them if you include the guy at the checkpoint. That means there are five of them now... but since it's Cobra we're talking about, consider them as fifteen.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_prepare_attack_dialog_3">
    <text>What's our plan?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_prepare_attack_dialog_4">
    <text>You take up a position behind the tree and flank them. I'll blast them with a 'nade and we finish off the survivors.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_prepare_attack_dialog_5">
    <text>I'll first talk to Cobra, then we'll finish them off.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_prepare_attack_dialog_6">
    <text>If he survives.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_prepare_attack_dialog_7">
    <text>Let's move.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_snake_wounded_dialog_0">
    <text>I guess this is it...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_snake_wounded_dialog_1">
    <text>You turned out less of a scumbag than I thought, but knocking me out and carrying me off to get shot was uncalled for.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_snake_wounded_dialog_2">
    <text>Agreed. I should've dealt with you on the spot. Would've saved me the trouble.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_snake_wounded_dialog_3">
    <text>You know Chrome?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_snake_wounded_dialog_4">
    <text>That I do. You work for him?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_snake_wounded_dialog_5">
    <text>I work for myself. I first came to you on Goose's behalf, who's dead by now. Chrome told me you ripped him off and beat him.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_snake_wounded_dialog_6">
    <text>I shouldn't be surprised it was his doing.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_snake_wounded_dialog_7">
    <text>Your man took me away behind the checkpoint and was about to shoot me, but Chrome came just in time to help. He told me you killed his friend. So even though you helped Goose, you threatened my life and killed Chrome's friend. That's why you're lying on the ground now, bleeding like a pig, and soon you'll die altogether.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_snake_wounded_dialog_8">
    <text>Do you know why I killed his friend? No? Then listen. And listen carefully, 'cause I'm not about to shout. His friend's name was Whip — a rotten stalker. He once ambushed and shot down an entire group of stalkers because of a valuable artifact. But a dying stalker from that group managed to send a message to the network saying what artifact they gave their lives for... and surprisingly, a few days later, Whip sells Sakharov that very same artifact. Fortunately, Duty was guarding the bunker there and messaged Petrenko about it, who he gave me a contract on him. I don't take lives without reason.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_snake_wounded_dialog_9">
    <text>Farewell, Cobra.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_final_dialog_0">
    <text>You alive?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_final_dialog_1">
    <text>Are you satisfied?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_final_dialog_2">
    <text>Quite. My friend is avenged.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_final_dialog_3_1">
    <text>Are you aware your friend shot down a stalker group because of an artifact? A real shit thing to do.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_final_dialog_3_2">
    <text>A shame I couldn't speak to Cobra.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_final_dialog_4_1">
    <text>Don't you talk about him like that. He did the wrong thing, but he was still my friend. He saved my life many times; he was willing to sacrifice everything for me if need be. Still, thanks for helping me. I'll send info on my personal stash to your PDA — take it. As for me, I guess I'll go.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_final_dialog_4_2">
    <text>It doesn't matter that much anymore. Thanks for helping me. I'll send info on my personal stash to your PDA — take it. As for me, I guess I'll go.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_final_dialog_5">
    <text>Bye, stalker.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_idle_dialog_0_1">
    <text>Yeah, what is it?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_idle_dialog_0_2">
    <text>What do you want?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_idle_dialog_0_3">
    <text>I'm listening.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_idle_dialog_0_1_friend">
    <text>Hi, stalker.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_idle_dialog_0_2_friend">
    <text>Hey, man.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_google_chrome_idle_dialog_0_3_friend">
    <text>What's up?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_goose_idle_dialog_0_1">
    <text>Hell...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_goose_idle_dialog_0_2">
    <text>What do I do?...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_goose_idle_dialog_0_3">
    <text>Guess that's life...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_goose_idle_dialog_1_1">
    <text>We'll think of something.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_goose_idle_dialog_1_2">
    <text>Keep it together. It'll be alright.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_stalker_goose_idle_dialog_1_3">
    <text>Don't get sour on me. Have a drink.</text>
  </string>
</string_table>
