п»ї<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<string_table>

	<string id="agr_diggers_start_dialog_0">
		<text>Yeah? What are you doing here?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_diggers_start_dialog_1">
		<text>I'm here for your leader. I've got important information for him.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_diggers_start_dialog_2">
		<text>Alright. Leave your weapons and head on in. You'll get them back once you leave.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_diggers_start_dialog_3">
		<text>Suits me.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_diggers_leader_dialog_0">
		<text>Hello. Speak your mind.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_diggers_leader_dialog_1">
		<text>I have some bad news. You guys are in some deep shit. A group of mercenaries are on their way to get you. They're going to tear this whole place apart.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_diggers_leader_dialog_2">
		<text>The hell are you on about? What mercenaries, and what do they want? Who are you anyway?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_diggers_leader_dialog_3">
		<text>I'm just an ordinary stalker. I came to check out the scientific complex around these parts to snoop around for loot. I overheard some negotiations along the way, likely mercenaries. Their objective seems to be the case you discovered.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_diggers_leader_dialog_4">
		<text>Well, would you look at that... How many of them are there? What else do you know? And how'd you manage to pick up those negotiations if the mercenaries are pros in their field, who almost never leave any traces? And they went on an unencrypted frequency just like that? To me, stalker, all of this sounds a bit too good to be true.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_diggers_leader_dialog_5">
		<text>I have no reason to lie to you. I don't know why they operated on that frequency; they were probably in a hurry. It was just two groups, likely three to four men each. They'll be here in an hour or less.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_diggers_leader_dialog_6">
		<text>Damn it. Never been this knee-deep in shit before... You don't know who's contracting them?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_diggers_leader_dialog_7">
		<text>No. They only discussed their objective. Your men didn't share the info with anyone, did they?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_diggers_leader_dialog_8">
		<text>Nah. My men wouldn't go yapping about it left and right. Seems to me it's those bastards that separated from us - we had some real disagreements back in the day. What interests me is the identity of the contractor... Perhaps our former "friends" were the ones who put the hit on us and they might've been the ones sharing the info, hence the mercenaries appearing out of nowhere with their yet-unknown contractor.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_diggers_leader_dialog_9">
		<text>I have no interest in the contractor. I only came here to warn you, and I deserve some sort of reward for that. I'll be heading far away from here, since I'm not looking for trouble with the mercs.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_diggers_leader_dialog_10">
		<text>Yeah, here you go. Now step out. I need to discuss some details with my comrade.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_diggers_leader_dialog_11">
		<text>Bye.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_diggers_volodya_dialog_0">
		<text>Oh, you again. What do you need?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_diggers_volodya_dialog_1">
		<text>Hey, what are you doing here? Your men are out there getting torn to pieces!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_diggers_volodya_dialog_2">
		<text>My boys will handle it just fine. They're experienced!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_diggers_volodya_dialog_3">
		<text>Ten "experienced" men standing up to a merc platoon? Yeah, right.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_diggers_volodya_dialog_4">
		<text>Got anything better? We can't leave the camp either - they'll shoot us in the back and call it a day.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_diggers_volodya_dialog_5">
		<text>Come with me. We'll flank 'em and help your boys gain the upper hand.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_diggers_volodya_dialog_6">
		<text>I can't. My task is to remain here!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_diggers_volodya_dialog_7">
		<text>Then sit here, you sleazy rat. I'll go help your men. Can't stand your kind...</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_diggers_volodya_dialog_8">
		<text>Fine, damn it! Let's go... Can't even imagine what they're going through.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_diggers_volodya_dialog_9">
		<text>Here's the plan: you go down while I head onto the rooftop. I'll cover you from above, okay?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_diggers_volodya_dialog_10">
		<text>Good idea. I'm off!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_diggers_volodya_dialog_11">
		<text>Let's go!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_diggers_dialog_final_leader_0">
		<text>Stalker, there aren't many of us left after the collapse. Will you help? Your reward will be handsome!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_diggers_dialog_final_leader_1_1">
		<text>No, thanks. I'm going my own way. I'd like to steer clear of problems and maintain relations with both sides.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_diggers_dialog_final_leader_1_2">
		<text>Oh, what the hell. I'll help! [...]</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_diggers_dialog_final_leader_2">
		<text>Alright, man, do your thing. It was kind of you to warn us. Good luck to you.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_diggers_dialog_final_leader_3">
		<text>I wish you the best.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_diggers_dialog_final_volodya_0">
		<text>Thanks for warning us, stalker. It would've been great if you'd helped with the mercs too!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_diggers_dialog_final_volodya_1_1">
		<text>No, thanks. I'm going my own way. I'd like to avoid problems and maintain relations with both sides.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_diggers_dialog_final_volodya_1_2">
		<text>Alright, I'll help you. [...]</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_diggers_dialog_final_volodya_2">
		<text>Alright, man, do your thing. It was kind of you to warn us. Good luck to you.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_diggers_dialog_final_volodya_3">
		<text>You too.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_diggers_weapons_dialog_0">
		<text>Hey, don't forget your weapons.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_diggers_weapons_dialog_1">
		<text>Thanks.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_diggers_start_robbery_dialog_0">
		<text>Here's the deal: we saw a body lying in a Fruit Punch down below. Can barely even call it a body; all that's left are bones. There's a gun next to it, still in mint condition. Get it for us and then go your own way. Try screwing us over or coming back without it and that'll be your last breath. We wouldn't mind if you kick the bucket down there either. Everything clear?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_diggers_start_robbery_dialog_1">
		<text>Can I just take my gun back?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_diggers_start_robbery_dialog_2">
		<text>How about taking a hike? We'll drop you a rifle and some ammo once you descend. Quit sweating it out - it's clear down there.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_diggers_start_robbery_dialog_3">
		<text>Screw you.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_stalker_help_sos_dialog_0">
		<text>Over here!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_stalker_help_sos_dialog_1">
		<text>What happened? I heard a distress signal.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_stalker_help_sos_dialog_2">
		<text>Hey, stalker. Name's Red. My friend, if I can call him that, needs help. He burned his legs in a Fruit Punch in the tunnels, and he needs help getting out. Could you help? I'll make it worth your while... Everyone knows me in the Bar.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_stalker_help_sos_dialog_3">
		<text>Red? Heard a lot about you. You're one of the few to reach the center of the Zone, is that so?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_stalker_help_sos_dialog_4">
		<text>That's right. And I don't recommend anyone go there. Anyway, we've only got a few minutes left, if we're not too late already. You with me?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_stalker_help_sos_dialog_5_1">
		<text>Of course. How are we doing this?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_stalker_help_sos_dialog_5_2">
		<text>None of my business. Sorry.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_stalker_help_sos_dialog_6">
		<text>As usual, there are loads of creatures in the tunnels, so we'll make our way to him carefully and provide assistance. Afterwards, you cover us while I take my friend to a doctor.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_stalker_help_sos_dialog_7">
		<text>Understood. Let's go.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_diggers_final_robbery_dialog_0">
		<text>So, Olesha, do you have what we agreed on?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_diggers_final_robbery_dialog_1">
		<text>Here. Hope you choke on it.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_diggers_final_robbery_dialog_2">
		<text>You run into an anomaly or something?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_diggers_final_robbery_dialog_3">
		<text>We're even. Give me my equipment and I'll leave, just as agreed.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_diggers_final_robbery_dialog_4">
		<text>Beat it, asshole. And don't show your face again.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_diggers_final_robbery_dialog_5">
		<text>Rat bastards.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_first_dialog_0">
		<text>Halt! No entry without a pass!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_first_dialog_1_1">
		<text>I need Dubinin. He promised me work when we met in the Dark Valley.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_first_dialog_1_2">
		<text>I need Dubinin. I have important news for him.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_first_dialog_2_1">
		<text>Ah, another recruit. I see, I see... Whatever the case, you're not entering the facility without a pass. I'll tell him you're here, and he'll come out if he sees fit. In the meantime, you be on your way. Don't bother us.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_first_dialog_2_2">
		<text>And? Am I supposed you let you through for that? Cough up the pass.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_first_dialog_3_1">
		<text>Got it.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_first_dialog_3_2">
		<text>I don't have one.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_first_dialog_4">
		<text>Then get outta here!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_first_dialog_5">
		<text>What am I gonna do? How do I get a pass?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_first_dialog_6">
		<text>Not my problem. Of course, I could go tell Dubinin he has guests, but that means leaving my post, walking up the stairs... talking to people, which is even worse... and I don't have the energy for that. They give us third-rate meals and it just ain't enough. Tell me, why should I exert myself for some stalker?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_first_dialog_7_1">
		<text>I see. Well, I have some food.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_first_dialog_7_2">
		<text>I'll bring you food.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_first_dialog_8_1">
		<text>Now we're talking. Alright, wait here... if he decides to step out for you, of course. Just stay put and don't meddle.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_first_dialog_8_2">
		<text>Get going. We'll talk later!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_first_dialog_9_1">
		<text>Okay.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_first_dialog_9_2">
		<text>Deal.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_first_dialog_10">
		<text>I'm leaving.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_first_dialog_two_2">
		<text>Now we're talking. Alright, wait here... if Dubinin decides to come out for you, of course. Just stay put and don't meddle.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_first_dialog_two_3">
		<text>Alright.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_stalker_perch_start_dialog_0">
		<text>What, they're not letting you in?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_stalker_perch_start_dialog_1">
		<text>Yeah, no way in without a pass. I see you have one?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_stalker_perch_start_dialog_2">
		<text>I have it. I work with the scientists when I feel like it.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_stalker_perch_start_dialog_3">
		<text>How is it?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_stalker_perch_start_dialog_4">
		<text>It's okay. The tasks don't always pay that well, but it's nothing hard either, usually bringing in cheap artifacts or mutant hooves... Not even the military touches you when you have a pass, which is a plus.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_stalker_perch_start_dialog_5">
		<text>How can I get such a pass?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_stalker_perch_start_dialog_6">
		<text>Well, for that, you gotta give the scientists a good show: first, you get rid of your detector and bolts, go in right between a couple of Whirligigs and then... You should see the look on your face - I'm kidding! I got mine in the Bar through negotiating with a drunken scientist. Told him I saw a red Meat Chunk at the Rostok factory, but I couldn't get to it 'cause of anomalies. This was all bullshit, of course, but he fell for it and asked me to take him there; promised me a pass, scientific medkits, and all sorts of detectors. I signed up just for the pass.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_stalker_perch_start_dialog_7">
		<text>Did you take him there?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_stalker_perch_start_dialog_8">
		<text>Well, I did. Like I said, there was no red Meat Chunk there. I told him, "Well, sorry. Bandits must've snatched it - they stopped to rest not far from here." He got upset, but I got the pass, and now I can walk into the facility and bring them all sorts of things. They don't let me into the building, of course, but I visit this one guy who can hook you up with work with free stalkers. You should look for him, 'cause they don't let just anyone inside.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_stalker_perch_start_dialog_9">
		<text>Thanks for the info.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_stalker_perch_start_dialog_10">
		<text>Hey, if you're ever at the Bar, come see me. I see you're not lacking in equipment. You could join our squad - we work for the Barman. Work isn't as easy as what the scientists give, but the pay goes up too. Think about it.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_stalker_perch_start_dialog_11">
		<text>Alright. I'll keep that in mind.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_task_dialog_0_1">
		<text>Oh, my old acquaintance! Hello! What brings you here? Did you accept my proposal to collaborate?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_task_dialog_0_2">
		<text>Oh, my old acquaintance! Hello! What brings you here?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_task_dialog_1_1">
		<text>We'll discuss that later. Gamzat from the Garbage sent me. He asked me to hand you these papers.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_task_dialog_1_2">
		<text>We'll discuss that later. Gamzat from the Garbage sent me and asked me to hand you these papers. Since I had no time in Dark Valley, I'm also here to return your device.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_task_dialog_2_1">
		<text>Oh, so quickly! He's doing fine. Since he's entrusted you with delivering the documents, I believe you're already aware of our mutual business? You do realize that this remains strictly between us?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_task_dialog_2_2">
		<text>Thank you for returning our equipment! Gamzat is doing fine. Since he's entrusted you with delivering the documents, I believe you're already aware of our mutual business? You do realize that this remains strictly between us?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_task_dialog_3">
		<text>Yes, I understand.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_task_dialog_4">
		<text>Why did professor Gamzatov not warn us that he'd send you to hand over the research?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_task_dialog_5">
		<text>Bad news, I'm afraid: he's dead.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_task_dialog_6">
		<text>Gamzatov, dead? How? What happened?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_task_dialog_7">
		<text>We were testing his theory on sedating mutants with transmuted artifacts. Everything went as planned until the artifact literally dissolved in my hands.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_task_dialog_8">
		<text>Goodness. That's... very bad news for all of us. Truly, he was a valuable assistant... and a good friend. It's hard to believe everything went such a way, and now all research in that field faces a great risk. No one knew it better than Gamzatov. I do hope that these documents will provide useful insights and that his death wasn't in vain.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_task_dialog_9">
		<text>I share your grief. A good man with a noble goal... I wonder how they'll do without a medic now.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_task_dialog_10">
		<text>You know, I could help you with that. I believe the stalkers would be grateful to you if you brought them a new medic.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_task_dialog_11">
		<text>How?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_task_dialog_12">
		<text>One of our workers was recently kicked out of the facility. He may be a slob, but he knows his medicine well... or at least knows how to patch wounds from boar fangs. There is one problem, though...</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_task_dialog_13">
		<text>What problem?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_task_dialog_14">
		<text>He took to drinking. After his dismissal, he spent his entire payroll on drinks. He slept next to the fence surrounding the facility, begging us to accept him back and causing a ruckus until security kicked him out. What a shame... His liver will fail in a week or two if he continues like that. You should talk to him - he doesn't want to listen to us, his former colleagues, but with you, it's a different story. Perhaps you could convince him to come to his senses and go to the stalker base, as Gamzat once did.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_task_dialog_15">
		<text>Yeah, having a medic is vital. I hurt my shoulder a while ago, and I'd be screwed without a doctor. What's his name, and where can I find him?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_task_dialog_16">
		<text>Alexander Kireyev. I don't know where he is, but he was last seen to the southwest. Look there.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_task_dialog_17">
		<text>I'll try.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_task_dialog_18">
		<text>In the meantime, I'll try to study Gamzatov's notes. You are one of few who know about our research, and I hope we can continue our partnership. Can I count on you? You'll be paid, of course.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_task_dialog_19">
		<text>I'd say yes.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_task_dialog_20">
		<text>Excellent. Then I'll contact you when we have the results.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_task_dialog_21">
		<text>Until next time.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_drunk_medic_start_dialog_0">
		<text>Huh?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_drunk_medic_start_dialog_1">
		<text>Alex, c'mon, get up!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_drunk_medic_start_dialog_2">
		<text>What... hic! do you... hic! want? Who are you even, huh? Get outta here.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_drunk_medic_start_dialog_3">
		<text>You sure picked a good sleeping place...</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_drunk_medic_start_dialog_4">
		<text>Whatcha want? Get out!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_drunk_medic_start_dialog_5">
		<text>So you're going to lay here until your liver fails?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_drunk_medic_start_dialog_6">
		<text>I'll shoot ya down, ya hear? What do ya want from me? What does it even matter to you?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_drunk_medic_start_dialog_7">
		<text>I want you to stop burying your precious knowledge with liters of vodka. Yes, you were kicked out, but people still need you. Not the scientists, but ordinary stalkers in need of medical assistance. Let's get to the camp so you can get some sleep and start working there.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_drunk_medic_start_dialog_8">
		<text>I ain't got nothing to do no more... I feel just fine here. I said get out of here! I'll bash your face with my stock!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_drunk_medic_start_dialog_9">
		<text>What do you say about a drink?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_drunk_medic_start_dialog_10">
		<text>Well, why didn't you just say so? Instead of coming here and getting under my skin... C'mon now, pour it up!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_drunk_medic_start_dialog_11">
		<text>Bottoms up!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_drunk_medic_start_dialog_12">
		<text>So... what do I call you?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_drunk_medic_start_dialog_13">
		<text>Axe!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_drunk_medic_start_dialog_14">
		<text>What's your name?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_drunk_medic_start_dialog_15">
		<text>Sorry, but I don't have a death wish. I'll keep my name to myself.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_drunk_medic_start_dialog_16">
		<text>Why's that? Pour it up!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_drunk_medic_start_dialog_17">
		<text>Cheers! Because that's how it is here. No real names in the Zone.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_drunk_medic_start_dialog_18">
		<text>Ah, you stalkers and your unwritten rules... I never went far beyond the base, so I didn't know. Sorry. I'm Alex! Sanya!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_drunk_medic_start_dialog_19">
		<text>Sanya, what's with the drinking yourself into an early grave?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_drunk_medic_start_dialog_20">
		<text>The hell am I supposed to do? They kicked me out of the base for nothing. Ain't my fault the equipment broke, but there's no way you'll get that into their heads!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_drunk_medic_start_dialog_21">
		<text>They won't let you back now?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_drunk_medic_start_dialog_22">
		<text>Tried already. They won't.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_drunk_medic_start_dialog_23">
		<text>"Tried" how? By protesting outside the fence, asleep with a bottle in your hand?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_drunk_medic_start_dialog_24">
		<text>Don't push it, okay? I tried and they won't let me back. That equipment had a serious glitch... Pour it up! Gotta drink more!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_drunk_medic_start_dialog_25">
		<text>Phew... I'm really feeling it.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_drunk_medic_start_dialog_26">
		<text>I've felt it for a week, and it won't let me go. This is the way to live!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_drunk_medic_start_dialog_27">
		<text>You think? You want to drink under a tree and sleep with rotting swines? Is this what you've studied for and put your soul into?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_drunk_medic_start_dialog_28">
		<text>What else do I have left? Pour up, damn it. Why's my glass empty?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_drunk_medic_start_dialog_29">
		<text>I suggest... hick... you relocate to the stalker camp. They need a medic there. You can help people.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_drunk_medic_start_dialog_30">
		<text>Wait, what about Gamzat?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_drunk_medic_start_dialog_31">
		<text>He's gone...</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_drunk_medic_start_dialog_32">
		<text>Well I'll be... Let's drink to his memory!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_drunk_medic_start_dialog_33">
		<text>Let's! And to yours, if you don't put away the bottle!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_drunk_medic_start_dialog_34">
		<text>Honestly, I don't care. I always wanted to be in the Zone, in that specific facility - not the old one in Yantar - and I got what I wanted. And I got kicked out in six months. I'm such a dumbass, right? Pour up, I said!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_drunk_medic_start_dialog_35">
		<text>That sure hit the spot. Phew! Take my word and go to the stalkers. You can benefit people, and you might return to the facility if you prove you can control yourself.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_drunk_medic_start_dialog_36">
		<text>I dunno...</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_drunk_medic_start_dialog_37">
		<text>What do you mean, you don't know? If I were you, I'd do it right this instant! You get to sit and make a killing while we, the stalkers, dive into damp tunnels underground or deal with those goddamned mutants! I used to wander around at the Cordon, earning bit by bit. When I decided to make my way to the center, everything changed. The things I ran into back then! You have any idea what crap dwells in the Dark Valley? Psychic creatures that hammer at your head to the point you stop perceiving reality. And as for ghosts? They're real. I have no idea what they are, but I've seen it all with my own eyes! And that's not even the center of the Zone... The things happening here are very real! Pour up!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_drunk_medic_start_dialog_38">
		<text>Yeah... Tough luck for you stalkers!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_drunk_medic_start_dialog_39">
		<text>Still, this is the life I want. Society around me makes me sick. Better being here with psychic creatures and ghosts! Fill it up!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_drunk_medic_start_dialog_40">
		<text>Cheers!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_drunk_medic_start_dialog_41">
		<text>I'm starting to envy you! I mean, look at me: who needs me? Where does anyone want me? Nowhere! Those hucksters only need me as an errand boy, as cannon fodder for their big business. Sure, they pay, but it's next to nothing. You, on the other hand, could be of use to the stalkers, help them live another day. Pour it!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_drunk_medic_start_dialog_42">
		<text>Maybe you're right... I'll sleep it off and head to the stalkers first thing in the morning.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_drunk_medic_start_dialog_43">
		<text>That's the spirit! I'll check on you later and see how you settle in. You're a good guy, Sanya! One more for you.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_drunk_medic_start_dialog_44">
		<text>You look like you're done, pal. You okay?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_drunk_medic_start_dialog_45">
		<text>I'm greeeat... burp... hic...</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_drunk_medic_start_dialog_46">
		<text>I'll come by later, Sanya.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_task_second_dialog_0">
		<text>Good morning. You look rather unwell.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_task_second_dialog_1">
		<text>It's all your Kireyev's fault. I had to join him in his drinking to get it into his head...</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_task_second_dialog_2">
		<text>Did you manage to convince him?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_task_second_dialog_3">
		<text>I hope so. He wasn't there in the morning. Either he's in the stalker camp or off to get another bottle. I hope it's the former... Got something to discuss with me?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_task_second_dialog_4">
		<text>I do. I've studied Gamzatov's notes and made certain conclusions. Since few people know about our experiment, I'd first like to ask: are you willing to continue working with me on this? If you accept, I promise you a pass into the facility and a worthy payment.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_task_second_dialog_5">
		<text>Sure, I could try.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_task_second_dialog_6">
		<text>Then I would like for everything we say to each other to remain strictly confidential. May I count on you?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_task_second_dialog_7">
		<text>You may.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_task_second_dialog_8">
		<text>Then listen. I will attempt not to go into details and put everything as simply as possible.\n \nGamzatov and I have, for some time, engaged in artifact transmutation experiments. Through hybridization, they've displayed unique properties... provided everything is done correctly, of course. At times, we've succeeded in improving the properties of an artifact, occasionally even giving it new features. In addition, Gamzatov was sure that artifacts are somehow capable of affecting not only humans but also mutants. He only began conducting his own experiments *after* our branch of research was closed down.\n \nThe notes you brought to me verified that he attempted to procreate a selection of the Soul and Stone Flower artifacts. It gave us rather specific results, as you might've noticed: when in vicinity of the artifact, mutants calm down. Do you realize the magnitude of this discovery? For some reason, however, such artifact formations act only for a limited time.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_task_second_dialog_9">
		<text>What do we do, then?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_task_second_dialog_10">
		<text>I've made some calculations according to the notes, and I've found that it is intrinsically dependent on the force of the anomalies where the transmutation occurs. At the Garbage, they're not nearly as strong as we'd like, so the selection was not entirely successful. Our task is to find an anomaly field strong and concentrated enough to yield a better outcome.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_task_second_dialog_11">
		<text>What will be required?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_task_second_dialog_12">
		<text>Unfortunately, I don't know where such an anomaly field may be found, but I do know where to begin the search: a group of military stalkers recently returned from the area around Novoshepelychi and reported anomalous acitivity after the last emission. I'm sure the transmutation can be carried out in the most powerful of these fields. Are you willing to depart there?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_task_second_dialog_13">
		<text>Novoshepelychi? Never been there. Could you clarify what I need to do?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_task_second_dialog_14">
		<text>Your task is to reach the area and place five scanners along a certain perimeter. Using them, we will determine the zone with the highest level of anomalous activity. After that, you will carry out a transmutation. It's very simple - I will give you a small technical manual.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_task_second_dialog_15">
		<text>I think I understand. Anything else?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_task_second_dialog_16">
		<text>Yes. I've carried out a selection of the Soul and Stone Flower artifacts in the anomaly field in the swamp that's nearby. The artifact should have transformed by now. Go to the swamp together with an assistant of mine and try to extract it.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_task_second_dialog_17">
		<text>Keep your assistant. I'll make it on my own.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_task_second_dialog_18">
		<text>The anomaly field in the swamp is very dangerous - it'll help if you go together. After retrieving the artifact, return to the facility. You will find me outdoors. Oh, and here's your pass and settling-in allowance. Good luck!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_task_second_dialog_19">
		<text>Thank you.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_assistant_start_dialog_0">
		<text>Hello. Are you ready to retrieve the artifact?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_assistant_start_dialog_1_1">
		<text>I'm ready. What's the plan?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_assistant_start_dialog_1_2">
		<text>Not ready yet.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_assistant_start_dialog_2">
		<text>I believe professor Dubinin has already told you about the abundance of anomalies in that area. With help of an anomaly detection device, I'll be able to calculate a safe path to the artifact. After that, it's all up to you. Clear?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_assistant_start_dialog_3">
		<text>Clear.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_assistant_second_dialog_0">
		<text>Phew!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_assistant_second_dialog_1">
		<text>How are you? Are you okay?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_assistant_second_dialog_2">
		<text>I'm okay. Damn... What are they... Why'd they do that?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_assistant_second_dialog_3">
		<text>This is the Zone. Some here would die to get their hands on an ordinary Jellyfish, and for this artifact... they'd sell their soul to the devil.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_assistant_second_dialog_4">
		<text>They shot us on sight, without warning!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_assistant_second_dialog_5">
		<text>They must've been frightened. Don't worry - it's all behind us.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_assistant_second_dialog_6">
		<text>I didn't think I'd have to use this pistol. Got it eons ago.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_assistant_second_dialog_7">
		<text>First time in action? Congratulations!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_assistant_second_dialog_8">
		<text>Uhuh. Thanks.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_assistant_second_dialog_9">
		<text>How are we getting the artifact? Looks like one guy didn't make it already.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_assistant_second_dialog_10">
		<text>That's why I went with you. I'll now try to locate a safe point where you can begin moving toward the anomaly.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_assistant_second_dialog_11">
		<text>Alright.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_assistant_third_dialog_0">
		<text>Damn it!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_assistant_third_dialog_1">
		<text>What happened?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_assistant_third_dialog_2">
		<text>Look at that! See this? A bullet! How'd that happen?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_assistant_third_dialog_3">
		<text>No way. The device saved your life!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_assistant_third_dialog_4">
		<text>Yes. Lucky me... This will, however, add a level of complexity in getting to the artifact. We have no other device right now.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_assistant_third_dialog_5">
		<text>I promise nothing, but I'll try getting into the anomaly. I have some experience, and thank goodness that experience was on the positive side.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_assistant_third_dialog_6">
		<text>I can only cross my fingers for you from over here, on the shore.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_assistant_third_dialog_7">
		<text>Let's do this.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_assistant_reversed_dialog_0">
		<text>What a feat! You haphazardly retrieved the artifact with no devices!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_assistant_reversed_dialog_1">
		<text>I'll admit I'm surprised myself.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_assistant_reversed_dialog_2">
		<text>In any circumstance, you would've had to act by yourself. My equipment took a bullet in the firefight.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_assistant_reversed_dialog_3">
		<text>It happens. So, are we going back to base?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_assistant_reversed_dialog_4">
		<text>You go and I'll catch up. I'm not as nimble as you.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_assistant_reversed_dialog_5">
		<text>Later, then.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_assistant_wait_artefact_dialog_0">
		<text>Try to retrieve the artifact!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_assistant_wait_artefact_dialog_1">
		<text>I'll think of something.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_assistant_four_dialog_0">
		<text>You were hanging by a thread! The anomaly triggered several times, and I nearly jumped out of my skin!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_assistant_four_dialog_1">
		<text>Easy. I've dealt with artifacts harder than this.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_assistant_four_dialog_2">
		<text>Then we can return to the facility. Shall we go?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_assistant_four_dialog_3">
		<text>Let's go.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_task_third_dialog_0">
		<text>Oh, you're back! How did it go?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_task_third_dialog_1_1">
		<text>We had to go in blind. Your device took a bullet and ceased working.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_task_third_dialog_1_2">
		<text>We had to go in blind.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_task_third_dialog_2">
		<text>What happened? Is Karavayev alive?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_task_third_dialog_3_1">
		<text>He's alive. We're lucky the bullet went into the device, or else... Ask him yourself what happened.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_task_third_dialog_3_2">
		<text>He's alive. We're lucky the bullet didn't go into his head, or else... Ask him yourself what happened.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_task_third_dialog_4">
		<text>Did you retrieve the artifact?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_task_third_dialog_5">
		<text>Yes. I have it.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_task_third_dialog_6">
		<text>Good. That means almost everything is done. We only have to find and retrieve one more artifact, and then we can commence searching for an anomalous zone.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_task_third_dialog_7">
		<text>What kind of artifact?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_task_third_dialog_8">
		<text>"Concrete Chip". That's its name. A very rare specimen, but I know where one was last seen. It happens to be in Novoshepelychi, in the abandoned military base. If no one's yet walked away with it, it should be there. Once you find the Insulator, you will have to install five scanners in areas marked on your map. After that, I'll send you the location of the zone with the highest anomalous activity - that's where you will transmutate the "Concrete Chip" and "Starwort" artifacts.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_task_third_dialog_9">
		<text>Starwort?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_task_third_dialog_10">
		<text>My name for the artifact you retrieved in the swamp. Don't mind it - it's a temporary name.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_task_third_dialog_11">
		<text>Okay, seems clear enough. I hope the scanners aren't heavy?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_task_third_dialog_12">
		<text>No, of course not. No heavier than a mobile phone. I don't believe you'll exhaust yourself... heh.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_task_third_dialog_13">
		<text>That settles it, then. Can I go?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_task_third_dialog_14">
		<text>Yes. Here are the scanners and an additional sum. And remember: tell no one about the purpose of your visit to Novoshepelychi. We know of a few squads of stalkers in the area around the village, and it's best they don't know anything. In official terms, you went to search for artifacts marked on a list from me. Understood?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_task_third_dialog_15">
		<text>Yes, of course.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_task_third_dialog_16">
		<text>Then I look forward to hearing from you soon. Good luck!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_task_third_dialog_17">
		<text>Thank you. I hope we'll meet again soon.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_secondary_dialogs_0">
		<text>I have a few questions.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_secondary_dialogs_1">
		<text>Of course. Ask.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_secondary_dialogs_2_1">
		<text>Why was your research shut down?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_secondary_dialogs_2_2">
		<text>Can you tell me more about the science facility?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_secondary_dialogs_2_3">
		<text>What happened to your assistants at Yantar?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_secondary_dialogs_2_4">
		<text>Why are stalkers not allowed in the main building?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_secondary_dialogs_2_5">
		<text>While at the Cordon, some stalkers and I ran into some strange flesh who lure victims and imitate stalker voices. Sound familiar in any way?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_secondary_dialogs_2_6">
		<text>Why did you sell psychotropic substances to the bandits?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_secondary_dialogs_2_7">
		<text>Tell me about this place.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_secondary_dialogs_2_8">
		<text>I'd like to know about the Agroprom Undergrounds.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_secondary_dialogs_3_1">
		<text>Unfortunately, our financing is unstable, and our superiors expect immediate results. Our research offered great potential, but we still had a great deal of work on our hands. Not just that, though: science is not just about formulas but experiments through trial and error. Loosely speaking, we did not have enough expendable supplies... artifacts. The head of the scientific department argued that we were wasting precious resources without visible results and closed our work. Yet, several other assistants and I, including Gamzatov - may his soul rest in peace - were passionate to carry through with the project, and so we never abandoned it.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_secondary_dialogs_3_2">
		<text>The facility was established a year ago; a decision that I believe was long due. The Zone does have its share of mobile stations, but all are located in harsh areas where no ordinary scientists would ever go regardless of the salary. Only zealous scientists who'd do anything for the sake of discoveries would work there - even amidst dirty, snork-filled swamps. The fact stands that ordinary scientists used to working in calm and comfortable conditions are also significant, which is what this complex is ideal for: its location is the most favorable for our work, being part of the Zone but not in its center, and thus giving us a safer work environment for research. Thanks to additional financing, new staff was recruited and new areas of research were opened up; part of that new staff included me, Gamzatov, and many others. Additionally, the situation at Yantar has recently taken an unpleasant turn: the lake overflowed its banks, the bunker flooded, and mutants poured in. The area turned into a dead zone overnight, making this place, undoubtedly, the scientific center of the Zone.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_secondary_dialogs_3_3">
		<text>They died. Frankly speaking, I don't know the details, but I haven't met them since. It's classified information. In these times, stalkers avoid Yantar altogether - that place holds only death and nothing more.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_secondary_dialogs_3_4">
		<text>Well, what do you think? We conduct secret research there, and as few people as possible should know about it. Therefore, access to the main building is restricted to those with special passes, which hired stalkers do not carry.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_secondary_dialogs_3_5">
		<text>I've heard lots, but unfortunately, we lack detailed information. Many consider it to be part of the numerous campfire tales from the Zone. I don't think I'm the right person to ask, though I've heard the swamp is home to the Swamp Doctor - he heals stalkers and even mutants. Perhaps he could shed light on your question?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_secondary_dialogs_3_6">
		<text>I'm have no fondness for such individuals, if we can even call them that, but research takes priority over principles. I'm in dire need of finances in order for our work to flourish.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_secondary_dialogs_3_7">
		<text>Now, as you can see, it is a full-fledged scientific complex with everything necessary to study such an interesting, so to speak, place. At least, as far as our budget and current geographical conditions allow. Did you know that it was here before, back in the Soviet Union? Now, listen, since you asked. I'll give you a history lesson, so to speak. The central building of the institute was built in the seventies, when Pripyat was still under construction. It was a large medical complex known as the Medpribor Research Institute. According to the official, so to speak, version, this place was supposed to treat people, study diseases, perform especially complicated operations and conduct other medical research. They obviously spared no expense, as a lot of expensive equipment had been imported and a large number of bright minds had been attracted. But you know that a lot of truths were hidden from people during the Soviet Union..... Therefore, I am convinced that the complex was obviously military-oriented, as can be seen from the surviving documents and remnants of infrastructure. However, after the Chernobyl accident in 1986, this place changed its original purpose. People were evacuated and there was no one left to treat them. So then this research institute began to study and analyse the effect of radioactive radiation on plants and soil. So to speak, they wanted to check how radiation affects the growth and development of agricultural crops. The central complex contained administrative facilities, test sites and even plantations for growing plants. We have them now, by the way, if you've noticed. A tribute to the traditions of Soviet science, so to speak. But another building, a few kilometres further down the road, used to be the central loading complex. There they stored and later transported various cargoes and fertilisers along the railway tracks. Some trains were driven to the big earth, and some were sent through the tunnels towards the undergrounds of Pripyat. What they did with them, I don't know myself.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_secondary_dialogs_3_8">
		<text>Before this place became an Exclusion Zone, these undergrounds served as communication collectors. They were used to supply heat, electricity and other communications to the facilities, as well as to drain the institute's sewage into the nearest body of water. And now this place is abandoned, filled with anomalies and mutants. Why, it's a very acceptable environment for all sorts of local nasties. To be honest, we in the complex can not be happy with the fact that right next door is a rich source of various biomaterial and anomalous formations for research. But not everyone dares to go down there. And mutants and anomalies are not the main threat. In my opinion, the collectors could collapse at almost any moment! In Soviet times, even though they built everything for centuries, but this dungeon has suffered a lot of fate! When this base was still inhabited by representatives of the group Duty, they and some mercenary flooded most of the collectors to stop mutant attacks. Some rooms are still flooded to this day. And a few years after the flood, there was a war here! I don't know how many grenades exploded inside and how much damage the structures of the dungeons might have sustained. So my prediction is that in a couple of years, there will be no more places like the Agroprom Undergrounds on the map of the Zone.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_secondary_dialogs_4_1">
		<text>And if you get exposed?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_secondary_dialogs_5_1">
		<text>At best, I'll be discharged. At worst, I'll face court.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_secondary_dialogs_6_1">
		<text>Are you willing to take those risks?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_secondary_dialogs_7_1">
		<text>As of late, the science facility has remained at a standstill. We are no longer making discoveries or researching what we should be researching. Our project is all that's capable of turning the tide, and I'm ready to risk everything - including my own life - to reach an outcome.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_secondary_dialogs_8_1">
		<text>But you're working behind your superiors' backs. Where are you going with your developments?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_secondary_dialogs_9_1">
		<text>As I've mentioned, they expect immediate results. Hence, they'll disregard the fact that we've been working clandestinely. At any rate, this isn't the first time it happens.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_secondary_dialogs_10">
		<text>Thanks. That's all.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_secondary_dialogs_11">
		<text>We'll talk another time.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_idle_dialog_0">
		<text>Hello.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_idle_dialog_1">
		<text>Welcome.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_idle_dialog_2">
		<text>What brings you by?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_idle_dialog_3">
		<text>Nice to see you.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_idle_dialog_4">
		<text>How are you?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_close_post_dialog_0">
		<text>Halt! This is the service entrance. If you want to enter, go through the main one. Don't expect any entry without a pass.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_close_post_dialog_1">
		<text>I understand.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_second_dialog_0">
		<text>Didn't I tell you already? No pass, no entry.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_second_dialog_1_1">
		<text>I'm leaving.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_second_dialog_1_2">
		<text>I have a pass.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_second_dialog_2">
		<text>I see. Go on, but keep your gun out of sight.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_second_dialog_3">
		<text>Right.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_wait_supplies_dialog_0">
		<text>Got the food?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_wait_supplies_dialog_1_1">
		<text>Have a nice meal.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_wait_supplies_dialog_1_2">
		<text>I'll be right back.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_idle_actor_dialog_0">
		<text>Until next time, professor.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_idle_actor_dialog_1">
		<text>Take care.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_idle_actor_dialog_2">
		<text>Bye, professor.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_idle_actor_dialog_3">
		<text>I'm going.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_idle_actor_dialog_4">
		<text>See you.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_stalker_trader_idle_dialog_0_1">
		<text>What do you need?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_stalker_trader_idle_dialog_0_2">
		<text>Well, hello, stalker.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_stalker_trader_idle_dialog_0_3">
		<text>What do you need, stalker?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_stalker_trader_idle_dialog_0_4">
		<text>Come here. Got lots in store.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_stalker_trader_idle_dialog_0_5">
		<text>Wanna trade?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_stalker_technic_idle_dialog_0_1">
		<text>What did you break this time?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_stalker_technic_idle_dialog_0_2">
		<text>What've you got, stalker?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_stalker_technic_idle_dialog_0_3">
		<text>Hi. Come to patch up your armor?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_stalker_technic_idle_dialog_0_4">
		<text>Hey, man.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_stalker_technic_idle_dialog_0_5">
		<text>Welcome. Show me what you need fixed.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_colonel_idle_dialog_0_1">
		<text>I'm listening.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_colonel_idle_dialog_0_2">
		<text>Speak.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_colonel_idle_dialog_0_3">
		<text>Speak up.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_colonel_idle_dialog_0_4">
		<text>Got something to discuss?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_colonel_idle_dialog_0_5">
		<text>What've you got?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_actor_with_colonel_idle_dialog_0_1">
		<text>I'm going, colonel, sir.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_actor_with_colonel_idle_dialog_0_2">
		<text>Permission to leave, sir?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_actor_with_colonel_idle_dialog_0_3">
		<text>I'll be on my way, if you allow it.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_colonel_start_yantar_dialog_0">
		<text>Hello.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_colonel_start_yantar_dialog_1">
		<text>Called for me?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_colonel_start_yantar_dialog_2">
		<text>I did. How are things in the facility? How's it treating you?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_colonel_start_yantar_dialog_3">
		<text>Badly. Is that what you wanted to discuss with me?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_colonel_start_yantar_dialog_4">
		<text>Watch it! Or I'll have you guarding the cornfields until your contract expires. If you want to head out, you'll get to head out. You ready for this mission?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_colonel_start_yantar_dialog_5">
		<text>I'm always ready.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_colonel_start_yantar_dialog_6">
		<text>What, not gonna ask what you're taking on?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_colonel_start_yantar_dialog_7">
		<text>I'm tired of seeing the same faces. I signed my contract to work in the Zone, not to pave trails at Agroprom.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_colonel_start_yantar_dialog_8">
		<text>I won't even tell you that you brought it upon yourself. You know it full well. Speak to professor Volkov and he'll tell you everything.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_colonel_start_yantar_dialog_9">
		<text>Understood.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_yantar_dialog_0">
		<text>You do know what happened a month ago at Yantar?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_yantar_dialog_1">
		<text>Everyone knows. Place is flooded, scientists are dead.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_yantar_dialog_2">
		<text>We'd like to believe that there are survivors left. If not - dear lord, I hope not - then their research is of utmost importance to us. We must extract all objects of interest to us from the science bunker. As of late, professor Sakharov was carrying out some rather interesting studies, and I do hope their result wasn't left behind there... or worse, in the hands of stalkers.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_yantar_dialog_3">
		<text>What are our exact objectives?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_yantar_dialog_4">
		<text>Investigate the situation, rescue any survivors and retrieve the results of the research. It's also crucial that we get a full picture of the incident there; we don't know a damn thing about what hppened.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_yantar_dialog_5">
		<text>Understood. Any additional instructions?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_yantar_dialog_6">
		<text>You'll get them during the course of the operation. We'll try to stay in touch with you. That's all for now.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_scientist_yantar_dialog_7">
		<text>Got it.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_colonel_start_second_dialog_0">
		<text>Everything clear? You'll move out tomorrow at dawn, so have your squad gear up. You'll have special equipment for this one... as well as an additional member.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_colonel_start_second_dialog_1">
		<text>Why another? The four of us will manage. Who is this man anyway?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_colonel_start_second_dialog_2">
		<text>Dmytro Koval. He's a former stalker and knows a lot about anomalous formations. Having a specialist by your side won't hurt.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_colonel_start_second_dialog_3">
		<text>Koval? A questionable person. I'm sure we'll manage without him.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_colonel_start_second_dialog_4">
		<text>Denied. Koval's going with you and that's final. One more thing: I believe you understand that you won't be running into any survivors. Concentrate on finding the scientists' data and pull out of there.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_colonel_start_second_dialog_5">
		<text>How do we know there are no survivors left?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_colonel_start_second_dialog_6">
		<text>We caught a distress signal as soon as shit hit the fan. It all went quiet, and no one even tried making radio contact. I doubt anyone made it.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_colonel_start_second_dialog_7">
		<text>Understood. Permission to be dismissed, sir.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_colonel_start_second_dialog_8">
		<text>Granted, lieutenant.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_colonel_start_second_dialog_9">
		<text>Thank you. I'm off.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_vuslich_before_sending_dialog_0">
		<text>Hey, boss!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_vuslich_before_sending_dialog_1">
		<text>Hi. I see you're exercising here? Attaboys. You don't waste time.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_vuslich_before_sending_dialog_2">
		<text>What else is there to do? We're burning sunshine here. Anyway, I heard the colonel called you? Did they really trust us with something better than guarding expeditions?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_vuslich_before_sending_dialog_3">
		<text>They did. Tomorrow morning, we fly to lake Yantar. The mobile bunker's flooded there, and the scientists aren't making any radio contact. I'm told there are zero survivors, so we need to concentrate on finding research data. Wake up Sky, finish up your training, and get in gear. I'll go talk to another passenger of ours.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_vuslich_before_sending_dialog_4">
		<text>Who's that?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_vuslich_before_sending_dialog_5_1">
		<text>Koval. The colonel insisted he come with us, though I have no idea why. I'll go find out what kind of guy that is... sounds too slippery for my liking.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_vuslich_before_sending_dialog_5_2">
		<text>Koval. The colonel insisted he come with us, though I have no idea why. I talked to him, and he's real sketchy...</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_vuslich_before_sending_dialog_6">
		<text>Well, don't think about it too much. We'll go get our equipment.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_vuslich_before_sending_dialog_7">
		<text>Go on.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_koval_before_sending_dialog_0">
		<text>Oh, hey.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_koval_before_sending_dialog_1">
		<text>Didn't the colonel tell you? Tomorrow morning, you're going with my squad to Yantar.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_koval_before_sending_dialog_2">
		<text>He told me.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_koval_before_sending_dialog_3">
		<text>So what the hell are you doing here?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_koval_before_sending_dialog_4">
		<text>I'm all set for the flight. Don't work yourself up.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_koval_before_sending_dialog_5">
		<text>The question stands. What are you doing here?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_koval_before_sending_dialog_6">
		<text>Why's that matter to you?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_koval_before_sending_dialog_7">
		<text>From this moment on, I am your commanding officer. If I ask you anything, you answer. I give you an order, you carry it out. Understood?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_koval_before_sending_dialog_8">
		<text>Understood, understood. Easy, just wanted to stretch my legs. There's plenty of time before we head off.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_koval_before_sending_dialog_9">
		<text>You know our objective?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_koval_before_sending_dialog_10">
		<text>The colonel gave me a quick rundown.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_koval_before_sending_dialog_11">
		<text>Good. We'll discuss details on the way to Yantar. Go get ready, and do message me about any and all movements. You want to stretch your legs or take a piss, you report to me. Clear?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_koval_before_sending_dialog_12">
		<text>Clear, commander. Clear.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_koval_before_sending_dialog_13">
		<text>I'll see you before dawn.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_soldier_xottab_after_yantar_start_dialog_0">
		<text>Morning! Sleep well?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_soldier_xottab_after_yantar_start_dialog_1">
		<text>Morning. I suppose... though my head's splitting. Seems we had a real good time yesterday.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_soldier_xottab_after_yantar_start_dialog_2">
		<text>A real good time, yeah. I had to keep you on a leash so you wouldn't thrash the whole barracks. The boys next door even came by a few times and asked you to keep it down.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_soldier_xottab_after_yantar_start_dialog_3">
		<text>Man, if the colonel finds out...</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_soldier_xottab_after_yantar_start_dialog_4">
		<text>He stopped by this morning and asked you to see him in his office when you wake up. We gave him the full report, and our compensatory time hasn't ended yet. I wonder what he wants?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_soldier_xottab_after_yantar_start_dialog_5">
		<text>Hope he doesn't charge us for drinking.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_soldier_xottab_after_yantar_start_dialog_6">
		<text>Nah, he seemed to be in a good mood. Don't worry, he's not gonna shout at you or anything.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_soldier_xottab_after_yantar_start_dialog_7">
		<text>We'll see. Maybe he's got some small work for us. I'll go clean up and talk to him.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_washboard_soldier_start_dialog_0">
		<text>Hey, Zhuravlyov. Back on your feet after the operation? You looked exhausted after coming back.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_washboard_soldier_start_dialog_1">
		<text>Alive and kicking, as you can see.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_washboard_soldier_start_dialog_2">
		<text>How are things at Yantar? Must be hell, since stalkers don't go there?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_washboard_soldier_start_dialog_3">
		<text>The colonel asked me to keep it classified - you'll have to ask him yourself. I can only say that this place is a five-star resort in comparison. How are you, what's new?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_washboard_soldier_start_dialog_4">
		<text>One of our scientists went missing. What's his name... Ah, yeah! Dubinin! We gathered all personnel two days ago and combed the entirety of Agroprom... but nope, no signs of him. Came upon a stalker camp and asked them, "Did you see anyone here?" The mentioned some mercenaries hanging by the tunnel. I don't know whether that has anything to do with it, but we have no other clues.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_washboard_soldier_start_dialog_5">
		<text>So did they call off the search?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_washboard_soldier_start_dialog_6">
		<text>Hah! No way. This is Dubinin we're talking about. He's no run-of-the-mill lab assistant; his security's top-notch, and he's got tons of field assistants at his disposal. Until they find him, whether he's alive or dead in a ditch, the colonel's not letting up on this. Want a smoke?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_washboard_soldier_start_dialog_7">
		<text>No, thanks.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_washboard_soldier_start_dialog_8">
		<text>And that other guy, what's his name... Ah, yeah! Koval! I hear he joined you for the operation?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_washboard_soldier_start_dialog_9">
		<text>I dunno. Something's off with him. What matters is that he didn't mess up the operation, and it's good the colonel didn't permanently assign him to our squad. I have far less trust in former stalkers than in any of our men. What do *you* say about joining us?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_washboard_soldier_start_dialog_10">
		<text>Hah. Thanks for the offer, but how can I leave my own guys?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_washboard_soldier_start_dialog_11">
		<text>Sure, okay. I'll be going now. The colonel wanted me.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_washboard_soldier_start_dialog_12">
		<text>Alright. He probably has something to say about Dubinin.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_washboard_soldier_start_dialog_13">
		<text>We'll see.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_washboard_soldier_idle_dialog_0_1">
		<text>Zhuravlyov? I'm all ears.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_washboard_soldier_idle_dialog_0_2">
		<text>Say it.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_washboard_soldier_idle_dialog_0_3">
		<text>Tell me what you've got.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_colonel_after_yantar_dialog_0">
		<text>There you are!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_colonel_after_yantar_dialog_1">
		<text>Sir.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_colonel_after_yantar_dialog_2">
		<text>You're finally awake. How's your head? Koval was just giving me a report on the black smoke substance you saw. We might have to send another expedition to Yantar, but with research assistants this time. Such phenomena need reviewing.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_colonel_after_yantar_dialog_3">
		<text>So that means we're off to Yantar again?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_colonel_after_yantar_dialog_4">
		<text>No. Others will worry about that. I'm assigning you to something else.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_colonel_after_yantar_dialog_5">
		<text>I'm listening.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_colonel_after_yantar_dialog_6">
		<text>We had a little emergency while you were away. Don't know if I can call it "little"... Dubinin, one of the scientists, went missing - he was one of the leading assistants in this facility. He was head of several research projects, so his case is now conducted directly by administration. Your task is to find him, and preferably in one piece. If he's dead, at least we'll know not to look for him anymore.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_colonel_after_yantar_dialog_7">
		<text>Any specific information that will aid the search?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_colonel_after_yantar_dialog_8">
		<text>Specific? Not much. After his disappearance, we gathered a scouting group that searched every inch of Agroprom, but they found no traces, only some undocumented stalkers that told them about an armed mercenary squad near the railway tunnel. We don't know what people they were.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_colonel_after_yantar_dialog_9">
		<text>Did the search not go beyond Agroprom?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_colonel_after_yantar_dialog_10">
		<text>That's where you come in. We'd rather not attract attention and send off entire squads. We need one man we can rely on, someone who won't blow it, and I'm sure you've got what it takes. Just don't screw it up out of nowhere, all right?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_colonel_after_yantar_dialog_11">
		<text>Task is clear, but I need to understand where to commence the search.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_colonel_after_yantar_dialog_12">
		<text>Here's the situation: Dubinin was doing research on artifacts and anomalies, often leaving the facility personally with a milstalker escort. He's spent a lot of time with them - they might know something, or at least give you pointers. And for this one, you'll need to try a lot of pointers...</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_colonel_after_yantar_dialog_13">
		<text>What do you mean?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_colonel_after_yantar_dialog_14">
		<text>Dubinin left the facility and simply vanished into thin air. Alone. And it's anyone's guess where the hell he is. Did he break his contract and go AWOL? Or was he abducted by those mercenaries? Maybe he learned something while researching that made him leave the Zone? There's a lot to speculate about. One more thing: word says he was seen with some stalker, but the reports make no mention of it. It's best we find out who this is.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_colonel_after_yantar_dialog_15">
		<text>Understood. I'll begin right away. Can I bring my boys?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_colonel_after_yantar_dialog_16">
		<text>Do as you see fit. Just remember that everything needs to be done quietly. Following behind Dubinin's trail with your entire squad could mean sabotaging the entire mission. By the way, you can also count on Koval - he'll be assigned to your squad.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_colonel_after_yantar_dialog_17">
		<text>We have no need for him! We'll manage any task without him.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_colonel_after_yantar_dialog_18">
		<text>We've already gone through this! He'll be with you. Look after him - he's a decent man, and his knowledge could be of use. Now, go! Report everything directly to me!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_colonel_after_yantar_dialog_19">
		<text>Yes, sir...</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_soldier_sky_after_yantar_dialog_0">
		<text>Hey, good morning!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_soldier_sky_after_yantar_dialog_1">
		<text>It's afternoon already, lazy bones! I just visited the colonel, and he's got a new mission.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_soldier_sky_after_yantar_dialog_2">
		<text>Oh, sweet! When are we moving? Where are we moving?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_soldier_sky_after_yantar_dialog_3">
		<text>Easy, tiger. For now, I'll be operating on my own, but it's important you stay in touch. I might need help at any moment.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_soldier_sky_after_yantar_dialog_4">
		<text>No problem. What's the mission?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_soldier_sky_after_yantar_dialog_5">
		<text>A scientist disappeared from the facility into thin air. Either he was killed or ran on his own; maybe he died in an anomaly somewhere. I need to look into this and ask the right people. In the meantime, you should try going through the stalker network. We're looking for any mention of the scientists, mercenaries and everything that could help, so get up and get to work. You find anything, report to me.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_soldier_sky_after_yantar_dialog_6">
		<text>Understood. I'll get on it.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_soldier_sky_after_yantar_dialog_7">
		<text>I'll be waiting for updates.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_sec_scientist_1_task_dialog_0">
		<text>What do ya need?...</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_sec_scientist_1_task_dialog_1">
		<text>Sorry for bothering. I've got a question for you.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_sec_scientist_1_task_dialog_2">
		<text>You're not the right rank to be asking me questions. I'm sleeping... Come back later.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_sec_scientist_1_task_dialog_3">
		<text>Hey, I need to ask you something!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_sec_scientist_1_task_second_dialog_0">
		<text>I told you I'm sleeping! What do you want?!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_sec_scientist_1_task_second_dialog_1">
		<text>I said I need to ask you something. Get up and cut the attitude!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_sec_scientist_1_task_second_dialog_2">
		<text>Two words for you: get lost.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_sec_scientist_1_task_second_dialog_3">
		<text>Alright then. I'll just report that Cord refused to testify about professor Dubinin's disappearance, making him the prime suspect. Go back to sleep.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_sec_scientist_1_task_second_dialog_4">
		<text>Hey, wait! I didn't realize what you wanted. What do you want to ask?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_sec_scientist_1_task_second_dialog_5">
		<text>You were part of the professor's escort during his field trips in the Zone. Tell me: where have you been, who have you met, have you noticed anything strange?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_sec_scientist_1_task_second_dialog_6">
		<text>Same old, same old: we go around one anomaly or the other.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_sec_scientist_1_task_second_dialog_7">
		<text>Was there anything strange about his behavior?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_sec_scientist_1_task_second_dialog_8">
		<text>Those scientists always act strange. They mumble something to themselves and get happy, mad, or upset depending on what the numbers on their devices say. Dubinin was always calm, though - I never noticed anything strange about him.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_sec_scientist_1_task_second_dialog_9">
		<text>Did he share any plans with you? Any random remarks?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_sec_scientist_1_task_second_dialog_10">
		<text>During all our trips, he did his work in complete silence... unlike many others.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_sec_scientist_1_task_second_dialog_11">
		<text>When did you last see him?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_sec_scientist_1_task_second_dialog_12">
		<text>'Bout five days ago. We were leading him toward the Swamps, and then he watched something through his binoculars. Then we went back to base.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_sec_scientist_1_task_second_dialog_13">
		<text>Any thoughts about his disappearance?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_sec_scientist_1_task_second_dialog_14">
		<text>No freakin' clue. Maybe he went off somewhere alone and got into an anomaly. We have eggheads disappearing every other day, don't we?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_sec_scientist_1_task_second_dialog_15">
		<text>Ever been new faces in your group that was escorting him?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_sec_scientist_1_task_second_dialog_16">
		<text>Nope. And he's been our only mission all this time.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_sec_scientist_1_task_second_dialog_17">
		<text>Where's your squad right now?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_sec_scientist_1_task_second_dialog_18">
		<text>Kridov's on a mission. I think Longboat went to eat.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_sec_scientist_1_task_second_dialog_19">
		<text>Alright. If you think of anything else, message me on my PDA.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_sec_scientist_2_task_dialog_0">
		<text>Yeah?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_sec_scientist_2_task_dialog_1">
		<text>Sorry to interrupt, but I have an urgent question regarding Dubinin. You know what happened to him.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_sec_scientist_2_task_dialog_2">
		<text>That he disappeared? Yeah, everyone knows 'bout that.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_sec_scientist_2_task_dialog_3">
		<text>What do you have to say about it?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_sec_scientist_2_task_dialog_4">
		<text>I mean... what's there to say?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_sec_scientist_2_task_dialog_5">
		<text>You did guard him, so you're the first ones I'll ask.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_sec_scientist_2_task_dialog_6">
		<text>We did, but that was when we were ordered to escort a research assistant, and he disappeared once he stopped being our responsibility. We're not gonna watch him whenever he goes for a leak, are we? Sorry, but that's not in the contract.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_sec_scientist_2_task_dialog_7">
		<text>Did you notice anything strange during the escort? You didn't see him meeting with anyone outside the facility, mentioning anything specific to you or worrying about anything?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_sec_scientist_2_task_dialog_8">
		<text>He was always one hundred percent calm and collected. We'd reach the target, he'd do his measurements or make his notes, and we'd leave. No remarkable moments, no conversation, business and only business.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_sec_scientist_2_task_dialog_9">
		<text>What are your thoughts on where he might've gone?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_sec_scientist_2_task_dialog_10">
		<text>Who knows? He never shared anything with us - always kept to himself. If you ask me, he probably stopped bothering with us and made his next anomaly trip by himself... and you're not getting out of that alive without the right skill set. I think that's where you need to direct your investigation.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldier_sec_scientist_2_task_dialog_11">
		<text>Alright. Eat up before it gets cold. Message me on my PDA if anything comes up. You'll be rewarded for any assistance.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_soldier_tonnel_boss_start_dialog_0">
		<text>Well, look who decided to visit our swamp! What are you doing here?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_soldier_tonnel_boss_start_dialog_1">
		<text>I've got some questions for you regarding professor Dubinin.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_soldier_tonnel_boss_start_dialog_2">
		<text>Well, I'm not surprised. We're sick and tired of people asking us about him.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_soldier_tonnel_boss_start_dialog_3">
		<text>I don't doubt that, but it's best you answer. The more details, the better.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_soldier_tonnel_boss_start_dialog_4">
		<text>Ask and I'll try to help.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_soldier_tonnel_boss_start_dialog_5">
		<text>You and your men escorted Dubinin on field trips. Did you notice anything strange about his behavior? Did he meet anyone outside the facility or tell you anything that might hint at his disappearance?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_soldier_tonnel_boss_start_dialog_6">
		<text>Out of all the eggheads I've had to work with, he was the most reserved. Ask him anything and he'll answer strictly according to protocol: "Soldier, your job is to hold that gun and keep your eyes sharp." I wanted to ask him about the properties of a few artifacts, but I never got anything out of him.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_soldier_tonnel_boss_start_dialog_7">
		<text>Why did you want to ask that?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_soldier_tonnel_boss_start_dialog_8">
		<text>When I was still a regular stalker in the Zone, I almost lost a friend... well, let's say I did lose him. He just now made it back to the outside - with a mutilated body. I want to help him somehow. I've heard stories about artifacts that can heal, which might help him... but the professor told me nothing, and I haven't learned anything useful.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_soldier_tonnel_boss_start_dialog_9">
		<text>You understand he's tied by a contract. Giving out such information could land him in court.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_soldier_tonnel_boss_start_dialog_10">
		<text>Yeah, I get that. Screw it all.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_soldier_tonnel_boss_start_dialog_11">
		<text>I've heard Dubinin hung around with some stalker. Do you know anything about that?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_soldier_tonnel_boss_start_dialog_12">
		<text>There was no one like that during our escorts, so I can't say anything.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_soldier_tonnel_boss_start_dialog_13">
		<text>Are there any clues you could point me at? He couldn't have vanished into thin air.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_soldier_tonnel_boss_start_dialog_14">
		<text>You're looking in the wrong place, Zhuravlyov. Look in places he might've had a hard-on for to the point he'd leave without an escort. No wonder he hasn't returned - go anywhere alone and you're done in a second. If I were on search duty, I would've checked each of the anomalous zones in the vicinity. That's all I can say, really.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_soldier_tonnel_boss_start_dialog_15">
		<text>Alright. Keep in touch if I have any further questions. If you recall anything or find anything out, message me ASAP.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_soldier_tonnel_boss_second_dialog_0">
		<text>Did you see that? Not an ounce of help from those four-eyed jackasses!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_soldier_tonnel_boss_second_dialog_1">
		<text>They need to be looked after like kids, that's for sure...</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_soldier_tonnel_boss_second_dialog_2">
		<text>When I get back, I'll PT them until their sphincters are sucking buttermilk. And you, thanks for the help. We'd be done for if it were just the two of us.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_soldier_tonnel_boss_second_dialog_3">
		<text>The gunshots didn't help you remember anything about Dubinin, did they?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_soldier_tonnel_boss_second_dialog_4">
		<text>Dubinin... Well, you see, he... Ah, forget it.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_soldier_tonnel_boss_second_dialog_5">
		<text>What? What did you want to say?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_soldier_tonnel_boss_second_dialog_6">
		<text>Nothing! Just know that he isn't such a saint after all for you to be chasing after him. Good luck in your search, Zhuravlyov... Unfortunately, I have nothing to add. Bye.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_soldier_tonnel_boss_second_dialog_7">
		<text>Okay then. Bye.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_soldier_sky_after_search_info_dialog_0">
		<text>Hey there, detective!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_soldier_sky_after_search_info_dialog_1">
		<text>Right now, I wouldn't really call myself a detective.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_soldier_sky_after_search_info_dialog_2">
		<text>What about the body by the anomaly? Could that be Dubinin?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_soldier_sky_after_search_info_dialog_3">
		<text>We're about to find out. Here, take this.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_soldier_sky_after_search_info_dialog_4">
		<text>Ew. Why'd you bring that here?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_soldier_sky_after_search_info_dialog_5">
		<text>We need to see this through and make sure these remains really do belong to Dubinin. This whole thing seems too good to be true, don't you think?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_soldier_sky_after_search_info_dialog_6">
		<text>What do you mean?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_soldier_sky_after_search_info_dialog_7">
		<text>Our milstalker "colleagues" all claim the same thing: that Dubinin might've died in an anomaly. I noticed the remains of someone in a scientific suit, but... damn, you could see that anomaly from a mile away. Are we supposed to believe Dubinin just waltzed right into it, considering his experience? The only way I'm buying that is if we get positive DNA evidence, so grab this piece of anatomy and give it to the right person.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_soldier_sky_after_search_info_dialog_8">
		<text>You're right. Wouldn't hurt to check. I'll hand it to Hottab, since he's good at that stuff. You think our colleagues might've conspired to lie about the professor's disappearance?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_soldier_sky_after_search_info_dialog_9">
		<text>That's a possibility. Kridov seems the most suspicious to me.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_soldier_sky_after_search_info_dialog_10">
		<text>You think he has a part in the disappearance?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_soldier_sky_after_search_info_dialog_11">
		<text>My belief is that he knows something but just isn't telling us. He's a good man and wouldn't have resorted to murder, but that's the same reason he doesn't want to set anyone up and spill the truth. We'll just have to wait for the DNA evidence. Did you dig anything up?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_soldier_sky_after_search_info_dialog_12">
		<text>I tried finding out more about the stalker that hung around with Dubinin. He doesn't appear in the reports, which is already a grave violation of the contract on the professor's part. If you work with a stalker, you need to write down his name in the reports and clarify what kind of assistance he's providing. But he didn't do that. I checked all the records in his chambers, and I've seen this individual on several occasions, even though he's not in the base.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_soldier_sky_after_search_info_dialog_13">
		<text>I don't know him. Do you?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_soldier_sky_after_search_info_dialog_14">
		<text>It's my first time too.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_soldier_sky_after_search_info_dialog_15">
		<text>Judging by his appearance, he seems like an ordinary stalker. And who do you think might know the face of every other stalker in the Zone?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_soldier_sky_after_search_info_dialog_16">
		<text>Who?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_soldier_sky_after_search_info_dialog_17">
		<text>Well, Sidorovich, of course!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_soldier_sky_after_search_info_dialog_18">
		<text>Thinking of visiting him?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_soldier_sky_after_search_info_dialog_19">
		<text>Absolutely. We find the stalker and find out what Dubinin was doing away from the eyes of his superiors.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_soldier_sky_after_search_info_dialog_20">
		<text>Do we accompany you?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_soldier_sky_after_search_info_dialog_21">
		<text>Keep digging. Read through the stalker network and ask every stalker you know. Maybe something will come up. We'll keep the boys on standby; if I need any help, I'll call.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_soldier_sky_after_search_info_dialog_22">
		<text>Got it. There's a helo about to transport an expedition to Dytiatky. They might give you a ride; beats going on foot.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_soldier_sky_after_search_info_dialog_23">
		<text>I sure could use the lift. Alright, I'm off.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_pilot_leader_task_escape_dialog_0">
		<text>Hey!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_pilot_leader_task_escape_dialog_1">
		<text>Hey, Ivanych! You headed for Dytiatky?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_pilot_leader_task_escape_dialog_2">
		<text>Yeah, Zhuravlyov! We're headed south!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_pilot_leader_task_escape_dialog_3">
		<text>Could I come with you?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_pilot_leader_task_escape_dialog_4">
		<text>Wait an hour and we'll let you aboard. These guys gather at turtle speed!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_pilot_leader_task_escape_dialog_5">
		<text>Not a problem. Thanks!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_composer_task_stalker_bird_start_dialog_0">
		<text>And who are you? What do you want?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_composer_task_stalker_bird_start_dialog_1">
		<text>Hi. We came for our boys, the ones lying on the ground. Did you do this?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_composer_task_stalker_bird_start_dialog_2">
		<text>No. I was just passing by, doing my own thing, when I got a PDA message saying, "My boys need help" or something.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_composer_task_stalker_bird_start_dialog_3">
		<text>What message? Did you get a name?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_composer_task_stalker_bird_start_dialog_4">
		<text>I don't know, man. I think it might've been professor Smyshlov, though, 'cause it sure wasn't someone in their twenties.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_composer_task_stalker_bird_start_dialog_5">
		<text>What did he want from you?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_composer_task_stalker_bird_start_dialog_6">
		<text>He told me to meet up with his wards at these coordinates and lead them where they tell me to. I'd get double payment and a couple of artifacts to boot. And now, here I am.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_composer_task_stalker_bird_start_dialog_7">
		<text>You sure took your time. Time someone else used to gun them down.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_composer_task_stalker_bird_start_dialog_8">
		<text>Well, rushing head-on wherever you go is sure to get you killed in the Zone! And for the record, I did get here on time. I was on the hill when I got to see the punks shoot each other. I'm stressed enough, so cut the crap before I blast someone else!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_composer_task_stalker_bird_start_dialog_9">
		<text>They shot at each other?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_composer_task_stalker_bird_start_dialog_10">
		<text>That's right. They all stood up at the same time and started firing, as if they were given an order.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_composer_task_stalker_bird_start_dialog_11">
		<text>Maybe it was a controller?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_composer_task_stalker_bird_start_dialog_12">
		<text>Who the hell knows! I haven't seen anything like that here...</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_composer_task_stalker_bird_start_dialog_13">
		<text>What's your old fart say? Did you talk to him?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_composer_task_stalker_bird_start_dialog_14">
		<text>Not yet, since you're here and all. Listen, boys, we need to get out of here... I can already feel some strange shit is going down.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_composer_task_stalker_bird_start_dialog_15">
		<text>Just a sec. I'll have a talk with my companion.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_composer_task_bandit_savior_start_dialog_0">
		<text>This is getting more interesting.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_composer_task_bandit_savior_start_dialog_1">
		<text>What's your take, Cluster?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_composer_task_bandit_savior_start_dialog_2">
		<text>What's there to say? We gotta take over the reins. I wish I knew where it would be better. If we contact Turov, who originally ordered the box, then somehow we need to treat him so that Vizir will get away from us, and also get a bit of money for his trouble. If that's the case, then we'll have to send Birdie this... I don't know, send him away. We don't need a leftist, and he's a bit shady, making up stories. I think he shot the survivors of the group.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_composer_task_bandit_savior_start_dialog_3">
		<text>I guess. What do you know about Smyshlov?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_composer_task_bandit_savior_start_dialog_4">
		<text>Man, no clue. We gotta find out what kind of guy he is. I ain't against talking to the professor, but I don't like that Birdie guy one bit! And when Cluster feels something's up, boy, you better believe something's up... You make the call and we'll see what happens.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_composer_task_bandit_savior_start_dialog_5">
		<text>Even if Birdie wasn't to your liking, it's better we have him on our side. That way, he's more likely to help us than hurt us.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_composer_task_bandit_savior_start_dialog_6">
		<text>Yeah, you're right about that.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_composer_task_bandit_savior_start_dialog_7">
		<text>Just a minute.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_composer_task_stalker_bird_second_dialog_0">
		<text>How's it going in there?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_composer_task_stalker_bird_second_dialog_1">
		<text>Birdie, let's talk to the scientist.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_composer_task_stalker_bird_second_dialog_2">
		<text>Yeah, it's about time.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_composer_task_stalker_bird_second_dialog_3">
		<text>Come on, start the radio.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_composer_task_bandit_savior_after_attack_dialog_0">
		<text>Hey, mate, this is a bit of a mess! We have to decide who to give the boxes to. It's a lot of work, but it's no use. No loot, no profit... I don't like neither Turov nor Smyshlov. And our Birdie is a fake, I've got a feeling about him.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_composer_task_bandit_savior_after_attack_dialog_1">
		<text>We can't do it alone! We should at least get to the Garbage, and then decide where to turn - to Turov or to Smyshlov.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_composer_task_bandit_savior_after_attack_dialog_2">
		<text>Then let's go!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_composer_task_bandit_savior_after_attack_dialog_3">
		<text>Cluster, I was wondering why you were nicknamed Cluster.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_composer_task_bandit_savior_after_attack_dialog_4">
		<text>Well, you certainly found the time! Yes, once we were walking with the guys in the Zone, and we ran into a pack of hungry rats, or tushkan they are there, in general, the hell you can not understand. So I started shooting at these rodents! They may be small, but they can do some damage. Anyway, when the wave passed, there was a lot of these rat carcasses. That's how it got attached...</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_composer_task_bandit_savior_after_attack_dialog_5">
		<text>Heh, that makes sense. All right, let's go to the Garbage. When we get to the bend, we'll decide who'll carry the load. Don't tell Birdie yet - let him think we're going through the Garbage to Cordon.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_composer_task_bandit_savior_wait_garbage_dialog_0">
		<text>So, what's our next move?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_composer_task_bandit_savior_wait_garbage_dialog_1">
		<text>I'm already regretting getting involved in this case. What do you think?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_composer_task_bandit_savior_wait_garbage_dialog_2">
		<text>I don't know.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_composer_task_bandit_savior_wait_garbage_dialog_3">
		<text>I'd get out of here as soon as possible. Let's go to the Cordon.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_composer_task_bandit_savior_wait_garbage_dialog_4">
		<text>Yeah, there's nothing else to do here. I don't want to meet Turov and his mutts.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_composer_task_bandit_savior_wait_garbage_dialog_5">
		<text>Then let's move.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_composer_task_scientist_boss_final_dialog_0">
		<text>Well, everyone is back alive and almost healthy. Now for the documents, to Smyshlov's.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_composer_task_scientist_boss_final_dialog_1">
		<text>I don't think he'll give them back willingly!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_composer_task_scientist_boss_final_dialog_2">
		<text>I feel the same way. But it's not my problem, you decide as you wish. But I'd prefer Smyshlov to stay alive! Go get your papers. The main thing is not to lose your way, so that Mr Vizir won't have to remind you of the guidelines and priorities.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_composer_task_scientist_boss_final_dialog_3">
		<text>We will try our best.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_soldier_xottab_need_health_care_0_1">
		<text>'Sup, commander?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_soldier_xottab_need_health_care_0_2">
		<text>Hey.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_soldier_xottab_need_health_care_0_3">
		<text>What's up, commander?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_soldier_xottab_need_health_care_1_1">
		<text>Will you patch me up, man?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_soldier_xottab_need_health_care_1_2">
		<text>Bye.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_soldier_xottab_need_health_care_2">
		<text>On it, commander. You'll feel just like new.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_soldier_xottab_need_health_care_3">
		<text>You kidding me? You're all right, commander.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_soldier_xottab_need_health_care_4">
		<text>[continue...]</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_soldier_xottab_need_health_care_5">
		<text>There you go. Stay safe!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_soldier_xottab_need_health_care_6_1">
		<text>Thank you.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_soldier_xottab_need_health_care_6_2">
		<text>Didn't want it anyway.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_composer_task_scientist_final_dialog_0">
		<text>O-oh...</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_composer_task_scientist_final_dialog_1">
		<text>Smyshlov, are you all right?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_composer_task_scientist_final_dialog_2">
		<text>I'm fine! A little dizzy, but I feel much better. How about you young men?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_composer_task_scientist_final_dialog_3">
		<text>I've had better.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_composer_task_scientist_final_dialog_4">
		<text>Come to your senses. We gotta get out of here.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_composer_task_scientist_final_dialog_5">
		<text>Yes, except your subject seems to be up to something....</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_composer_task_final_bandit_savior_final_dialog_0">
		<text>Science, so much for the engines of progress. Almost got us all killed.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_composer_task_final_bandit_savior_final_dialog_1">
		<text>We have to go after him! Now!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_composer_task_final_bandit_savior_final_dialog_2">
		<text>No, whatever you want, I've worn my body out a lot. I need to rest for a few days first, then figure out a plan of action.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_composer_task_final_bandit_savior_final_dialog_3">
		<text>Then call for backup, get them to come in pursuit!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_composer_task_final_bandit_savior_final_dialog_4">
		<text>What am I gonna tell them? A self-aware box has taken control of a zombie and is a danger to the state? They'll write me off right away, especially after the psi effect. No, Axe, you do what you want, but for now, we're going our separate ways!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_composer_task_final_bandit_savior_final_dialog_5">
		<text>What about...</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_composer_task_final_bandit_savior_final_dialog_6">
		<text>There's no way, just calm down. This operation is not your level, and in one with this box-master I do not recommend it either. And also, I'll put out a rumour that Cluster, a good kid, is lost in the Zone - either in an anomaly, or the controller killed him. So there you go. Maybe we'll see each other again, if the Zone wants us to. The only thing is, it's a pity I was chasing Birdie, he turned out to be a good man.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_composer_task_final_bandit_savior_final_dialog_7">
		<text>And thanks to you and him for covering it up. And maybe the Zone really will want our paths to cross.....</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_composer_task_final_bandit_savior_final_dialog_8">
		<text>So long, stalker. Take care.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_composer_task_final_bandit_savior_final_dialog_9">
		<text>See you later, Kucherenko...</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_stalker_trader_hello_dialog_0">
		<text>Greetings! Are you some kind of salesman?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_stalker_trader_hello_dialog_1">
		<text>Hello, stalker! I'd say you're the supply man around here! What do you want? Or are you just here for a chat?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_stalker_trader_hello_dialog_2">
		<text>I'll still have time to see your merchandise, but for now I'm just looking around, getting to know the locals.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_stalker_trader_hello_dialog_3">
		<text>That's right! Connections in the Exclusion Zone are a very valuable currency. I'm Thrush, I'd like to meet you.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_stalker_trader_hello_dialog_4">
		<text>They call me Axe! Will you tell me who you are and what you're doing here?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_stalker_trader_hello_dialog_5">
		<text>You got it pretty much right. I'm a trader here. And the Agroprom territory is like home to me! A few years ago, we had our own base here, at the factory nearby. It was run by a stalker called Orestes. I was a trader. We traded supplies, artefacts, weapons. I could even delivery my good friends an Exoskeleton! It was a good time on the base, even though times were turbulent. 2011 - factions were fighting, almost for every abandoned place in the Zone! Sometimes it seemed to me that it was not an abnormal Zone at all, but a hot spot of some kind! Tanks and aviation were the only thing missing, by God! A lot of people died back then. I'm surprised I'm still alive. And then, I think you know what happened. It was a hell of a blowout! We pissed off the Zone. You can't just start a war in the Zone like that. It will always fight back!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_stalker_trader_hello_dialog_6">
		<text>What happened to your base after the blowout?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_stalker_trader_hello_dialog_7">
		<text>Things went bad after the big blowout. Orestes disappeared somewhere. They say he saved up some money, spit on the Zone and went to the Big Earth. And without a competent leader, the whole organisation of the base went to the same place. Stalkers scattered. I shut down my business for a while, too. So, from time to time, I sold my remnants to free stalkers, hanging around here and there. I managed to work at the scientists' bunker, at Sidor's fetch-and-deliver, at Devil on the Garbage. In short, I've been all over the place over the years. But it's not my thing, wandering around the Zone. I'm more of a merchant than a stalker. And now, fate smiled on me, I found out that scientists have organised a base on the site of the former research institute, and they are not averse to cooperate with stalkers. So I came here. I trade here now, under good security and in good conditions. I can't complain, especially after all I've been through.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldiers_idle_dialog_0_1">
		<text>Don't distract from the service, rookie.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldiers_idle_dialog_0_2">
		<text>Well, what do you want? We're guarding the base, and here you are with your questions.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldiers_idle_dialog_0_3">
		<text>What do you need?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldiers_idle_dialog_0_4">
		<text>Get out of here, stalker, get out of my way.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldiers_idle_dialog_0_5">
		<text>Well, don't shine it in front of your eyes, go where you're going.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldiers_idle_dialog_1_1">
		<text>Greetings, Zhuravlev!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldiers_idle_dialog_1_2">
		<text>Greetings!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldiers_idle_dialog_1_3">
		<text>Good day!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldiers_idle_dialog_1_4">
		<text>How's it going, soldier?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="agr_scientists_base_soldiers_idle_dialog_1_5">
		<text>Not bad.</text>
	</string>

</string_table>
