<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251"?>
<string_table>
  <string id="st_antirad">
    <text>Anti-radiation drugs</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_antirad_descr">
    <text>The radioprotective drug "Corryzeron-B53", widely distributed in the Zone. When applied, it causes narrowing of peripheral blood vessels and oxygen starvation, which in this case is a means of preventing and treating radiation sickness. Well tolerated by the vast majority of people; in some cases, slight nausea, dizziness, pain, less often vomiting are possible.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_bandage">
    <text>Bandage</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_bandage_descr">
    <text>A normal elastic bandage used to stop bleeding and prevent infection of wounds. For regular bleeding, carefully apply the bandage to the wound. For arterial bleeding, urgently tie the bandage around the affected area.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_binocular_descr">
    <text>Standard issue military binoculars with a maximum of x7.5 magnification. Useful in the Zone in that they allow its owner to observe things from a distance.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_binocular_name">
    <text>Binoculars</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_bread">
    <text>Bread</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_bread_descr">
    <text>No bakers have ever been identified in the Zone, but this bread is neither contaminated nor radioactive, being fresh and quite edible. At least no complaints have been reported thus far.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_conserva">
    <text>"Tourist's Breakfast" can</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_conserva_descr">
    <text>Presumably, these canned goods were looted by stalkers from an army ration depot. Without any kind of label on the can, it's hard to say for sure. Should still be good to eat, if you believe the best before date.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_detector1">
    <text>Echo detector</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_detector1_descr">
    <text>This dated anomalous activity detector produces an alarm signal when anomalous particles enter a special chamber as you approach an anomaly. It can also register the presence of artifacts and measure the distance to the nearest one. The distance is indicated by the frequency of the sound the detector emits. To switch to artifact search mode, open the device's front cover. Due to its simple design, Echo can only be used to locate the most common artifacts.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_detector2">
    <text>Detector "Bear"</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_detector2_descr">
    <text>This last generation anomalous activity detector can be used to locate anomalous formations and has a color diode panel, which not only indicates the direction of artifacts, but also measures the distance to them. To switch to artifact search mode, open the device's front cover. Unfortunately, the device is programmed with a somewhat outdated list of detectable artifacts.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_detector3">
    <text>Veles detector</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_detector3_descr">
    <text>A detector scanner used by scientists.etection scanner. Thanks to three modernized detection chambers, the position of artifacts is shown on a special display screen. When closed, the device registers only radiation and anomalies. To switch to artifact search mode, open the front LED display. When in search mode, the detector is capable of locating all artifacts known to science.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_detector4">
    <text>Svarog detector</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_detector4_descr">
    <text>A new generation detector-scanner used by scientists. A programme has been added to recognise static zones of anomalous activity that exist in the database; at the same time, the possibility of detecting artefacts has been retained. The location of anomalous zones relative to the previous generation Veles detector is displayed on a special screen. The artefact search programme, which is activated by raising the indicator board on the front of the device, has been improved; theoretically, this makes it possible to detect anomalous formations not yet known to science.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_device_torch_descr">
    <text>A standard head-mounted flashlight. Useful for stalkers who find themselves out and about after dark, but may attract trouble if used unwisely.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_device_torch_name">
    <text>Flashlight</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_drug_anabiotic">
    <text>Anabiotics</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_drug_antidot">
    <text>Antidote</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_drug_antidot_descr">
    <text>The drug "Exdemoder Pharm IP2" is a complex of antidotes: metoclopramide, pyridoxine, thiamine, riboxia and others. It introduces into the blood substances capable of decomposing protein poisons, as well as absorbents of synthetic poisons. It is not particularly popular, since most stalkers rely more on a gas mask and overalls. Has a long lasting effect.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_drug_booster">
    <text>Hercules</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_drug_coagulant">
    <text>Vinca</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_drug_coagulant_descr">
    <text>Ukrainian Vikasolum — an artificial equivalent of vitamin K. The main purpose of this drug is to increase blood coagulation speed. In great demand among stalkers who want slow-healing wounds and lacerations inflicted by mutants to close up faster. The effects of the drug are long-lasting.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_drug_psy_blockade">
    <text>Psy-block</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_drug_psy_blockade_descr">
    <text>A drug that blocks avalanche-like nerve impulses. Consumption induces short-term loss of all emotion. Used exclusively in the Zone to counteract the effects of anomalous psy-fields. The effects of the drug are long-lasting.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_drug_radioprotector">
    <text>Radioprotectant</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_energy_drink">
    <text>Energy drink</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_energy_drink_descr">
    <text>Non-alcoholic energy drink from the company "Stalkers of Honest Fate" gives you a boost of energy for another dash for artefacts. It contains caffeine, which stimulates mental activity, increases reaction speed and concentration, with its help you will be able to outwit even the smartest mutant of the Zone.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_guitar_name">
    <text>Guitar</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_guitar_descr">
    <text>A trusty guitar.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_kolbasa">
    <text>Indifferent Boar Servalat</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_kolbasa_descr">
    <text>Often, for want of anything better, this sausage — a mixture of horns and hooves, spices and salt — becomes a stalker's breakfast, lunch and dinner. Due to the large amount of preservatives, it doesn't spoil for quite a long time.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_medkit">
    <text>First-aid kit</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_medkit_army">
    <text>Army medkit</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_medkit_army_descr">
    <text>A specialized medical kit for providing first aid to combat casualties. The kit includes blood coagulants based on menadione, painkillers, antibiotics and immunostimulants, as well as a kit for removing bullets and fragments from the body. This medkit is issued to army personnel as standard and is sometimes used by Duty forces.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_medkit_descr">
    <text>A general purpose single-use medical kit. Handy for treating various injuries — wounds, bruises, regular and chemical burns and various types of poisoning. In demand among stalkers.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_medkit_science">
    <text>Scientific medkit</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_medkit_science_descr">
    <text>A medical kit designed specifically for use in the Zone. The kit contains products for handling wounds, as well as preventing the development of radiation poisoning and reducing accumulated radiation in the body. Contains Vikasolum, Batilolum and Naphazoline, unlike other medkits.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_pda_descr">
    <text>No data stored.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_pda_name">
    <text>PDA</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_vodka">
    <text>Goncharovka Vodka</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_vodka_descr">
    <text>Made by AP-PRO. Goes down easy and considerably lowers the effects of radiation. Should be enjoyed in moderation.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_drug_anabiotic_descr">
    <text>An experimental drug developed for research groups operating in the Zone. The tetradotoxin included in the formula of the drug, known as "zombie powder", causes complete paralysis of the central nervous system; presumably this could ensure survival out of cover during the ejection. The drug has not been tested in the field and has not passed clinical trials, which calls into question its effectiveness and makes you think about possible side effects.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_bolt">
    <text>Bolt</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_drug_booster_descr">
    <text>The main component of this product is an anabolic androgen, an artificial steroid, the chemical composition of which resembles testosterone. Often used by stalkers during long raids to reduce muscle fatigue. Significantly increases weight-carrying capacity. The effects of the drug are long-lasting.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_drug_radioprotector_descr">
    <text>B190 Indraline radioprotectant, included in medkits issued to nuclear power plant personnel. Used in the Zone instead of the excessively toxic PC1 cystamine hydrochloride, repeated use of which often caused death. Reduces the effects of gamma radiation on live tissue. Best consumed before exposure, as effects are not instant. The effects of the drug are long-lasting.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_harmonica_name">
    <text>Harmonica</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_harmonica_descr">
    <text>For blues and prison romance lovers.</text>
  </string>
</string_table>
