<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>
<string_table>
  <!-- AMMUNITIONS DESCRIPTIONS -->
  <string id="ammo-11.43x23-fmj">
    <text>.45 ACP</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-11.43x23-fmj_descr">
    <text>.45 caliber round with a 230gr bullet, a design that has remained popular since its conception in 1906. The sheer mass of each bullet exerts considerable stopping power compared to most other handgun ammunition, despite the relatively low velocity.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-11.43x23-fmj_s">
    <text>.45 ACP</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-11.43x23-hydro">
    <text>.45 ACP HydraShok</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-11.43x23-hydro_descr">
    <text>HydraShok ammunition consists of a jacketed hollow point bullet with a patented center post, which produces reliable performance in penetration and expansion. The resulting combination has all the advantages and shortcomings of both armor piercing and hollow point ammunition types.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-11.43x23-hydro_s">
    <text>.45 Hydra</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-12x70-buck">
    <text>12x70mm 00-buck</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-12x70-buck_descr">
    <text>Standard 12-gauge shell filled with 8.4mm lead shot. Immense stopping power at close ranges. Only for smoothbore shotguns.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-12x70-buck_s">
    <text>12x70 buck</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-12x76-zhekan">
    <text>12x76mm slug</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-12x76-zhekan_descr">
    <text>12-gauge shotgun shell that exchanges lead shot for a single solid bullet, made popular within the Zone after stalkers found it worked incredibly well against the thick hide of its mutants. The effect it has against armor is also unconventional, as it won't quite penetrate Level IIIA body armor but transfers enough concussive force behind it to significantly cripple if not mortally wound the wearer entirely.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-12x76-zhekan_s">
    <text>12x76 slug</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-12x76-dart">
    <text>12x76mm dart</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-12x76-dart_descr">
    <text>12-gauge shotgun shell. The plumage stabilizes the bullet, which increases the accuracy of battle. The massive steel body of the bullet is capable of penetrating any body armor. Compatible with the TOZ-34 and BM-16 double-barrel shotguns, as well as the SPAS-12 and Winchester 1300.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-12x76-dart_s">
    <text>12x76 dart</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-5.45x39-fmj">
    <text>5.45x39mm 7N6</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-5.45x39-fmj_descr">
    <text>Introduced in 1974, the 5.45x39mm largely became the primary military service rifle cartridge used within the Warsaw Pact and saw multiple improvements ever since. The lighter weight allowed soldiers to carry more compared to its 7.62x39mm predecessor and also yielded less recoil, resulting in better accuracy during automatic fire. The round has a tendency to yaw on impact and create severe wound cavities on soft targets, leading to its nickname of the "poison bullet".</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-5.45x39-fmj_s">
    <text>5.45x39 7N6</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-5.45x39-ap">
    <text>5.45x39mm 7N22</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-5.45x39-ap_descr">
    <text>Armor-piercing variant of the original 5.45x39mm cartridge used by many Warsaw Pact assault rifles. The sharp-pointed penetrator made from hardened steel makes it effective against most body armor.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-5.45x39-ap_s">
    <text>5.45x39 7N22</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-5.56x45-ss190">
    <text>5.56x45mm SS109</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-5.56x45-ss190_descr">
    <text>Standardized in 1980 as the NATO SS109 (US M855) with the intention of penetrating steel helmets at long range. At lower velocities it will yaw to create large cavitation wounds, but at higher velocities it can fragment into smaller pieces, inflicting severe shrapnel injuries. Widely used in small arms throughout NATO territory.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-5.56x45-ss190_s">
    <text>5.56x45 SS109</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-5.56x45-ap">
    <text>5.56x45mm M995</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-5.56x45-ap_descr">
    <text>Armor-piercing variant of the NATO standard SS109 cartridge, with a tungsten core and ability to pierce up to 12mm of RHA steel. Highly effective against body armor and made popular by the warring factions within the Zone to counter the growing popularity of exoskeletons.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-5.56x45-ap_s">
    <text>5.56x45 M995</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-7.62x54-7h1">
    <text>7.62x54mmR 7N1</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-7.62x54-7h1_descr">
    <text>A 7.62x54mmR 7N1 cartridge designed for improved accuracy in combination with Soviet-made sniper rifles, like the SVD or SVU.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-7.62x54-7h1_s">
    <text>7.62x54 7N1</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-7.62x54-7h14">
    <text>7.62x54 7N14</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-7.62x54-7h14_descr">
    <text>An armor-piercing variant developed specifically for the SVD, with improved ballistics and penetrating power over the standard 7.62x54mmR. Consists of a steel core, jacketed boat-tail bullet, hardened steel-tip penetrator, and extruded match-grade powder. Extremely effective against all body armor.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-7.62x54-7h14_s">
    <text>7.62x54 7N14</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-7.62x54-ap">
    <text>7.62x54mmR 7N13</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-7.62x54-ap_descr">
    <text>A variation of the 7.62x54mmR round, developed in 1943 and eventually given the GRAU index designation 7N13 years later after its introduction. This specific round has superior armor-piercing performance, and it's meant for use by the SVD and SVU.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-7.62x54-ap_s">
    <text>7.62x54 7N13</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-pkm_100">
    <text>7.62x54mmR PP</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-pkm_100_descr">
    <text>Inexpensive standard 7.62x54mmR cartridges. Due to the lower ballistic requirements during manufacturing, these are generally unsuitable for precision work and are instead meant for sustained automatic fire.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-pkm_100_s">
    <text>7.62x54 PP</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-9x18-fmj">
    <text>9x18mm PM</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-9x18-fmj_descr">
    <text>A lead core and mushroom-shaped steel insert are hidden beneath the round-nose jacket. Has some good stopping power, but ineffective against body armor.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-9x18-fmj_s">
    <text>9x18 PBM</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-9x18-pmm">
    <text>9x18mm PMM</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-9x18-pmm_descr">
    <text>A high-impulse cartridge designed specifically for the PMM pistol. Compared to the conventional 9x18mm PM, its velocity is noticeably faster thanks to a lighter bullet and increased powder charge. However, the higher pressures cause accelerated wear on weapons not designed for it. Ineffective against body armor.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-9x18-pmm_s">
    <text>9x18 PMM</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-9x18-pbp">
    <text>9x18mm PBP</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-9x18-pbp_descr">
    <text>A cartridge with a jacketed soft point bullet designed to inflict as much wounding damage as possible, while allowing for a limited armor piercing effect. Compatible with the PM, PB, and Fort-12 pistols.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-9x18-pbp_s">
    <text>9x18 PBP</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-9x19-fmj">
    <text>9x19mm Luger</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-9x19-fmj_descr">
    <text>The most iconic and widespread pistol cartridge in the world since 1902, a balanced trade-off between stopping power and size. Standard jacketed bullet with a lead core. Good ballistic properties yet inexpensive to produce, making it a popular choice for anyone in the Zone. Ineffective against body armor.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-9x19-fmj_s">
    <text>9x19 Luger</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-9x19-pbp">
    <text>9x19mm JHP</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-9x19-pbp_descr">
    <text>Jacketed hollow-point variant of the 9x19mm cartridge that expands on impact to inflict severe soft-body trauma, with the added benefit of being faster and more accurate than its FMJ counterpart. Most commonly used by police and civilians for self-defense as its design also limits any over-penetration or ricochets that could cause collateral damage. Ineffective against body armor.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-9x19-pbp_s">
    <text>9x19 JHP</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-9x39-pab9">
    <text>9x39mm PAB-9</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-9x39-pab9_descr">
    <text>A 9x39mm armor-piercing round that's been given the GRAU index designation PAB-9. It's a cheap modification of the SP-6 armor-piercing round with a hardened steel core, being introduced after the more expensive SP-6 round came out. Due to the rushed development of the round, using it with firearms chambered for 9x39mm can potentially ruin their internals, requiring them to be serviced.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-9x39-pab9_s">
    <text>9x39 PAB-9</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-9x39-sp5">
    <text>9x39mm SP-5</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-9x39-sp5_descr">
    <text>Subsonic ammunition upon which the AS Val and VSS Vintorez were designed. The bimetallic jacket contains a two-part core, the front half being a mild-steel penetrator and the cavity behind it filled with lead. Noise suppression only possible when used with a silencer.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-9x39-sp5_s">
    <text>9x39 SP-5</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-9x39-ap">
    <text>9x39mm SP-6</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-9x39-ap_descr">
    <text>Subsonic armor-piercing ammunition designed with the AS Val and VSS Vintorez in mind. A hardened steel core protrudes beyond the bimetallic jacket and works as a penetrator on impact, however the mixed copper and steel composition accelerates wear on the barrel. Noise suppression only possible when used with a silencer. Highly effective against body armor.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-9x39-ap_s">
    <text>9x39 SP-6</text>
  </string>
  <!-- EXPLOSIVES DESCRIPTIONS -->
  <string id="ammo-og-7b">
    <text>PG-7VL HEAT</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-og-7b_descr">
    <text>RPG-7 launcher ammunition containing a high-explosive warhead originally meant for tanks, however its proliferation worldwide resulted in many entering the Zone. Stalkers found the anti-tank properties of a direct hit proved extremely effective against even the thickest of mutant hides. Despite the rocket's range and incredible damage output, its inherent inaccuracy limits most reliable shots to 200m or less.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-og-7b_s">
    <text>PG-7VL</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-m209">
    <text>M433 HEDP grenade</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-m209_descr">
    <text>40mm high-explosive grenade suitable for most underbarrel launchers in service with NATO. Effective blast radius of 5m.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-m209_s">
    <text>M433 HEDP</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-vog-25">
    <text>VOG-25 grenade</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-vog-25_descr">
    <text>Soviet fragmentation grenade primarily used in conjunction with the GP-25 Kostyor underbarrel grenade launcher. Effective blast radius of 6m.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-vog-25_s">
    <text>VOG-25</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-vog-25p">
    <text>VOG-25P grenade</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-vog-25p_descr">
    <text>Airburst variation of the VOG-25, with a small charge in the nose that detonates on impact and lifts the grenade a meter in the air before exploding. Highly effective against targets in cover.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-vog-25p_s">
    <text>VOG-25P</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_grenade_f1">
    <text>F1 grenade</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_grenade_f1_descr">
    <text>An F1 grenade. These specific types of grenades are nicknamed 'little lemon' due to the unique shape they have. Make sure you have a good throwing arm if you intend to use it. The scores in the grenade's body make it more effective against soft targets. Fragmentation radius - 7 meters.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_grenade_rgd5">
    <text>RGD-5 grenade</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_grenade_rgd5_descr">
    <text>The RGD-5 is one of the more common hand grenades used by armies from post-Soviet states. Stalkers often use these to blow mutant lairs. Fragmentation radius - 5 meters.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_grenade_smoke">
    <text>Smoke grenade</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_grenade_smoke_descr">
    <text>A smoke grenade. This grenade is meant to create a smoke screen for visual cover, hiding anyone who uses it for a short amount of time. It lasts for about ten seconds.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="explosive_dinamit_name">
    <text>Dynamite</text>
  </string>
  <string id="explosive_dinamit_descr">
    <text>A box of dynamite, intended for demolition purposes. Keep away from heat and corrosive substances.</text>
  </string>
  <!-- ADDONS DESCRIPTIONS -->
  <string id="st_grenade_launcher">
    <text>GP-25 Kostyor</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_grenade_launcher_descr">
    <text>Single-shot underbarrel grenade launcher for the AK family of assault rifles, produced in the USSR. The trigger mechanism is self-cocking, with a manual safety and spring catch that prevents the round from falling out under excessive movement or inversion. Accepts either VOG-25 or VOG-25P grenades.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_grenade_launcher_m203">
    <text>M203A1 SOPMOD</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_grenade_launcher_m203_descr">
    <text>The SOPMOD variant of the M203A1 grenade launcher shortens the launch tube by 3" and mounts to any standard Picatinny rail. Its versatility in combat and ease of adaptation for various weapon systems led to its use in many parts of the world. Accepts either M433 or M397A1 grenades.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_addon_scope">
    <text>PSO-1 5x sniper scope</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_addon_scope_descr">
    <text>Fixed 5x magnification optical sight with a reticle marked for long-range sniper fire. Attaches to the standard dovetail mount on Warsaw Pact weapons. Standard equipment on the SVD.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_addon_scope_detector">
    <text>PSO-1 5x "Thermal" sniper scope</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_addon_scope_detector_descr">
    <text>Fixed 5x magnification optical sight with a reticle marked for long-range sniper fire. Detects living beings via thermal signature. Attaches to the standard dovetail mount on Warsaw Pact weapons.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_addon_scope_night_vision">
    <text>PSO-1 5x "Night vision"</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_addon_scope_night_vision_descr">
    <text>Fixed 5x magnification optical sight with a built-in night vision device to help the shooter see in the dark. Attaches to the standard dovetail mount on Warsaw Pact weapons.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_addon_scope_susat">
    <text>SUSAT 4x assault sight</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_addon_scope_susat_custom">
    <text>SUSAT 4x "Variable magnification"</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_addon_scope_susat_custom_descr">
    <text>4x variable magnification optical sight, developed in the UK. Typically used in mid to long-range engagements. Mounts to a special dovetail rail on the L85.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_addon_scope_susat_descr">
    <text>4x optical sight, developed in the UK. Typically used in mid to long-range engagements. Mounts to a special dovetail rail on the L85.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_addon_scope_susat_dusk">
    <text>SUSAT 1.6x "Dusk" assault sight</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_addon_scope_susat_dusk_descr">
    <text>1.6x optical sight, developed in the UK. Used in short to mid-range engagements during bad visibility. Mounts to a special dovetail rail on the L85.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_addon_scope_susat_night_vision">
    <text>SUSAT 4x "Night vision"</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_addon_scope_susat_night_vision_descr">
    <text>4x optical sight with built-in night vision, developed in the UK. Typically used in mid to long-range engagements. Mounts to a special dovetail rail on the L85..</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_addon_scope_susat_x1.6">
    <text>SUSAT 1.6x assault sight</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_addon_scope_susat_x1.6_descr">
    <text>1.6x optical sight, developed in the UK. Typically used in short to mid-range engagements. Mounts to a special dovetail rail on the L85.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_addon_scope_x2.7">
    <text>PSO-1 2.7x sniper scope</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_addon_scope_x2.7_descr">
    <text>Optical sight with 2.7x magnification, suitable for engagements out to the far end of mid-range. Can attach to any Warsaw Pact weapon with a dovetail mount.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_addon_silencer">
    <text>Universal suppressor</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_addon_silencer_descr">
    <text>A universal suppressor with a kit for adapting to different calibers. Effective for when you want to stay stealthy.</text>
  </string>
  <!-- WEAPONS DESCRIPTIONS -->
  <string id="st_wpn_knife">
    <text>Knife</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_pm">
    <text>PM</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_pm_descr">
    <text>A legacy of the Soviet era, the Makarov PM is one of the best representatives of compact self defense weapons. Its size, reliability, and ease-of-use offset its relatively low firepower and accuracy. Compared to other more modern equivalents, it's much heavier and has a smaller magazine capacity as well.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_pb">
    <text>PB</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_pb_descr">
    <text>The PB silenced pistol, based on the Makarov, was developed in the 1960s for use by forward reconnaissance groups and KGB personnel. The pistol's distinguishing feature is its two-part integral suppressor, half of which can be detached for concealed carry and quickly reinstalled later if needed. It's possible to fire the weapon without it, however the silenced effect is almost entirely lost.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_fort">
    <text>Fort-14</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_fort_descr">
    <text>A Ukrainian-made pistol issued alongside the Makarov PM to various law enforcement, government, and security agencies. Despite surpassing the PM in almost every respect, many that enter the Zone are retired service weapons or factory rejects and suffer from any number of issues. Technicians regularly salvage components from these broken examples, which means replacement parts are cheap and easy to find. The good ones are in high demand among stalkers and yet, ironically, almost never have all of the same original parts that they left the factory with.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_hpsa">
    <text>Browning Hi-Power</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_hpsa_descr">
    <text>Semi-automatic pistol based on a design by inventor John Browning and brought to completion in 1934 by Dieudonne Saive for the French military. Ultimately, the commissioners decided to adopt a competing sidearm for their standard issue, however it was later produced by FN of Belgium during World wWar II when Nazis took control of their facilities. When it became clear the plant would fall into German hands, the plans were sent to Canada to be produced for the Allies, after which it proved popular with British airborne and commando groups as well as the OSS. Production continues to this day, making it one of the most iconic and numerous pistols ever made.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_beretta">
    <text>Beretta 92FS</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_beretta_descr">
    <text>Known around the globe as a reliable, accurate, and somewhat bulky weapon, the Italian-made Beretta 92FS continues to see service with military and police forces worldwide. They've become equally popular with criminals for many of the same reasons. As a general rule, it's not the newest or best-maintained models that make it to the Zone, yet their prevalence means most technicians have spare parts on hand.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_walther">
    <text>Walther P99</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_walther_descr">
    <text>A high-capacity sidearm from Germany with a reputation for incredible dependability, accuracy, and ergonomics. Many of these enter the Zone by way of well-funded mercenary groups, who inexplicably find themselves needing to trade them for emergency provisions. Highly popular, though expensive and can be costly to maintain.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_sig220">
    <text>SIG P220</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_sig220_descr">
    <text>Due to its excellent ergonomics and accuracy, the P220 has remained popular with special forces units all over the world since its introduction in 1975, when it replaced the aging P210. The powerful cartridge and dependability of a Swiss watch compensate for the small magazine capacity. An item in high demand among mercenaries and veteran stalkers alike.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_colt1911">
    <text>Colt 1911</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_colt1911_descr">
    <text>A refined version of the classic semi-automatic pistol that served honorably in all twentieth-century armed conflicts. Both the original and modified versions continue to be produced by dozens if not hundreds of manufacturers. The only notable drawback is its magazine capacity, which is compensated somewhat by the powerful cartridge.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_usp">
    <text>USP</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_usp_descr">
    <text>This pistol exhibits all the classic traits of precision German engineering, such as excellent accuracy, reliability, and durability. Despite the large size, high center of gravity, and massive slide, it's a very popular choice among veteran stalkers in the Zone. The tactical variant has a threaded barrel for mounting a suppressor.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_desert_eagle">
    <text>Desert Eagle Mark XIX</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_desert_eagle_descr">
    <text>The very definition of "hand cannon" - large, heavy, and extremely lethal. Very few semi-automatic pistols capable of firing magnum cartridges existed before its time, and certainly none that saw as many appearances in pop culture. Despite its fame and incredible stopping power, the overall price, weight, bulk, and expensive ammunition made it unpopular in the Zone.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_bm16">
    <text>TOZ-66</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_bm16_descr">
    <text>Standard side-by-side double-barrel shotgun, often carried by farmers and hunters, but now more regularly seen in the hands of bandits and rookie stalkers. Simple, cheap, and extremely effective at close range.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_toz34">
    <text>TOZ-34</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_toz34_descr">
    <text>Over-under hunting shotgun widely prevalent on the outskirts of the Zone, and at one point the most common of its type within the former Soviet Union. The inherent accuracy and stopping power performed admirably in the fight against both mutants and poorly-armored opponents. It's also cheap to maintain and easily affordable, making it one of the most popular weapons among bandits and rookie stalkers.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_wincheaster1300">
    <text>Winchester 1300</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_wincheaster1300_descr">
    <text>A Western smoothbore shotgun, popular all over world for its incredible dependability and ease of reloading. Hunters in the Zone have taken a particular liking to it for all the same reasons. All components appear to have received a corrosion-resistant treatment.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_spas12">
    <text>Franchi SPAS-12</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_spas12_descr">
    <text>Designed from the ground up in 1979 as a rugged military shotgun, the dual-mode SPAS-12 can be used as either a traditional pump-action shotgun or semi-automatic. Popular with both police and assault units for its versatility and sheer firepower. On top of its countless appearances in movies and television for decades, it's now in high demand within the Zone for its efficiency in taking down mutants, despite the relatively high weight and price.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_protecta">
    <text>Armsel protecta</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_protecta_descr">
    <text>A South African 12-gauge combat shotgun with revolving cylinder and high rate of fire, capable of generating an extreme amount of firepower for the riot police it was originally distributed to. The advantages are diminished slightly by its bulk and considerable weight, as well as the lengthy time to reload, yet it remains a fearsome sight to behold in the Zone.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_ak74u">
    <text>AKS-74U</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_ak74u_descr">
    <text>A shortened version of the AK-74 that bridged the gap between submachine gun and assault rifle. Primarily designed for paratroopers and combat vehicle crews, its small size also found favor among various internal security agencies during the late 1970s. Easily concealed and highly mobile, yet range and stopping power are limited by the shortened barrel, which reduces muzzle velocity and associated stopping power.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_ak74">
    <text>AKS-74</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_ak74_descr">
    <text>A later development of the AK series of assault rifles. The AK-74's development was inspired by the emergence of the M16 in Vietnam; it proved that a small bullet that tumbles upon impact instead of a large one forcing its way through was a better choice for modern warfare. The 5.45x39mm round it fires is a nasty little bullet, which clearly takes some inspiration from the 5.56x45mm round. As mentioned, it will tumble when it hits you, causing much more tissue damage, whereas the early intermediate cartridge the AK-47/AKM fires will simply just go straight through.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_ak74_nimble">
    <text>Modified AK-74</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_ak74_nimble_descr">
    <text>A modified variant of the AK-74 assault rifle. It is better in durability and has a larger magazine, and inflicts more damage than the standard AK-74. And while the fire rate has been cut down slighty and the rifle weighs more, it was done in an attempt to lower recoil felt by the shooter.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_abakan">
    <text>AN-94 "Abakan"</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_abakan_descr">
    <text>A modern assault rifle designed to replace the aging AK-74, but ultimately only saw limited use in the field due to its complex design and expense. One of its unique features is a 2-round burst mode, which fires a second round before the recoil of the first is felt, resulting in both shots landing almost on top of each other. This has the effect of increasing overall firepower along with a better probability of hitting the intended target.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_groza">
    <text>OTs-14 "Groza"</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_groza_descr">
    <text>A Russian selective-fire assault rifle developed on the basis of the AKS-74U for special operations. The bullpup layout and ammunition used makes it a compact yet effective weapon capable of reliably engaging both armored and non-armored targets. The modular design provides for a wide range of available loadouts and attachments for any scenario, including an underbarrel grenade launcher, suppressor, or an optic.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_mp5">
    <text>HK MP5</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_mp5_descr">
    <text>This iconic submachine gun is deservedly popular for its reliability, accuracy, and ease of handling. It's seen adoption by military and police units around the world, but also appears regularly on the black market and eventually made its way into the Zone. The 9x19mm ammunition it fires is cheap and never in short supply, making it a common sight among novice stalkers.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_l85">
    <text>Enfield L85A1</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_l85_descr">
    <text>British-made bullpup assault rifle with high single-shot precision and many potential upgrade paths. Firing in bursts has a negative impact on overall accuracy, while fully-automatic rate of fire is reduced slightly by the internal cycling mechanisms. Probably ended up in the Zone through the black market.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_lr300">
    <text>Z-M LR-300</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_lr300_descr">
    <text>A retooled version of the famous AR-15 done by American manufacturer Z-M Weapons. The gas impingement system has been entirely overhauled and recoil buffer tube replaced by a forward mounted return spring instead. This reduced recoil and weight, kept the bolt area much cleaner, and allowed for a folding stock not normally offered on standard AR-15 clones. Accuracy was improved overall as a result, however the weapon remains highly sensitive to contamination and requires constant upkeep to remain functional in the Zone's harsh conditions.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_sig550">
    <text>SIG SG-550</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_sig550_descr">
    <text>Swiss-made assault rifle designed in the 1980s as a response to the Swiss army's requirements for a successor to their SG 510. Highly reliable, extremely accurate, and easy to handle. A rare sight in the Zone as these are relatively expensive. Most have been brought in by well-funded mercenary groups or special ordered by experienced stalkers.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_g36">
    <text>HK G36</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_g36_descr">
    <text>A modern, selective-fire assault rifle accepted into service with the German Bundeswehr in 1997. It uses a short-stroke gas piston system firing from a closed rotary bolt, which creates a cycle that's both accurate and light on recoil. Standard military issue models include an integrated ZF 3x4 dual-optical sight that combines a 3x telescopic sight with an unmagnified reflex sight. The polymer frame helps to keep the overall weight down, and various attachments can easily be added, making this a highly ergonomic and versatile weapon.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_fn2000">
    <text>FN F2000</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_fn2000_descr">
    <text>This futuristic-looking weapon is a modularly-designed bullpup rifle that integrates extremely efficient ergonomics with certain unique features, such as ejecting spent casings out the forend of the frame. It includes a built-in 1.6x magnification low-light scope housing along with a standard backup iron sight. A proprietary grenade launcher can be coupled with an advanced rangefinder and aiming module to calculate a firing solution for several types of 40mm grenades. Despite its bulkiness, the weapon is a rare, competent blend of high-tech engineering.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_val">
    <text>AS Val</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_val_descr">
    <text>This Cold War-era rifle shares most of its parts with the VSS Vintorez and was originally developed for Spetsnaz operations in urban and reconnaissance settings. The folding stock, automatic firing mode, and relatively light weight made it especially favorable for paratroopers. An integrated silencer allows the shooter to remain concealed, while the subsonic 9x39mm cartridges it uses will effectively pierce most standard body armor.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_vintorez">
    <text>VSS Vintorez</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_vintorez_descr">
    <text>Soviet marksman rifle developed in 1987 for clandestine operations, where concealing the shooter's position is accomplished by the integral suppressor and flash hider. The available 9x39mm subsonic ammunition is both accurate and effective even against soft targets wearing GOST-rated Class 3 body armor. Despite the small magazine capacity, these rifles are highly sought after by stalkers. Unfortunately, the suppressor induces a natural loss in muzzle velocity, causing a steep drop in bullet trajectory that deviates sharply from long range optics' reticle markings.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_svu">
    <text>SVU</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_svu_descr">
    <text>A modernized version of the SVD sniper rifle in the form of a compact bullpup designed for rapid response forces. It allows for a faster rate of fire and is significantly lighter than its predecessor, while retaining mid-range accuracy comparable to the original it's based on. These characteristics have earned it the admiration of both present-day military and stalkers alike.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_svd">
    <text>SVD</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_svd_descr">
    <text>An iconic sniper rifle that's been on the arms market for over half a century and seen use in nearly as many conflicts. During this time it's managed to prove itself as an extremely reliable and easy to handle weapon. The intentions were for it to engage with targets beyond the range of standard machine guns, but stalkers have come to appreciate it for its ability to penetrate even the thickest mutant skins and armored vests.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_pkm">
    <text>PKM</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_pkm_descr">
    <text>This belt-fed machine gun is a portable modification of the original PK that's both lighter and easier to operate. Despite its complex two-stage feeding system and low precision, it's still developed a niche group of followers in the Zone, most notably among skirmishing faction members or stalkers tasked with clearing out mutant lairs.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_rg6">
    <text>RG6</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_rg6_descr">
    <text>This revolver-type grenade launcher holds six caseless 40mm grenades in rifled front-loaded chambers, identical to the GP-25, that then get launched down a smoothbore barrel. Widely used for rapid suppression of enemy firing positions or creating an opening for follow-up attackers to exploit. Stalkers have found it particularly effective against even the most dangerous mutants of the Zone.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_rpg7">
    <text>RPG-7V</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_rpg7_descr">
    <text>This infamous single-shot rocket launcher made its way into the Zone after stalkers started raiding the surrounding army depots for supplies. The weapon is a smoothbore recoilless launch system with an open-rear tube, capable of launching some of the most destructive ordnance available. Its heavy frame and almost equally as heavy ammunition make it an unlikely pick among stalkers, as most would tend to avoid the types of situations it's intended for entirely, however a small cult following has still developed around its destructive power for those rare cases.</text>
  </string>
  <!-- EXCLUSIVE WEAPONS DESCRIPTIONS -->
  <string id="st_wpn_pm_actor">
    <text>Honorary PM</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_pm_actor_descr">
    <text>Major Degtyarev's honorary PM, which he received for "successful execution of highly dangerous state orders, as well as valor and courage shown in the line of duty".</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_sig220_nimble">
    <text>SIG P220 "Alpine"</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_sig220_nimble_descr">
    <text>Tactical modification of the well-known P220, with increased magazine capacity, two-tone frame, and short Picatinny rail for mounting flashlights and lasers. Technicians with the right tools can also thread the end of the barrel for attaching a suppressor. An extremely rare sight in the Zone.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_usp_nimble">
    <text>USP Match</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_usp_nimble_descr">
    <text>Competition variant of the HK USP, with an added barrel compensator to reduce muzzle flip at the cost of overall weight. Production of the USP Match was discontinued in 1999 and examples rarely cross the boundaries of the Zone. This particular one is rumored to have been owned by the ruthless mercenary Wolfhound and many of its internals have been precisely tuned, making this a truly one-of-a-kind weapon.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_desert_eagle_nimble">
    <text>"Steppe" Eagle</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_desert_eagle_nimble_descr">
    <text>An enthusiast-owned Desert Eagle tailored for target shooting, with a brushed chrome finish and wooden grip panels. The result feels well-balanced and comfortable on top of its match-grade accuracy.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_wincheaster1300_trapper">
    <text>Anomalous Winchester 1300</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_wincheaster1300_trapper_descr">
    <text>A Western smoothbore shotgun, popular all over the world for its incredible dependability and ease of reloading. All components appear to have received a corrosion-resistant treatment. This particular weapon spent half a year inside an anomalous zone at the CNPP.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_spas12_m2">
    <text>Rifled SPAS-12</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_spas12_m2_descr">
    <text>A SPAS-12 variant produced by Duty technicians, made specifically for hunting large game in the Zone. This particular firearm had its fire rate increased, and a longer magazine tube installed that holds 10 standard 12-gauge shells.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_spas12_nimble">
    <text>SPAS-12 "Carabiner"</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_spas12_nimble_descr">
    <text>One of a small number of customized SPAS-12 shotguns issued to an elite Carabinieri unit in the early 1990s, which was frequently involved in high-stakes CQC with the Mafia. The basic mechanisms and functions are the same, however many components have been upgraded to significantly dampen the recoil felt with each shot.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_groza_nimble">
    <text>OTs-14 "Storm"</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_groza_nimble_descr">
    <text>A re-chambered version of the OTs-14 bullpup assault rifle, capable of using the much more common and widespread 5.45x39mm ammunition. What few surviving examples exist in the Zone are highly coveted for this reason and rarely ever pass through the trading posts. Overall ballistic characteristics are slightly improved at the expense of stopping power from the weaker cartridge. Compatible with higher capacity magazines from the Kalashnikov line of assault rifles.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_mp5_nimble">
    <text>HK MP5</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_mp5_nimble_descr">
    <text>This iconic submachine gun is deservedly popular for its reliability, accuracy, and ease of handling. It's seen adoption by military and police units around the world, but also appears regularly on the black market and eventually made its way into the Zone. The 9x19mm ammunition it fires is cheap and never in short supply, making it a common sight among novice stalkers.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_sig550_strelok">
    <text>Strelok's SIG-550</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_sig550_strelok_descr">
    <text>Although the rifle wasn't exactly made yesterday, it's clearly been meticulously maintained by its former owner. The weapon has been completely overhauled, and all of its parts have been carefully fitted together, the result being far more efficient than its original design. The buttstock is neatly carved with the letter "S" and 16 small crosses.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_vintorez_nimble">
    <text>VSSM Vintorez "Tide"</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_vintorez_nimble_descr">
    <text>A modified version of the original, distributed to military recon units for culling the zombie herds as they grew within the Zone. Several components have been replaced to increase the overall stopping power at the expense of its rate of fire.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_svu_nimble">
    <text>SVU-A "Kiddy"</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_svu_nimble_descr">
    <text>The former weapon of choice for Max, the legendary guardian of Freedom. Installed with options for single-shot or fully-automatic firing modes. It can also be modified further to accept larger standard magazines.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_svd_nimble">
    <text>SVD Dragunov "Long ranger"</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_svd_nimble_descr">
    <text>A hand-assembled version of the SVD Dragunov, the components and mechanisms of which have all been refined and carefully overhauled. This resulted in an outstanding example of both firepower and accuracy in a single long-range package while still retaining all the original appearances.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_pkm_zulus">
    <text>Zulu's PKM</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_pkm_zulus_descr">
    <text>A modified PKM previously owned by Zulu. Its special features include a larger ammo box and a particularly reliable return mechanism. The results meant an increase in the overall weight, but that wasn't a problem for its former owner.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_umirotvoritel">
    <text>Unidentified weapon</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_umirotvoritel_descr">
    <text>An unidentified weapon, the firing mechanisms of which have not yet been established. Regardless, the weapon is clearly inoperable, as pulling the trigger has no effect.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_gauss">
    <text>Gauss rifle</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_gauss_descr">
    <text>Advanced precision railgun developed within secret research labs throughout the Zone and classified as Item 62. The fired projectile is accelerated by a series of electromagnets to hypersonic speeds, providing incredible stopping power and completely negating all forms of body armor. The recoil felt is ironically fairly minimal and compares to that of a 7.62x54mm sniper rifle. Comes fitted with electronic sights that can be upgraded further for convenient long-range fire.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-gauss">
    <text>Gauss battery</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-gauss_descr">
    <text>Energy elements for a Gauss rifle, manufactured at the factory using high-tech equipment. Encapsulating shards of a Flash artifact within its housing allowed researchers to overcome the massive power requirements of the weapon itself.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-gauss_cardan">
    <text>Gauss Battery - Handmade</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-gauss_cardan_descr">
    <text>Batteries for the Gauss rifle powered by fragments of a Flash artifact. Handmade by Cardan, one of the former engineers on the project, but under less than ideal conditions and with comparatively inferior equipment. The result is a functional replacement for the originals at a cost of capacity and peak output current, which negatively affects projectile speed and accuracy.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_ak74u_fanat">
    <text>AKS-74UM</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_ak74u_fanat_descr">
    <text>A modernized variant of the AKS-74U, fitted with a 45-rounder magazine and a dovetail mount.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_saiga">
    <text>Saiga-12K</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_saiga_descr">
    <text>Fully-automatic 12-gauge shotgun with a pistol grip and folding plastic buttstock. The design was based on the Kalashnikov series of assault rifles, which makes it extremely reliable and mechanically simple. An excellent all-around choice for any game in the Zone up to mid-range. A basic dovetail mount on the receiver cover allows various types of sights and optics to be attached.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_saiga12_nimble">
    <text>Saiga-12M "Hunter"</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_saiga12_nimble_descr">
    <text>An upgraded variant of the Saiga-12K semi-automatic shotgun. Due to aftermarket parts, it has an increased fire rate, increased wounding damage, and is more accurate at longer ranges.</text>
  </string>
</string_table>
