п»ї<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<string_table>

	<string id="csky_heavy_outfit_name">
		<text>CS-3a body armor</text>
	</string>

	<string id="dolg_heavy_outfit_name">
		<text>PSZ-9d Duty Armor</text>
	</string>

	<string id="dolg_outfit_name">
		<text>PS5-M Universal Protection</text>
	</string>

	<string id="dolg_outfit_nimble_name">
		<text>PSZ-9d Hunter</text>
	</string>

	<string id="exo_outfit_name">
		<text>Exoskeleton</text>
	</string>

	<string id="military_outfit_name">
		<text>Bulat armored suit</text>
	</string>

	<string id="mp_exo_outfit_description">
		<text>This exoskeleton provides outstanding protection against bullet and fragmentation damage at the cost of mobility. Vulnerable to armor-piercing rounds.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="mp_exo_outfit_name">
		<text>Exoskeleton</text>
	</string>

	<string id="mp_military_outfit_description">
		<text>A military armored suit made for assault operations. Provides outstanding protection against full metal jacket rounds and fragmentation damage without reducing the wearer's mobility. Vulnerable to armor-piercing rounds.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="mp_military_outfit_name">
		<text>Military armored suit</text>
	</string>

	<string id="novice_outfit_description">
		<text>Common garb of a novice stalker. It won't save you from bullets or anomalies, but it's still better than nothing.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="novice_outfit_name">
		<text>Leather jacket</text>
	</string>

	<string id="scientific_outfit_name">
		<text>SEVA bodysuit</text>
	</string>

	<string id="specops_outfit_name">
		<text>Berill-5M armored suit</text>
	</string>

	<string id="specops_outfit_nimble_name">
		<text>Berill-5M1 armored suit</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_helm_battle">
		<text>Sphere M12 helmet</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_helm_battle_descr">
		<text>An aluminum/titanium helmet with a cloth exterior that comes with pockets for additional steel armor pieces and an armor face mask. Sphere M12 is normally used as part of a combination that includes PSZ series Spetsnaz body armor. Quite popular in the Zone thanks to its respirator and built-in first generation night vision device, as well as providing the maximum head protection possible. Comes with electronics slots.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_helm_hardhat">
		<text>Steel helmet</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_helm_hardhat_descr">
		<text>A desperately outdated steel army helmet without any additions. Provides no protection against anomalies or radiation, but can deflect bullets. This helmet was never particularly popular in the Zone, except for use in brief armed conflicts between factions.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_helm_protective">
		<text>Screen helmet</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_helm_protective_descr">
		<text>A light helmet with an airtight visor intended for protection from anomalies. Judging by the design, the helmet is made by the same Defense Research Institutes as the SEVA bodysuit. Its intended use may very well be in combination with military suits for operations in highly anomalous areas.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_helm_respirator">
		<text>Gas mask</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_helm_respirator_descr">
		<text>A regular plastic and rubber gas mask, used for filtering air for radioactive particles and poisonous substances. Widely used by rookies and veterans of all factions due to its universal functionality. Does not provide any physical protection.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_helm_tactic">
		<text>Tactical helmet</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_helm_tactic_descr">
		<text>A Western model of a tactical helmet that lacks camouflage. It is not known how it made its way into the Zone. The helmet is designed to provide a squad leader with strategic superiority over the enemy via its many scanners and satellite communications devices, which have not been installed in this particular helmet.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="stalker_outfit_name">
		<text>Sunrise bodysuit</text>
	</string>

	<string id="svoboda_heavy_outfit_name">
		<text>Freedom Guard bodysuit</text>
	</string>

	<string id="svoboda_light_outfit_description">
		<text>This lightweight stalker bodysuit is made by Freedom craftsmen. The suit's fabric is treated with Horizon, a special solution developed by the faction by trial and error to increase resistance to anomalies. Like the Sunrise suit, the Wind of Freedom comes with built-in body armor and artifact containers.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="svoboda_light_outfit_nimble_description">
		<text>This modified lightweight stalker bodysuit is made by Freedom craftsmen. The suit's fabric is treated with Horizon, a special solution developed by the faction by trial and error to increase resistance to anomalies. Like the Sunrise suit, the Wind of Freedom comes with built-in body armor and artifact containers, as well as an integrated metal wire mesh for protection from electric and magnetic fields.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="svoboda_light_outfit_name">
		<text>Wind of Freedom bodysuit</text>
	</string>

	<string id="svoboda_light_outfit_nimble_name">
		<text>Wind of Freedom M2 bodysuit</text>
	</string>

	<string id="dolg_outfit_description">
		<text>This modern version of the Duty bodysuit is better suited for stalker recruits who are used to lightweight suits. Unlike the PSZ series, this suit provides good protection against anomalies while also being capable of stopping a pistol bullet. The suit cannot be modified with an artifact container, but may be upgraded with a combat support system instead.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="dolg_outfit_nimble_description">
		<text>This modern version of the Duty bodysuit has been partially redesigned for hunting. Provides good protection against anomalies while also being capable of stopping a pistol bullet. The suit cannot be modified with an artifact container, but may be upgraded with a combat support system instead.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="military_outfit_description">
		<text>This modern military armored suit is designed for assault operations in anomalous areas. Comprises a PSZ-12p heavy military armored suit, built-in compensation suit, and an anomalous protection bodysuit. The armor provides excellent protection against bullet and fragmentation damage, without greatly reducing the wearer's mobility. Does not come with an artifact container.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="mp_scientific_outfit_description">
		<text>This bodysuit, intended for conducting research in the Zone, combines a closed-cycle respiratory module and an external isolation coating, resulting in excellent protection from anomalies. Due to poor protection from physical impact, the suit is not a good defense against bullet and fragmentation damage. Comes with a built-in artifact transportation container.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="scientific_outfit_description">
		<text>This suit, produced by one of Kiev's Defense Research Institutes, is a great alternative to homemade stalker suits. While its built-in body armor can only stop a pistol round, the anomaly and radiation protection system is second to none. Fully upgradeable and boasting two built-in artifact containers, this bodysuit is the equipment of choice for many experienced stalkers.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="specops_outfit_description">
		<text>This item comprises military PS5 series body armor with beryllium sputter modified for use in the Zone. Designed for assault operations in highly radioactive areas, it is ineffective in areas of high anomalous activity. The suit makes its way to stalkers through the military, who exchange it for loot. Does not come with an artifact container.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="specops_outfit_nimble_description">
		<text>This item comprises military PS5 series body armor with beryllium sputter modified for use in the Zone. Designed for assault operations in highly radioactive areas, it is ineffective in areas of high anomalous activity. The suit makes its way to stalkers through the military, who exchange it for loot. Does not come with an artifact container. The fabric of the suit is saturated with a streptozoidal lotion, which speeds up the healing of wounds.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="stalker_outfit_description">
		<text>This DIY stalker bodysuit is a combination of a bodysuit of twin-layered rubberized cloth with plexiglass lining and built-in body armor. Despite the fact that the body armor is incapable of protecting the wearer from even pistol bullets, the suit enjoys great popularity due to its low cost and modification potential. Comes with built-in artifact containers.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="svoboda_heavy_outfit_description">
		<text>This stalker bodysuit with reinforced body armor made by Freedom craftsmen represents a good compromise between combat and anomaly protection. The built-in body armor comprises armor plating and ten Kevlar layers, capable of stopping a pistol bullet. The suit uses the relatively expensive Sovereign compound for anomaly protection. Comes with an artifact container.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="dolg_heavy_outfit_description">
		<text>This early model of the Duty bodysuit is the Spetsnaz PSZ-9 body armor modified for the Zone. The suit is capable of stopping a rifle bullet, however, this level of protection comes at the cost of its weight, bulkiness and virtually non-existent anomaly protection. The suit cannot be modified with an artifact container, but may be upgraded with a combat support system.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="csky_heavy_outfit_description">
		<text>Once used as standard by Clear Sky assault squads, after the faction's elimination this armor serves as a reminder that even an excellent protective bodysuit cannot guarantee you safety this side of the perimeter. The armor is capable of stopping a pistol bullet, while the wearer is also well protected from anomalies. Comes with a built-in artifact container.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="exo_outfit_description">
		<text>An experimental sample of a military exoskeleton. Was never mass-produced due to extraordinary cost and some design flaws. Despite this, it is in demand due to its ability to take on the weight of all carried equipment, and therefore small batches are made in underground facilities outside Ukraine. Comes with a built-in artifact container.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="mp_scientific_outfit_name">
		<text>SEVA bodysuit</text>
	</string>

	<string id="bandit_outfit_description">
		<text>Traditional bandit clothing  -  a leather jacket with armor pieces sewed in. The protection it provides is completely inadequate for the harsh conditions of the Zone.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="bandit_outfit_name">
		<text>Bandit jacket</text>
	</string>

	<string id="bandit_brownrain_outfit_description">
		<text>Stylish bandit trench coat with sewed-in armor pieces. Provides more protection from adverse effects than a jacket, but is wholly inadequate for the harsh conditions of the Zone. Comes with a container that can hold up to two artifacts.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="bandit_brownrain_outfit_name">
		<text>Brown bandit trench coat</text>
	</string>

	<string id="bandit_blackrain_outfit_description">
		<text>Stylish bandit trench coat with sewed-in armor pieces. Provides more protection from adverse effects and gunfire than a jacket, but is wholly inadequate for the harsh conditions of the Zone. Comes with a container that can hold up to two artifacts.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="bandit_blackrain_outfit_name">
		<text>Black bandit trench coat</text>
	</string>

	<string id="bandit_light_outfit_description">
		<text>A homemade stalker costume. Effectively lightweight military body armor with additional protection against anomalous activity. Includes a container that can hold up to two artifacts.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="bandit_light_outfit_name">
		<text>Gentleman of Fortune suit</text>
	</string>

	<string id="merc_outfit_description">
		<text>A homemade stalker costume. Effectively lightweight military body armor with additional protection against anomalous activity. Includes a container that can hold up to two artifacts.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="merc_outfit_name">
		<text>Soldier of Fortune suit</text>
	</string>

	<string id="exo_merc_outfit_description">
		<text>An upgraded version of a regular exoskeleton. Assault variant with increased resistance against bullets, explosions and anomalous effects.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="exo_merc_outfit_name">
		<text>Hireling's suit</text>
	</string>

	<string id="soldier_outfit_description">
		<text>Standard military equipment in the form of light body armor. Provides decent protection against bullet and fragmentation damage, but is ineffective against anomalous effects and others. The suit cannot be modified with an artifact container.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="soldier_outfit_name">
		<text>Military body armor</text>
	</string>

	<string id="dolg_scientific_outfit_description">
		<text>A wonderful protective suit for the Zone. Stalkers appreciate it because it combines excellent anomaly-proof and bullet-proof qualities. It includes the PSZ-9d suit, a closed cycle breathing system and an integrated system of anomalous field suppression. It provides quality bullet and splinter protection.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="dolg_scientific_outfit_name">
		<text>PSZ-9Md Universal Protection</text>
	</string>

	<string id="exo_dolg_outfit_description">
		<text>An upgraded version of a regular exoskeleton. The use of more durable materials has allowed the designers to increase protection against mechanic effects and boost the durability of the suit itself.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="exo_dolg_outfit_name">
		<text>Duty exoskeleton</text>
	</string>

	<string id="svoboda_outfit_description">
		<text>This standard lightweight stalker bodysuit is made by Freedom craftsmen. Includes a container that can hold up to two artifacts.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="svoboda_outfit_name">
		<text>Freedom suit</text>
	</string>

	<string id="exo_freedom_outfit_description">
		<text>An upgraded version of a regular exoskeleton. The use of lighter materials has allowed the designers to reduce the suit's weight and boost its durability.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="exo_freedom_outfit_name">
		<text>Freedom exoskeleton</text>
	</string>

	<string id="neutral_assault_outfit_description">
		<text>A lightweight version of the exoskeleton. Its armour elements were used in manufacturing. There is no hydraulic system. The body armour provides good protection against small arms, and the built-in gas mask and rubberised cloth overalls provide good protection against abnormal effects. It has a built-in container for artefacts.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="neutral_assault_outfit_name">
		<text>Assault armor</text>
	</string>

	<string id="monolith_outfit_description">
		<text>A Monolith bodysuit made with unknown technology. The armor is capable of stopping a pistol bullet while the suit's dual-layered material offers protection against various anomalies and radiation. Comes with a built-in artifact container.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="monolith_outfit_name">
		<text>Monolith-2 suit</text>
	</string>

	<string id="monolith_scientific_outfit_description">
		<text>As with many Monolith creations, the technology used in creating this suit is unknown. It is made up of unknown materials that are lighter than their counterparts and protect very well against radiation. Contains a closed-loop breathing system.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="monolith_scientific_outfit_name">
		<text>Monolith science suit</text>
	</string>

	<string id="monolith_assault_outfit_description">
		<text>Standard equipment used by Monolith assault squads, made with unknown technology. The armor provides good protection from gunfire while the included gas mask and suit ensure good protection from anomalies. Comes with a built-in artifact container.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="monolith_assault_outfit_name">
		<text>Monolit-Sh armored suit</text>
	</string>

	<string id="exo_mono_outfit_description">
		<text>A Monolith exoskeleton made with unknown technology that provides good protection against all effects. Wears out slowly.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="exo_mono_outfit_name">
		<text>Monolith exoskeleton</text>
	</string>

	<string id="ecolog_outfit_description">
		<text>A SSP-99M chemical protection suit specially designed for the Zone's conditions. Used by scientific expeditions and eco-stalkers who cooperate with them. It has an integrated air-filtering and air-conditioning system. It is heat and electricity resistant, provides good protection from radiation and biological anomalies. It is resistant to chemically aggressive environments. Provides excellent protection against all anomalous effects and also against psy-effects thanks to its induced field suppression system. Has Kevlar plates.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="ecolog_outfit_name">
		<text>SSP-99M VEGA</text>
	</string>
	<string id="red_ecolog_red_outfit_name">
		<text>SSP-99 Ecologist</text>
	</string>
	<string id="red_ecolog_red_outfit_description">
		<text>A SSP-99 chemical protection suit specially designed for the Zone's conditions. Used by scientific expeditions and eco-stalkers who cooperate with them. It has an integrated air-filtering and air-conditioning system. It is heat and electricity resistant, provides good protection from radiation and biological anomalies. It is resistant to chemically aggressive environments. Provides excellent protection against all anomalous effects and also against psy-effects thanks to its induced field suppression system. Not designed for combat.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_scientific_outfit_name">
		<text>PSZ-9Md Universal protection</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_scientific_outfit_description">
		<text>An excellent protective jumpsuit for the Zone. Stalkers appreciate it for the combination of excellent anti-anomalous qualities and anti-bullet protection. Includes: PSZ-9d jumpsuit, closed-cycle breathing system, built-in system of suppression of anomalous fields. Provides quality protection against bullet and shrapnel damage.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_helm_respirator_gp7">
		<text>M40 protective mask</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_helm_respirator_gp7_descr">
		<text>The M40 protective mask provides reliable defense against many toxic and chemically hazardous substances, radioactive dust and bacterial agents. Respected among stalkers and mainly used by mercenary groups throughout the Zone.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_helm_battle_dolg">
		<text>Sphere helmet</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_helm_battle_dolg_descr">
		<text>A Sphere helmet adjusted by Duty technicians for the faction's needs. The gas mask provides increased protection against radiation and chemical substances. Contains a built-in night vision device.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="svoboda_scientific_outfit_name">
		<text>Freedom science suit</text>
	</string>

	<string id="svoboda_scientific_outfit_description">
		<text>A DIY armored suit made by Freedom specifically for scientific research in the Zone. The closed breathing system and special impregnation provide excellent protection against radiation and harmful anomalous influences, though the body armor is incapable of protecting the wearer from even pistol bullets, making the suit unfitting for combat.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_stalker_outfit_barge">
		<text>Tourist suit</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_stalker_outfit_barge_descr">
		<text>The former owner of this thing was a real tourist and, it seems, often went on very difficult, on the verge of human endurance, hiking trips. He knew how to distribute correctly the weight that he carried, and which things to give preference to. The coat pockets and the educated choice of the backpack allow its owner to carry a heavy weight.</text>
	</string>

</string_table>
