<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<string_table>

	<string id="st_af_baloon_descr">
		<text>The artefact is several hollow formations of organic nature connected to each other. It emits a gaseous substance that can have a positive effect on the skin, healing wounds; no harmful effects of the substance on the human body have been detected. Due to its high efficiency, it is in great demand.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_af_baloon_name">
		<text>Bubble</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_af_blood_descr">
		<text>It is a reddish formation of compacted and fossilised plant, soil and animal remains. It has the ability to partially neutralise substances harmful to humans. Emits radiation.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_af_blood_name">
		<text>Stone Blood</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_af_cristall_descr">
		<text>The artefact appears in anomalous zones under the influence of high temperatures. It actively absorbs excessive heat from the space around it, while remaining cool to the touch. Emits radiation.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_af_cristall_flower_descr">
		<text>The artefact is a stone close in its characteristics to granite. It appears under the influence of a gravitational field of great intensity. It is able to fully or partially remove radiation from the organism, similar in its properties to the "Night Star", so it also slightly saturates the organism.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_af_cristall_flower_name">
		<text>Stone Flower</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_af_cristall_name">
		<text>Crystal</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_af_dummy_battery_descr">
		<text>It is known that this artefact contains electrostatic elements, but under what conditions it is formed, science does not know yet. It is valued among residents and visitors of the Zone for its ability to have a tonic effect on the human body. If exposed for too long, it exhausts the organism. Emits radiation.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_af_dummy_battery_name">
		<text>Battery</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_af_dummy_dummy_descr">
		<text>Previously, this artefact was considered junk, devoid of any useful properties. However, some time ago it was found out that in constant contact with the human body this artefact removes radiation and saturates the body.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_af_dummy_dummy_name">
		<text>Shell</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_af_dummy_glassbeads_descr">
		<text>Much about this artefact remains a mystery. However, it is definitely established that the radiation arising from the pulsation of the thickenings of Mum's Beads causes neural connections in the brain to be restored. Emits radiation.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_af_dummy_glassbeads_name">
		<text>Mama's Beads</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_af_electra_flash_descr">
		<text>An artefact of an electrostatic nature. Demonstrates an amazing ability to absorb the stimulation of the wearer's muscles. Capable of releasing tension from the body, giving coolness, moisture, and probably the power of the earth. Emits radiation.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_af_electra_flash_name">
		<text>Flash</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_af_electra_moonlight_descr">
		<text>This artefact of electrostatic nature demonstrates the ability to resonate under the influence of radiation. Over time, stalkers have learnt to adjust the Moonlight so that it resonates in phase with the main source of radiation, thereby stimulating the muscles completely or largely. Emits radiation.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_af_electra_moonlight_name">
		<text>Moonlight</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_af_electra_sparkler_descr">
		<text>A member of the electrostatic artefact family, named for its brightness. Possesses the ability to relieve tension in human muscles. Emits radiation.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_af_electra_sparkler_name">
		<text>Sparkler</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_af_eye_descr">
		<text>This artefact outwardly really resembles an organ of vision. In case of injuries, it accelerates metabolic processes, which contributes to the rapid recovery of psi-health. In addition, there is a belief among experienced stalkers that the "Eye" can bring good luck. Emits radiation.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_af_eye_name">
		<text>Eye</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_af_fire_descr">
		<text>It is formed in areas of increased thermal activity. It is characterised by strong infrared radiation, which accelerates the process of blood clotting in open wounds of the bearer. Due to the great rarity of this artefact, its cost is extremely high.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_af_fire_name">
		<text>Flame</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_af_fireball_descr">
		<text>Despite the name, which is quite reflective of the nature of this artefact, the Fireball can easily be held in the hands without fear of burns. It is valued for its ability to maintain a constant temperature of about +24 degrees Celsius in a small radius around it, regardless of environmental conditions.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_af_fireball_name">
		<text>Fireball</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_af_fuzz_kolobok_descr">
		<text>Quite a rare artefact formed in areas of heavy chemical pollution. It is highly valued for its ability to "spur" the body to recover from injuries of any severity in a matter of minutes. Scientists are spreading information about the artifact's effect on the owner's genetic material; however, there is no confirmation of this yet. Emits radiation.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_af_fuzz_kolobok_name">
		<text>Kolobok</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_af_glass_name">
		<text>Dacite</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_af_gold_fish_descr">
		<text>The artefact is formed in places where multiple gravitational fields interact. Generates a sphere of directed gravitational field around itself. Reduces the weight of the contents of the carrier's backpack much more effectively than other artefacts of this kind; therefore, it is in great demand among stalkers. Emits radiation.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_af_gold_fish_name">
		<text>Goldfish</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_af_gravi_descr">
		<text>The artefact is formed by prolonged gravitational effect on metal-containing substances. It is able to maintain a small anti-gravity field around itself. Many stalkers use it to significantly reduce the weight of their backpack. Emits radiation.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_af_gravi_name">
		<text>Gravi</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_af_ice_descr">
		<text>Outwardly, the artefact looks like a "Kolobok"; there is an opinion that it is a "Kolobok", but only after getting into a powerful electric field. It is capable of sharply increasing the muscle tone of the wearer. Emits radiation.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_af_ice_name">
		<text>Snowflake</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_af_medusa_descr">
		<text>An artefact of gravitational nature with the ability to actively restore neural connections in the brain. Widespread in the Zone; outside the Zone it is widely, albeit tacitly, used in the treatment of brain cancer.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_af_medusa_name">
		<text>Jellyfish</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_af_mincer_meat_descr">
		<text>An artefact of an organic nature. It consists of deformed tissues of animal origin. When it enters the zone of negative influence it starts to "heal" the organism. Emits radiation.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_af_mincer_meat_name">
		<text>Meat Chunk</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_af_night_star_descr">
		<text>A glowing artefact capable of absorbing radiation, which has a favourable effect on the general state of the organism, making a person feel satiated. Widely used by stalkers for trips to highly radioactive zones.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_af_night_star_name">
		<text>Night Star</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_af_soul_descr">
		<text>An organic artefact with unique properties. In a yet unknown way, it increases the overall rate of recovery from injuries of any nature without accelerating the accumulation of toxins. Due to its pleasant appearance, it is of particular interest to collectors. Emits radiation.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_af_soul_name">
		<text>Soul</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_af_vyvert_descr">
		<text>An artefact of bizarre shape that appears in places of increased gravitational activity has a positive effect on the state of the organism, thanks to which the bearer feels a surge of strength.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_af_vyvert_name">
		<text>Wrenched</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_compass">
		<text>Compass</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_compass_descr">
		<text>A rare artefact - last found many months ago. It has the ability to show gaps in anomalous fields. It is said that it can be used to get past the most difficult anomalies without the slightest risk, but very few people know how to use it.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_oasis_heart">
		<text>Heart of the Oasis</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_oasis_heart_descr">
		<text>This artifact was found at the center of the legendary Oasis. It appears that the Heart is a crystallized plant, which has acquired the healing properties of the Oasis. Unlike the Oasis itself, however, this artifact is extremely radioactive.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_af_glass_descr">
		<text>Dacite occurs in psi-zones with high levels of radiation. It has properties of resistance to thermal effects and slightly protects the bearer from negative consequences of being in psi zones.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_af_drops">
		<text>Droplets</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_af_drops_descr">
		<text>Formed by the Heat anomaly at high temperatures. Externally, it looks like a blackened drop-shaped formation with a glossy surface covered with cracks.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_af_ameba_slime">
		<text>Slime</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_af_ameba_slime_descr">
		<text>It is known for certain that the artefact is spawned in a chemical anomaly. When worn on the belt, wounds bleed less, though the host's body is put at risk of radiation.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_af_ameba_slug">
		<text>Slug</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_af_ameba_slug_descr">
		<text>Formed in chemical anomalous zones. The artefact is radioactive, but increases blood clotting. This artefact is uncommon and fetches a good price.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_af_ameba_mica">
		<text>Mica</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_af_ameba_mica_descr">
		<text>A chemical anomaly is capable of producing such an artefact under the rarest, most extreme set of physical conditions. The result is a translucent solid object. The artefact is expensive and rare.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_af_dummy_pellicle">
		<text>Pellicle</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_af_dummy_pellicle_descr">
		<text>This artefact is so rare that many researchers have no idea that such a substance can exist in natural conditions. Rejects caustic chemical components.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_af_rusty_sea_urchin">
		<text>Urchin</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_af_rusty_sea_urchin_descr">
		<text>The Chemical anomaly very rarely spawns such an artefact. The artefact copes very well with chemically polluted air. Sakharov in his fundamental paper "Ionisation and polarisation of components of rare artefacts" noticed that the composition of this formation has critical stability, and to achieve the creation of such an artefact in the conditions of the laboratory in the coming decades is unrealistic.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_af_dummy_spring">
		<text>Spring</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_af_dummy_spring_descr">
		<text>According to some research theorists, this artefact is a hybrid of a Battery and a Shell</text>
	</string>

	<string id="af_rusty_thorn">
		<text>Thorn</text>
	</string>

	<string id="af_rusty_thorn_descr">
		<text>The result of the interaction between the Chemical anomaly and the body of an inattentive stalker. The spiky artefact prickles the owner's body, no matter how it is attached. But it also helps to purify the body from the progenitor - chemical gases. Quite common and cheap.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="af_rusty_kristall">
		<text>Crystal Thorn</text>
	</string>

	<string id="af_rusty_kristall_descr">
		<text>Crystallised in the Chemical anomaly. It is rare and filters chemical gases quite effectively, which has earned it a stable price on the artefact market.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_af_jagel_name">
		<text>Lichen</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_af_jagel_descr">
		<text>The artefact by its nature is only born in psi zones with little radiation. Radioactive, but this is offset by its ability to absorb small electrical discharges.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_af_tuber_name">
		<text>Truffle</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_af_tuber_descr">
		<text>It is one of the few artefacts that is born in psi zones with rather strong radiation. It differs from its predecessor "Jagel" by its greater ability to resist electricity, and the radiation level of both artefacts is practically the same.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_af_mumiyo_name">
		<text>Mumieux</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_af_mumiyo_descr">
		<text>A rare artefact born in areas with very high psi radiation. It has enormous properties of electrical resistance and, unfortunately, emits quanta of light (gamma radiation) at a high frequency, which can give the bearer radiation sickness.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_af_oskolok_vikidish_name">
		<text>Miscarriage</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_af_oskolok_vikidish_descr">
		<text>Dead, failed artefact, most often occurs in a place where there was an anomaly, but dissipated after ejection. No properties other than radioactivity have been detected.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_af_oskolok_sirota_name">
		<text>Orphan</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_af_oskolok_sirota_descr">
		<text>A dead artefact from a vanished anomaly, essentially a fragile shard of solid rock. Radioactive.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_af_oskolok_shmatok_name">
		<text>Clump</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_af_oskolok_shmatok_descr">
		<text>Fragile fragment of soft rock, degeneration zone, has no positive properties, as well as negative ones. Scientists would be willing to pay for the study of this specimen.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_esc_stalker_liar_artefact">
		<text>Dog's heart</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_esc_stalker_liar_artefact_descr">
		<text>This artefact is quite rare, and its appearance on the outskirts of the Zone remains a mystery. The heart emits waves with healing properties similar to those of such artefacts as Soul and its like, and, among other things, makes the wearer's skin rougher, protecting it from cuts and scratches. Despite its beneficial properties, the artefact is radioactive and caution should be used.</text>
	</string>

</string_table>
