<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>
<string_table>
  <string id="agroprom_docs">
    <text>LOCKED-UP CASE</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_diggers_reach_base_name">
    <text>Reach the digger base</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_diggers_reach_base_text">
    <text>I have the safe code, and now I just have to get to the base. Better not get caught!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_diggers_speak_leader_name">
    <text>Talk to the digger leader</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_diggers_speak_leader_text">
    <text>I gotta trick the clan and convince them that I come with good intentions. Time to improvize.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_diggers_speak_leave_base_name">
    <text>Exit the area</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_diggers_speak_leave_base_text">
    <text>Seems I was able to convince that weirdo. Now I wait and see what happens next.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_diggers_go_open_safe_name">
    <text>Open the safe</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_diggers_go_open_safe_text">
    <text>I need to open the case, grab the documents and scram out of here.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_diggers_not_full_take_case_name">
    <text>Grab the documents from the safe</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_diggers_not_full_take_case_text">
    <text>The safe is open. Time to grab the loot.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="diggers_take_weapons">
    <text>RIFLES</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_diggers_weapons_take_start_name">
    <text>Retrieve your weapons</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_diggers_weapons_take_start_text">
    <text>I need to retrieve the weapons that I handed in before entering the digger base.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_diggers_speak_patron_name">
    <text>Report to Shooter</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_diggers_speak_patron_text">
    <text>I have the case. Time to report to the contractor.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_diggers_speak_trader_name">
    <text>Hand over the case to Crutch</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_diggers_speak_trader_text">
    <text>Hand over the case to the trader. I hope this will smooth out our relations.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agroprom_docs_new_attempt">
    <text>WAR OF THE CASE</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_diggers_go_attack_case_name">
    <text>Acquire the case by force</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_diggers_go_attack_case_text">
    <text>I was unable to get the case peacefully. I'll have to get a hold of it by force, or else I won't earn the trader's trust.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agroprom_docs_not_full">
    <text>SAFE CODE</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_diggers_not_full_go_attack_leader_name">
    <text>Kill the digger leader</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_diggers_not_full_go_attack_leader_text">
    <text>The easy way didn't work - I'll have to do this by sheer force. The code is likely held by the leader.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_stalker_help_sos_task">
    <text>DISTRESS SIGNAL</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_stalker_help_sos_task_start_name">
    <text>Respond to the stalker's distress signal</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_stalker_help_sos_task_start_text">
    <text>A stalker named Red sent an SOS signal. I'll go check the entrance to the Agroprom underground.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_stalker_help_sos_task_under_start_name">
    <text>Help Red rescue his friend</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_stalker_help_sos_task_under_start_text">
    <text>Red needs help with rescuing his friend from an anomaly. We'll see what happens...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_stalker_help_sos_task_follow_name">
    <text>Follow Red</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_stalker_help_sos_task_follow_text">
    <text>I need to follow Red to where his comrade was left to wait for help.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_stalker_help_sos_task_speak_final_name">
    <text>Talk to Red</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_stalker_help_sos_task_speak_final_text">
    <text>Looks like we arrived, but all I can see are corpses...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_stalker_perch_task">
    <text>DANGEROUS MISSIONS</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_stalker_perch_task_start_name">
    <text>Meet Perch in the Bar</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_stalker_perch_task_start_text">
    <text>A stalker named Perch offered me a good sum to partner up for Barkeep's work. If I find myself in the Bar, I'll check it out.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_soldier_post_task">
    <text>HUNGRY SENTRY</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_soldier_post_start_name">
    <text>Get food for the soldier</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_soldier_post_start_text">
    <text>A soldier in the vicinity of the scientist base has asked for food. Only then will he call over Dubinin. Four bread loafs, cans of meat or sausages should be enough.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_soldier_post_final_name">
    <text>Give the soldier food</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_soldier_post_final_text">
    <text>I hope the army guy will talk to Dubinin about meeting me now.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_drunk_medic_search">
    <text>DRUNKEN MEDIC</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_drunk_medic_search_start_name">
    <text>Find Alexander</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_drunk_medic_search_start_text">
    <text>The stalker camp is in dire need of a medic. The most reliable option would be bringing a former research assistant to their base, but first he needs to be found... and laid off the bottle.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_scientific_job">
    <text>SCIENTIFIC WORK</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_scientific_job_start_speak_scientist_task_name">
    <text>Talk to Dubinin</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_scientific_job_start_speak_scientist_task_text">
    <text>Head's throbbing... but I should get up and go meet with Dubinin. He wants to talk to me regarding Gamzat's notes.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_scientific_job_start_speak_assistant_name">
    <text>Talk to Dubinin's assistant</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_scientific_job_start_speak_assistant_text">
    <text>I signed up to contribute to the scientist effort by studying artifact transmutation. I was given a pass and paid quite handsomely. Doesn't seem like a tough job, and my instructions are crystal clear - better to rummage in anomalies than run from mutants and sneak off bandit boxes.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_scientific_job_start_go_name">
    <text>Go to the anomalous swamp</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_scientific_job_start_go_text">
    <text>I need to extract a transmuted artifact from the anomalous swamp. Karavayev will provide assistance.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_scientific_job_kill_stalkers_name">
    <text>Kill the stalkers</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_scientific_job_kill_stalkers_text">
    <text>We encountered some stalkers seeking to get their hands the transmutational artifact. They aren't willing to part with it so easily...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_scientific_job_relax_speak_name">
    <text>Talk to Karavayev</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_scientific_job_relax_speak_text">
    <text>I need to talk to Karavayev and discuss our next steps.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_scientific_job_relax_wait_assistant_name">
    <text>Wait until Karavayev finds a safe path</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_scientific_job_relax_wait_assistant_text">
    <text>Karavayev will attempt to find a safe way to the artifact. Let's see how that turns out.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_scientific_job_detector_broken_speak_name">
    <text>Talk to Karavayev</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_scientific_job_detector_broken_speak_text">
    <text>It seems my companion's search didn't go as planned...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_scientific_job_take_artefact_name">
    <text>Get the artifact</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_scientific_job_take_artefact_text">
    <text>Time to do things the good old fashioned way: no equipment. I'll have to find a safe path to the artifact and get it.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_scientific_job_speak_final_assistant_name">
    <text>Talk to Karavayev</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_scientific_job_speak_final_assistant_text">
    <text>I got the artifact. Now I can return to the scientist facility.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_scientific_job_go_base_name">
    <text>Return to Dubinin</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_scientific_job_go_base_text">
    <text>Time to return to the scientist facility and talk to Dubinin about the artifact I acquired.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_scientific_job_second">
    <text>NEW SURROUNDINGS</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_scientific_job_second_start_name">
    <text>Talk to Yurok about the road to Novoshepelychi</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_scientific_job_second_start_text">
    <text>I saw a long road to places not yet discovered! I'll go through the Cordon and see an old acquaintance of mine. I should to talk to Yurok about the safest way to get to Novoshepelychi.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_scientific_job_second_change_level_name">
    <text>Go to Novoshepelychi</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_scientific_job_second_change_level_text">
    <text>It's time to familiarize myself with new surroundings. Yurok told me that Novoshepelychi is an even more dangerous place than the Garbage. I'll keep that in mind.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_mid_final_task">
    <text>ESCORT</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_mid_final_task_follow_the_scientists_name">
    <text>Cover the scientists on the way to the facility</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_mid_final_task_follow_the_scientists_text">
    <text>I must cover the scientists while they carry out their scientific work.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_colonel_task">
    <text>COMMANDER'S CALL</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_colonel_task_go_talk_name">
    <text>Talk to the colonel</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_colonel_task_go_talk_text">
    <text>Colonel Klinskikh called me to see him. I hope he's got more important work for me than strolling with the scientists.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_before_sending">
    <text>BEFORE THE DEPARTURE</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_before_sending_talk_with_squad_name">
    <text>Talk to the squad</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_before_sending_talk_with_squad_text">
    <text>My squad was at last trusted with a serious operation. Its outcome will decide everything: either I keep protecting the scientist chambers until the contract expires or I keep advancing to the center of the Zone. I need to prepare for the departure and exchange a few words with my squadmates.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_before_sending_talk_with_koval_name">
    <text>Talk to Koval</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_before_sending_talk_with_koval_text">
    <text>Before commencing the operation, I need to get to know more about Koval. He's a strange one, rarely speaking to other milstalkers, keeping to himself and disappearing from the facility. So why does the colonel tolerate all that and even insist on sending him off with our team? His signal is coming from the edges of Agroprom. I'll go check it out.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_before_sending_go_sleep_name">
    <text>Rest until morning</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_before_sending_go_sleep_text">
    <text>The squad is ready to launch the operation. For now, though, I should get some rest and build up my strength. Yantar's always given me strange and sullen feelings - it's always felt damp, hopeless... and ridden with death, even while the mobile bunker was in operation and while stalkers flocked to sign up for work and go artifact hunting. But what about now? There have been all kinds of legends about the lake for a month now. Stalkers stay as far away from it as possible, the scientists haven't made contact with anyone and the anomalies have become increasingly active. What did Sakharov research? Are they still alive? We'll have our answers tomorrow.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_after_yantar_task">
    <text>RISE AND SHINE</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_after_yantar_task_talk_with_xottab_name">
    <text>Talk to Hottab</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_after_yantar_task_talk_with_xottab_text">
    <text>After reporting the mission's success to the colonel, we decided to celebrate our return from such hazardous areas. We had a good time. The boys are still sleeping, except Hottabych. I'll go have a talk with him.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_after_yantar_task_to_wash_name">
    <text>Head to the bathroom</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_after_yantar_task_to_wash_text">
    <text>I need to freshen up before seeing the colonel.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_scientist_boss_info_task">
    <text>FACE-TO-FACE</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_scientist_boss_info_task_start_name">
    <text>Go to the colonel's office</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_scientist_boss_info_task_start_text">
    <text>The colonel wanted to see me this morning. I should check what he wants.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_scientist_boss_search_task">
    <text>MISSING SCIENTIST</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_scientist_boss_search_task_start_name">
    <text>Have a word with the group</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_scientist_boss_search_task_start_text">
    <text>The colonel set the objective of finding a missing scientist named Dubinin. I'll be searching for him on my own in order not to draw any attention. Beforehand, I need to inform my group about this mission so that they can render assistance should the need arise.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_scientist_boss_search_task_talk_with_soldiers_name">
    <text>Have a word with the military stalkers</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_scientist_boss_search_task_talk_with_soldiers_text">
    <text>The military stalkers might know more about how the scientist disappeared, having previously acted as an escort for him during fieldwork. I should question them.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_scientist_boss_search_task_check_tonnel_name">
    <text>Examine the tunnel at Agroprom</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_scientist_boss_search_task_check_tonnel_text">
    <text>According to the stalkers, a scientist landed in an anomaly in a tunnel at Agroprom. It could be Dubinin. I should examine that area and confirm my suspicions.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_scientist_boss_search_task_go_back_name">
    <text>Take the remains to an expert</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_scientist_boss_search_task_go_back_text">
    <text>Human remains and scraps of Dubinin's signature scientist suit were located by the anomaly. To confirm that it's really him, I should take the genetic material to the scientist facility.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_scientist_boss_search_task_heli_name">
    <text>Go to the Cordon</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_scientist_boss_search_task_heli_text">
    <text>A scientific expedition is preparing to fly to Dityatki. Perhaps they'll bring me on board so I don't have to trudge to Sidorovich on foot.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_scientist_boss_global_state_name">
    <text>Find clues behind Dubinin's disappearance</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_scientist_boss_global_state_text">
    <text>For all intents and purposes, I've been given free rein on the operation. I must find all possible clues to find out what happened to professor Dubinin.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_tonnel_dogs_task">
    <text>DOG ATTACK</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_tonnel_dogs_task_kill_dogs_name">
    <text>Help the field group fight off the attack</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_tonnel_dogs_task_kill_dogs_text">
    <text>These mutant attacks on assistants in the field are nothing out of the ordinary. I should help my colleagues protect the scientists.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_tonnel_dogs_task_talk_name">
    <text>Talk to Kridov</text>
  </string>
  <string id="agr_tonnel_dogs_task_talk_text">
    <text>Before leaving, I'll have another word with Kridov.</text>
  </string>
</string_table>
