<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<string_table>
  <string id="esc_trader_side_task_1_title_start">
    <text>Find a Stone Blood artifact</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_trader_side_task_1_descr_start">
    <text>Sidorovich asked me to get a Stone Blood artifact, part of an order he received from the scientists. He promised a good reward.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_trader_side_task_1_dialog_descr">
    <text>I got an order from the scientists for the Stone Blood artifact. I seem to remember they have heaps of those lying around, but if they need it, they need it. You up for it?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_trader_side_task_1_title_reward">
    <text>Bring the Stone Blood to Sidorovich</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_trader_side_task_1_descr_reward">
    <text>Artifact found. Now I can see the trader for my reward.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_trader_side_task_2_title_start">
    <text>Find a Meat Chunk artifact</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_trader_side_task_2_descr_start">
    <text>Another request from Sidorovich: get the Meat Chunk artifact. He's offered more money than usual for this hunt, so I should look for it.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_trader_side_task_2_dialog_descr">
    <text>The scientists have sent another order, this time for a Meat Chunk. Don't pass this up — I'll pay you more than what it's usually worth!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_trader_side_task_2_title_reward">
    <text>Bring the Meat Chunk to Sidorovich</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_trader_side_task_2_descr_reward">
    <text>The reward should be bigger this time than the last. I hope it'll be worth it.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_trader_side_task_3_title_start">
    <text>Find a Wrenched artifact</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_trader_side_task_3_descr_start">
    <text>Another scientist artifact order from Sidorovich. I need to get him a Wrenched — for that, he'll share a generous part of his wealth.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_trader_side_task_3_dialog_descr">
    <text>So, the eggheads have ordered another artifact. Get me a Wrenched and I'll get you a nice reward.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_trader_side_task_3_title_reward">
    <text>Bring the Wrenched to Sidorovich</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_trader_side_task_3_descr_reward">
    <text>The third in the line of artifact orders is done. Sidorovich should be generous now more than ever.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_trader_side_task_4_title_start">
    <text>Get a pseudodog tail</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_trader_side_task_4_descr_start">
    <text>Besides artifacts, scientists send Sidorovich orders for mutant body parts. For now, the trader has asked me to bring a pseudodog tail.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_trader_side_task_4_dialog_descr">
    <text>The scientists are doing research on the nature of mutants. I got an order for a pseudodog tail. Will you take it?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_trader_side_task_4_title_reward">
    <text>Bring the pseudodog tail to Sidorovich</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_trader_side_task_4_descr_reward">
    <text>I have the pseudodog tail. Time to return to the trader for the reward.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_trader_side_task_5_title_start">
    <text>Get three tushkan heads</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_trader_side_task_5_descr_start">
    <text>Another order's come in for mutant body parts. I need to get the heads of three tushkans.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_trader_side_task_5_dialog_descr">
    <text>Here's the next mutant order: three tushkan heads. Good pay in it for you.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_trader_side_task_5_title_reward">
    <text>Bring the tushkan heads to Sidorovich</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_trader_side_task_5_descr_reward">
    <text>I found all three tushkan heads. Time to return to the trader and get my reward.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_trader_side_task_6_title_start">
    <text>Get a bloodsucker jaw</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_trader_side_task_6_descr_start">
    <text>Sidorovich has ordered a bloodsucker jaw. He promised a good reward, so it'll be worth a shot.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_trader_side_task_6_dialog_descr">
    <text>Yet another urgent order from the scientists. Bring me a bloodsucker jaw and I'll pay you generously.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_trader_side_task_6_title_reward">
    <text>Bring the bloodsucker jaw to Sidorovich</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_trader_side_task_6_descr_reward">
    <text>I've completed the trader's request. Time to hand him this filth and get my well-earned reward.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_trader_side_task_7_title_start">
    <text>Kill the stalker novice</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_trader_side_task_7_descr_start">
    <text>Sidorovich has asked me to deal with a certain stalker novice who's been a thorn in his side. The trader guarantees anonymity when dealing with such contracts and promises a good reward.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_trader_side_task_7_dialog_descr">
    <text>I need a stalker who's been in a pain in my ass urgently taken care of. We won't go over the details; just know that the price for these things is worth it and your identity stays safe.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_trader_side_task_7_title_reward">
    <text>Tell Sidorovich that the stalker is dead</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_trader_side_task_7_descr_reward">
    <text>Sidorovich's pain-in-the-ass stalker won't be a pain for anyone anymore. Time to retrieve my reward.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_trader_side_task_8_title_start">
    <text>Kill the "sales representative"</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_trader_side_task_8_descr_start">
    <text>Sidorovich is crossed again, this time by a certain "sales representative". I need to deal with him.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_trader_side_task_8_dialog_descr">
    <text>Another sprat is trying to get a piece of my business dealings — he's calling himself a "sales representative". Remove him and you'll get a well-earned reward.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_trader_side_task_8_title_reward">
    <text>Tell Sidorovich that the bandit is dead</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_trader_side_task_8_descr_reward">
    <text>The stalker who put a price on Sidorovich's head turned out to be a bandit. I can now retrieve my reward.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_trader_side_task_9_title_start">
    <text>Kill the small-time stalker trader</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_trader_side_task_9_descr_start">
    <text>Someone is constantly putting spokes in the wheels of Sidorovich's peaceful business. I need to deal with another such stalker.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_trader_side_task_9_dialog_descr">
    <text>Your next task is to remove another small-time trader who's already done a lot of harm to me. Will you do it?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_trader_side_task_9_title_reward">
    <text>Tell Sidorovich that the stalker is dead</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_trader_side_task_9_descr_reward">
    <text>Another one of Sidorovich's hits is done. Time to grab my reward.</text>
  </string>
</string_table>
