<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<string_table>
  <string id="yan_treasure_1_name">
    <text>Pipe in Kamaz</text>
  </string>
  <string id="yan_treasure_1_descr">
    <text>While the factory's still irradiated, I'm gonna leave a stash with medical supplies nearby. I'm sick of carrying it around already.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="yan_treasure_2_name">
    <text>Safe</text>
  </string>
  <string id="yan_treasure_2_descr">
    <text>This guy gave me the coords to his stash at Yantar for helping him hunt mutants. Whether I'll even get there, though... that's a whole different story.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="yan_treasure_3_name">
    <text>Fuse box at fence</text>
  </string>
  <string id="yan_treasure_3_descr">
    <text>After a catch like that, I might as well stash some of it. There's a nice little place nearby where I think I'll drop it off.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="yan_treasure_4_name">
    <text>Switchboard room</text>
  </string>
  <string id="yan_treasure_4_descr">
    <text>On the way to the factory, there's a switchboard room. I doubt anyone is gonna risk their ass and go there while Yantar's still covered by psy-emissions.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="yan_treasure_5_name">
    <text>Stump on hill</text>
  </string>
  <string id="yan_treasure_5_descr">
    <text>I saw this zombie digging in a rotten stump a moment ago. Looks like it's not brain-dead just yet! Once our boys leave, I'll see what the poor fella's got there.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="yan_treasure_6_name">
    <text>Hidden stash</text>
  </string>
  <string id="yan_treasure_6_descr">
    <text>A pal of mine on contract for the scientists sent off a distress signal. He hasn't been on the air for days now. Looks I'll be cleaning out his stuff on my next visit to Yantar, 'cause it's a shame letting it go to waste.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="yan_treasure_7_name">
    <text>Backpack on helicopter</text>
  </string>
  <string id="yan_treasure_7_descr">
    <text>The paths to the helicopter are heavily flooded... and not just with water, but with mutants. I don't even know whether I should even go back to my stash around there...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="yan_treasure_8_name">
    <text>Rusty pipe</text>
  </string>
  <string id="yan_treasure_8_descr">
    <text>Found a good place for hiding my well-earned pickings from the eggheads. I'll be filling up this stash while they don't suspect anything.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="yan_treasure_9_name">
    <text>Hatch</text>
  </string>
  <string id="yan_treasure_9_descr">
    <text>I found a fat stash under this heavy old hatch. Gonna return once I leave my backpack — walking with all that loot on your back and a gun in your hands ain't the wisest decision.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="yan_treasure_10_name">
    <text>Log at garages</text>
  </string>
  <string id="yan_treasure_10_descr">
    <text>There's a ton of space in a log by the three garages, great place for my loot. I'll leave some of my stuff there for a while.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="yan_quest_treasure_1_name">
    <text>Panel under rubble</text>
  </string>
  <string id="yan_quest_treasure_1_descr">
    <text>I dug up a ton of useful things while finding a way out of the lab. Too bad I can't carry it all, so I'll leave some of it here. Might come back for it later.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="yan_quest_treasure_2_name">
    <text>Case in toilet</text>
  </string>
  <string id="yan_quest_treasure_2_descr">
    <text>There's a case in the toilet by the door. One of the stalkers who went down here made a cache with supplies. You might just find something useful there.</text>
  </string>
</string_table>
