<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<string_table>
  <string id="gar_treasure_1_name">
    <text>Hatch</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_treasure_1_descr">
    <text>I followed the stalker as he was going to his stash. I'll check it out sooner or later.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_treasure_2_name">
    <text>Heaps of pipes</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_treasure_2_descr">
    <text>I squeezed some info out of a sucker on a stash of his. He and his pal are hiding all kinds of stuff there. Riches, here I come!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_treasure_3_name">
    <text>Ravine near outpost</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_treasure_3_descr">
    <text>This one chump was taking a whiz in the bushes. Didn't notice when I made it off with his backpack. Think I'll hide it for some time.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_treasure_4_name">
    <text>Dropped backpack</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_treasure_4_descr">
    <text>Can't make it off with this wound... Gotta let go of the stuff...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_treasure_5_name">
    <text>Cross near stones</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_treasure_5_descr">
    <text>Perfect spot for a stash: a remote cross in high radiation.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_treasure_6_name">
    <text>Backpack in heli</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_treasure_6_descr">
    <text>Near the chemical swamp, there's a spot for hiding loot in the helicopter graveyard.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_treasure_7_name">
    <text>Near the farm</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_treasure_7_descr">
    <text>Sorry, Vitka, but I'm low on supplies. I'm grabbing our loot. You'll get your share after our next hike.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_treasure_8_name">
    <text>Swamp</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_treasure_8_descr">
    <text>That watchtower was hit real hard! But it's an amazing spot, great for keeping my spoils.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_treasure_9_name">
    <text>Panel board</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_treasure_9_descr">
    <text>Time to grab what I've earned from the chumps of the Zone with blood, sweat and tears, hehe!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_treasure_10_name">
    <text>Doghouse</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_treasure_10_descr">
    <text>Saw a bandit searching some stalker's body. I'll keep my eye out for where he's going with his loot.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_treasure_11_name">
    <text>Crane cab</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_treasure_11_descr">
    <text>Damn it, not a moment of peace from those pieces of human garbage... Gotta throw away some of my stuff, I'm barely walking...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_treasure_12_name">
    <text>Hidden safe</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_treasure_12_descr">
    <text>Hehe, those bandits can't see shit. I'm walking around the vehicle graveyard and no one's even touching me. And there's a safe here, great place for my loot!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_treasure_13_name">
    <text>Box in bus</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_treasure_13_descr">
    <text>Whacked a couple of bandits. Got some stash coordinates off of one of 'em.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_treasure_14_name">
    <text>UAZ trunk</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_treasure_14_descr">
    <text>While I look for arties, I'll let my backpack sit nearby. Just hope the bandits don't show up, or that'll be the last I see of my stuff...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_treasure_15_name">
    <text>Mutated tree</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_treasure_15_descr">
    <text>Is there any place better than a pile of garbage under a deformed tree like this?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_treasure_16_name">
    <text>Crane</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_treasure_16_descr">
    <text>Found a kick-ass spot near the hangar. Hard to catch with the naked eye, and I have my guys nearby, so nobody's ever getting close to it.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_treasure_17_name">
    <text>Hangar safe</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_treasure_17_descr">
    <text>Freaking stalkers took over our hangar! I wonder if they cleared out the safe or not?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_treasure_18_name">
    <text>Backpack in wreckage</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_treasure_18_descr">
    <text>Hid my backpack in our base. If anyone actually finds it, I doubt they'll touch it.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_treasure_19_name">
    <text>Muscle man's stash</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_treasure_19_descr">
    <text>We had this one guy... dead at this point. Anyway, on a dare, he flung an entire pipe onto the roof of the hangar shop room, and I hid my loot inside. Those were the days...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_treasure_20_name">
    <text>Stash in vent</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_treasure_20_descr">
    <text>There's some ventilation thingy linked to the hangar. Should be a good place for my stuff.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_treasure_21_name">
    <text>Swamp log</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_treasure_21_descr">
    <text>Caught sight of some stalkers. One of them hid something in a log. I'll get there soon enough and clean it out real good for 'em.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_treasure_22_name">
    <text>Dead man's stash</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_treasure_22_descr">
    <text>Nobody's gonna believe how much stuff I loaded up on the other day! Man... problem is, if I take it over to my boys, they'll grab it all in a flash. Nah, I better hide it somewhere.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_treasure_23_name">
    <text>By the hangar</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_treasure_23_descr">
    <text>I found a backpack in the woods. Good find, to say the least: it's got weapons and medical supplies. Judging by the latter, the owner couldn't have been an ordinary stalker.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_treasure_24_name">
    <text>Anomalous stash</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_treasure_24_descr">
    <text>I was walking around anomalies looking for artifacts and found a little spot for hiding stuff just in case.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_treasure_25_name">
    <text>Garbage pile</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_treasure_25_descr">
    <text>That's some damn strong radiation in the trash. Doubt anyone's gonna look for my stuff there.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_treasure_26_name">
    <text>Hideaway in panel board</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_treasure_26_descr">
    <text>Man, I swear, these catacombs are something else! You could hide anything here: food, guns, ammo, even a body... oh wait.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_treasure_27_name">
    <text>Dead man's stuff</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_treasure_27_descr">
    <text>The SOB bandits popped a stalker... Good thing they didn't clean him out entirely — the rest is mine.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_treasure_28_name">
    <text>Soda water</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_treasure_28_descr">
    <text>It's amazing what you can find in these catacombs. Stumbled onto some Soviet-era water vending machines, should serve as a good place for hiding some stuff.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_treasure_29_name">
    <text>Stolen backpack</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_treasure_29_descr">
    <text>Hehe, haven't had a laugh like that in ages... The dumbass left his backpack when he went into an anomaly and forgot to get it back! What's yours is now mine!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_treasure_30_name">
    <text>Checkpoint box</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_treasure_30_descr">
    <text>Sanya, I hid your stuff by the hangar at the checkpoint, 'cause I don't trust our guys. Once you get better, pick it up, but don't take too long.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_treasure_31_name">
    <text>Hanging backpack</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_treasure_31_descr">
    <text>Decided to joke with our joker and hide his backpack in the tree. Try finding it now.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_quest_treasure_1_name">
    <text>Chrome's stash</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_quest_treasure_1_descr">
    <text>Stalker Chrome's stash. Contents are unknown.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_quest_treasure_11_name">
    <text>Remnants of the past</text>
  </string>
  <string id="gar_quest_treasure_11_descr">
    <text>I'll just hide this stuff inside the anomalous cistern. After having to close up shop, it'd be a shame to leave my stuff in an undependable place.</text>
  </string>
</string_table>
