<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>
<string_table>
  <string id="esc_treasure_1_name">
    <text>Fool's loot</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_treasure_1_descr">
    <text>On the way to Sid, I saw a goofball hide his loot while running around like a headless chicken. I should look for it under the roof, might have something of use.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_treasure_2_name">
    <text>Village log</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_treasure_2_descr">
    <text>At this point, they're just taking the piss out of us. The jarheads once again had me suppressed with that damn machine gun of theirs, so I had to leave on all fours. Had to hide my loot in a log 'cause it was just too heavy. I'll pick it up at night.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_treasure_3_name">
    <text>Strapless backpack</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_treasure_3_descr">
    <text>I was walking along the road, drunk as a skunk and swinging my backpack around... Long story short, the strap tore off and the backpack flew onto a rooftop. I'll go look for a ladder.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_treasure_4_name">
    <text>UAZ safe</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_treasure_4_descr">
    <text>There's a hidden safe in the UAZ on the road. I'll drop off stuff I don't need there and come back later.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_treasure_5_name">
    <text>Tree loot</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_treasure_5_descr">
    <text>This tree right here is the shit. Perfect place for hiding stuff. Not a single soul's gonna find it.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_treasure_6_name">
    <text>Under the wheels</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_treasure_6_descr">
    <text>The boys and I had this one stalker say bye-bye to his belongings. His PDA had the the coordinates to some stash, says it's located under a couple of wheels.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_treasure_7_name">
    <text>Backpack in mill</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_treasure_7_descr">
    <text>I escaped the jarheads and bolted to the mill. Hid my backpack there. They're close, not sure I'll get away...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_treasure_8_name">
    <text>Hidden flowerbed</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_treasure_8_descr">
    <text>I ran onto a flowerbed along the track and left all my stuff inside of it. I'm not too worried about it, as the army will keep it safe.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_treasure_9_name">
    <text>In the tunnel bushes</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_treasure_9_descr">
    <text>Found a pretty good spot in the tunnel for leaving my loot. I'll pick it up once I come back.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_treasure_10_name">
    <text>Electric barrel</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_treasure_10_descr">
    <text>Someone explain to me why the hell those jarheads deserve having their palms greased? I'll go through the anomalies as usual... and hide my loot while I'm at it.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_treasure_11_name">
    <text>Anomalous rocks</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_treasure_11_descr">
    <text>This one stalker got popped a while ago. On him, I found the coordinates to a stash where there's some fancy anomalous jacket. An anomalous jacket among anomalous rocks. I just stuffed my anomalous things there.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_treasure_12_name">
    <text>Stalker grave</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_treasure_12_descr">
    <text>I left my deceased comrade a few things for storage. Hope no one touches them.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_treasure_13_name">
    <text>In the bushes at the checkpoint</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_treasure_13_descr">
    <text>I'll hide some of my loot at the checkpoint leading to the Garbage. My backpack just can't handle the load.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_treasure_14_name">
    <text>Army stash</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_treasure_14_descr">
    <text>The patrol put me in a tight spot, so I had to take 'em out. The stuff I gathered from the bodies are hidden right around the corner.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_treasure_15_name">
    <text>Hideaway in tree stump</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_treasure_15_descr">
    <text>I put the stuff in a tree stump. Look for the radioactive truck.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_treasure_16_name">
    <text>Radioactive basement</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_treasure_16_descr">
    <text>I found some ginormous box, probably from the truck that was carrying corpses two years ago. I'm just wondering who in the world brought it into this basement? In any case, I left my loot in that box. Somewhat radioactive there, but that's alright — it'll scare off others.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_treasure_17_name">
    <text>Pipe in bushes</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_treasure_17_descr">
    <text>I found a metal pipe. I'll leave some extra stuff there.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_treasure_18_name">
    <text>Stash in panel board</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_treasure_18_descr">
    <text>I saw a rookie hide his knick-knacks in a nearby panel board. I should check out what exactly those knick-knacks might be.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_treasure_19_name">
    <text>Underwater hatch</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_treasure_19_descr">
    <text>No idea who or what the hatch in the muddy water is intended for, but it's perfectly hidden away from prying eyes. I'll hide my loot there.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_treasure_20_name">
    <text>Tree stump by the road</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_treasure_20_descr">
    <text>I found a stalker body with loot to boot. He's also got a stash that I'll check later.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_treasure_21_name">
    <text>Stash in the barrel</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_treasure_21_descr">
    <text>I'm not one to go pocketing, but I'll let surplus mutual equipment stay in the RAF van.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_treasure_22_name">
    <text>Stinking garage</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_treasure_22_descr">
    <text>That's a real stench in there, coming from the dead jarhead. Guy's already decomposing... but, who cares. Means nobody'll try snooping around there. I'll stash my loot where it's nastiest.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_treasure_23_name">
    <text>Tunnel in the Dark Valley</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_treasure_23_descr">
    <text>While I hunt down artifacts in the tunnel, I'll drop my backpack in the bushes. Wouldn't want to weigh myself down.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_treasure_24_name">
    <text>Boss' grave</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_treasure_24_descr">
    <text>I tucked away some loot in the boss' grave. If anyone tries anything, he'll raise up from the dead... and beat the living daylights out of the living! Hehehe.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_treasure_25_name">
    <text>Lonely cross</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_treasure_25_descr">
    <text>I found the isolated grave of a stalker. Hid some loot there, nobody's gonna think to take a look.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_treasure_26_name">
    <text>Hidden log</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_treasure_26_descr">
    <text>There's a log next to the mill, near the cistern. Hid some extra loot there.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_treasure_27_name">
    <text>In the tree</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_treasure_27_descr">
    <text>I threw my backpack onto the tree. If I have trouble getting there, imagine the fun others will have.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_treasure_28_name">
    <text>Under wagon</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_treasure_28_descr">
    <text>I'll make a stash under the wagon. Can't carry everything.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_quest_treasure_1_name">
    <text>KAMAZ trunk</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_quest_treasure_1_descr">
    <text>There's a stash in the KAMAZ trunk with some decent loot.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_quest_treasure_2_name">
    <text>Two wagons</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_quest_treasure_2_descr">
    <text>There are two wagons in the vicinity. One of them contains a hidden stash.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_quest_treasure_3_name">
    <text>Backpack at vehicle station</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_quest_treasure_3_descr">
    <text>There's a stash at the vehicle station, hidden real tight. Contains good loot.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_quest_treasure_4_name">
    <text>Safe at farm</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_quest_treasure_4_descr">
    <text>There's a pretty decent stash in a small safe at the farm house.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_quest_treasure_5_name">
    <text>Living hell</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_quest_treasure_5_descr">
    <text>There's a stash nearby... in an anomaly. But it's worth the effort getting there.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_quest_treasure_6_name">
    <text>Under bridge</text>
  </string>
  <string id="esc_quest_treasure_6_descr">
    <text>The jarheads have a stash close at hand, but it's hard to find.</text>
  </string>
</string_table>
