<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251"?>
<string_table>
  <string id="mlab_stalker_fate_task">
    <text>A STALKER'S FATE</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_stalker_fate_task_name">
    <text>Talk to Termite</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_stalker_fate_task_text">
    <text>Kalinskiy told me that Termite allegedly killed a stalker named Axe after he helped us carry out the artifacts selection. Hearing this left me outraged; we cannot afford to lose such valuable personnel like him. I need to head to our security department to figure out what happened.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_trials_task">
    <text>TRIALS</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_trials_task_start_name">
    <text>Start the equipment</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_trials_task_start_text">
    <text>Our superiors overseeing the laboratory have set a new goal of studying the possibility of reversing mutations in the Zone. Several civilian zombies who have wandered the Chornobyl Zone for several years have been located and taken in as test subjects. Perhaps, we could least partially return them to normal life soon. Today we will be conducting the first set of experiments. The work ahead of us will demand painstaking efforts.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_trials_task_wait_name">
    <text>Wait until the experiments are finished</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_trials_task_wait_text">
    <text>I've started the equipment. I only have to wait for the results now.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_trials_task_talk_name">
    <text>Talk to the assistant</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_trials_task_talk_text">
    <text>The first set of experiments are finished. I should talk to my assistant about the results.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_trials_task_final_name">
    <text>Answer call in office</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_trials_task_final_text">
    <text>I've received a call, likely from our superiors regarding the tests. I should go to my office and pick up the phone.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_final_task">
    <text>BREAKTHROUGH</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_final_task_start_name">
    <text>Head deeper into the laboratory</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_final_task_start_text">
    <text>I've managed to enter the underground area. God knows what or who lives here. Apparently there's some sort of laboratory here too. This place is probably filled with traps, so I should be on my guard as I move deeper. My objective is to find Dubinin and figure out what kind of place this is.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_final_task_scientist_boss_sprint_name">
    <text>Catch up with the professor</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_final_task_scientist_boss_sprint_text">
    <text>Professor Dubinin refused to surrender. I must catch up and arrest him.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_final_task_search_merc_leader_name">
    <text>Find Termite</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_final_task_search_merc_leader_text">
    <text>The professor is dead. I don't know whether I made the right choice or not, but he clearly never intended to turn himself in. Now I have to finish searching the laboratory, and find Termite.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_final_task_search_merc_leader_second_name">
    <text>Deal with the mercenaries</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_final_task_search_merc_leader_second_text">
    <text>The power is off. Now I have to finish searching the laboratory, deal with the mercenaries and evacuate the survivors.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_final_save_alives_name">
    <text>Evacuate the survivors</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_final_save_alives_text">
    <text>I couldn't locate Termite, but at least his cutthroats are all dead. Now I need to evacuate the survivors.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_final_task_follow_scientist_laborant_name">
    <text>Follow the scientist</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_final_task_follow_scientist_laborant_text">
    <text>The laboratory assistant said that Dubinin and the rest of his staff are planning to leave the laboratory via a teleporter. He also said that he will instruct me on how to turn the power off in the laboratory.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_final_task_teleport_off_name">
    <text>Cut power to the teleporter</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_final_task_teleport_off_text">
    <text>The scientist instructed me on how to turn the power off inside the laboratory. Dubinin won't escape so easily without it.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_final_task_talk_final_name">
    <text>Talk to Dubinin</text>
  </string>
  <string id="mlab_final_task_talk_final_text">
    <text>Power has been completely cut off in the laboratory. Professor Dubinin shouldn't be going anywhere without it.</text>
  </string>
</string_table>
