<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251"?>
<string_table>
  <string id="bar_treasure_1_name">
    <text>Cross</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_treasure_1_descr">
    <text>There's an abandoned stalker grave nearby, and no one ever goes there anymore. Might make a good place for a stash!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_treasure_2_name">
    <text>Dangerous container</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_treasure_2_descr">
    <text>I found a bunch of boxes meant for radioactive waste. Looked inside and it was all empty. I'll drop off my junk here. Nobody else looks through this stuff, right?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_treasure_3_name">
    <text>Pipe</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_treasure_3_descr">
    <text>There's a building along the road to the Army Warehouses where no one ever enters. Looks like a great place for stashing away.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_treasure_4_name">
    <text>Safe in abandoned building</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_treasure_4_descr">
    <text>Finally figured out where that bastard's hiding his loot! Once everyone goes away, that's my chance to clean out his stuff.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_treasure_5_name">
    <text>Grave at checkpoint</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_treasure_5_descr">
    <text>Been six months since he passed away. These things he left behind... they've been gnawing away at me. Only right thing to do is take it all to his grave.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_treasure_6_name">
    <text>Chemical hazard</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_treasure_6_descr">
    <text>Duty has a small arsenal not far from where the technician stays. One of them was stashing something in an empty waste bin.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_treasure_7_name">
    <text>Case in camp</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_treasure_7_descr">
    <text>I'll save up my medical supplies for when I go deeper into the center. It's a perfect spot — I've got my boys nearby along with the gallant Duty guard.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_quest_treasure_1_name">
    <text>Bottleman's stash</text>
  </string>
  <string id="bar_quest_treasure_1_descr">
    <text>Sanya Bottleman's personal stash. It apparently contains a Jellyfish artefact.</text>
  </string>
</string_table>
