<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>
<string_table>
  <string id="encyclopedia_mutant_unknown">
    <text>Unknown creature</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_mutant_animal">
    <text>Mutated animal</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_mutant_unmutated_animal">
    <text>Animal</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_mutant_experimental">
    <text>Test subject</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_mutant_human">
    <text>Human</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_mutant_bird">
    <text>Bird</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_mutants_crow">
    <text>Crow</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_mutants_crow_descr">
    <text>Crows are one of the few bird species that survived in the Zone. Many feathered birds have not been able to endure radiation and have not learnt to avoid anomalies. In order not to die in the maze of gravitational disturbances, military pilots use sophisticated detectors, but the secret of crows will soon drive ornithologists and biologists crazy. There are many theories explaining this phenomenon; however, they all agree that the cause of the miracle is the evolved brain of crows, which has managed to develop the most complex reflexes.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_mutants_flesh">
    <text>Flesh</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_mutants_flesh_descr">
    <text>Domestic pigs in the Zone, like many other living organisms, have undergone severe mutation. As genes controlling metabolic processes were affected, the animal's phenotype changed dramatically. Mutated pig, which stalkers call flesh — one of the most obvious examples of the Zone's abuse of nature. These creatures have formed a scaly-bone protective cover, significantly increased the body's ability to regenerate, and the nervous system has become more complex. Like an ordinary pig, the flesh is omnivorous, so when hungry, it may well attack a stalker.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_mutants_flesh_talker">
    <text>Talking flesh</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_mutants_flesh_talker_descr">
    <text>Talking flesh has long been regarded as the stuff of Stalkers, eagerly poisoned at campfires to frighten newcomers. However, among such stories were a few credible accounts of encounters with these creatures. Supposedly, the Talking Flesh live in the thickest swamps in the south-west of the Chornobyl Zone, but sometimes make a temporary migration to hunt in the territory of Agroprom and Cordon. A distinctive feature of these individuals is their ability to imitate the human voice, with the help of which the mutants manage to lure their victims into a trap. According to scientists, the Talking Flesh record the voices of Stalkers, like a dictaphone, stealthily creeping up to their camps, and then use these voices to hunt. The origin of the Talking Flesh is shrouded in mystery. Either they are an evolution of ordinary Flesh, or they are experiments of the scientific laboratories of the Alienation Zone. There are legends among the Stalkers that in the depths of the Swamps dwells a mad scientist who conducts sinister experiments with monsters. And perhaps the Talking Flesh is one of his brainchildren.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_mutants_boar">
    <text>Wild boar</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_mutants_boar_descr">
    <text>A large animal, reaching one and a half metres in withers. This animal surpasses its relatives outside the Zone with its vitality and aggressiveness, and is not inferior to most mutants. Mutagenic processes caused by radiation and anomalies have significantly affected the appearance of these mammals: in some places the latter have gone bald, and in some places, on the contrary, have grown very long stiff hair. Their hooves have changed their shape and become sharper, acquiring some resemblance to claws; their pupils have discoloured, pigmentation spots and deep wrinkles have appeared on the bald head. The boars of the Zone have a good tolerance for radiation, which allows them to stay in heavily contaminated areas for long periods of time. These animals usually attack from a run, trying to rip open the victim's belly with their fangs or knock him down.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_mutants_boar_king">
    <text>General Shtok</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_mutants_boar_king_descr">
    <text>Rumours that the forest surroundings of Novoshepelichi village are inhabited by a huge wild boar, at least twice the size of its relatives, began to appear in 1975, long before the Chornobyl accident. Back then, local hunters spent weeks in the forest, trying to track down and shoot the animal. But all was in vain. Many people believed that such a Boar did not really exist, and all this was just a fantasy of local men. A local Loch Ness monster, no less. But the legend rose from the ashes a few decades later, when the vicinity of the village became part of the anomalous Exclusion Zone, and in these parts visited Stalkers. There are several eyewitness accounts of monster sightings in the forest. Moreover, there were cases of attacks on Stalker squads, which did not do without victims... Tracking down and killing the monster became the main goal of local hunters. They nicknamed him — General Shtok. According to them, for its large and unnatural size and shape.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_mutants_dog">
    <text>Blind dog</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_mutants_dog_descr">
    <text>Since the first catastrophe several generations had passed in the canine family, and in each of them the influence of the Zone was more and more evident. Mutations and evolutionary adaptation led to the strengthening of previously weakly expressed canine abilities, often to the detriment of the usual ones. The main physiological changes affected vision — it turned out to be almost useless after the rapid increase in senses: for example, blind puppies survived in the Zone no worse, if not better than their sighted counterparts. As a result, ordinary dogs soon degenerated here completely, giving way to a new species — blind dogs. These animals perfectly recognise and bypass anomalies, radiation and other invisible dangers that swarm the Zone. Like their ancestors, blind dogs hunt in packs; encountering a large group of these creatures means serious danger even for a well-armed stalker.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_mutants_dog_amur">
    <text>Amur</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_mutants_dog_amur_descr">
    <text>Dogs in the Chornobyl Exclusion Zone are far from being man's best friends. And only one single dog in these parts has preserved something good and valiant. This is Amur — a dog of hunters from the neighbourhood of Novoshepelichi. They found him in the village, sleeping in one of the abandoned houses. To the surprise of the hunters, he was not aggressive towards them, and when they met, he wagged his tail and pulled his paws towards the stalkers. Subsequently, the dog followed the group and stayed in their camp, to which no one was against it. Over the years, Amur acquired enough skills to help in hunting, and, in fact, became a full-fledged member of the group. They say that earlier it was a dog of one of the first Stalkers who came to the Zone in 2006. What happened to the owner is unknown.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_mutants_dog">
    <text>Blind dog</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_mutants_dog_descr">
    <text>Since the first catastrophe several generations had passed in the canine family, and in each of them the influence of the Zone was more and more evident. Mutations and evolutionary adaptation led to the strengthening of previously weakly expressed canine abilities, often to the detriment of the usual ones. The main physiological changes affected vision — it turned out to be almost useless after the rapid increase in senses: for example, blind puppies survived in the Zone no worse, if not better than their sighted counterparts. As a result, ordinary dogs soon degenerated here completely, giving way to a new species — blind dogs. These animals perfectly recognise and bypass anomalies, radiation and other invisible dangers that swarm the Zone. Like their ancestors, blind dogs hunt in packs; encountering a large group of these creatures means serious danger even for a well-armed stalker.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_mutants_pseudodog">
    <text>Pseudodog</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_mutants_pseudodog_descr">
    <text>Despite the name, pseudodogs are not descended from dogs, but from wolves. Wild animals that lived in the forests of the Zone at the time of the catastrophe became the ancestors of one of the most dangerous mutant species. Pseudodogs are as different from mutated dogs as wild wolves are from mongrels. These creatures are territorial and fiercely attack anyone who invades their domain. The pseudodog's lightning-fast reactions, incredible mobility and sharp teeth make it a very serious opponent that even a large mutant or a well-armed stalker can't resist.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_mutants_psydog">
    <text>Psy dog</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_mutants_psydog_descr">
    <text>Psy-dogs are solitary animals. Usually found near psy fields. They hunt mostly stalkers, and do not tolerate roommates in their territory. Stalkers often confuse them with pseudodogs because of their external similarity. Psy-dogs can be recognised by their white fur. Otherwise, it is an exact copy of a pseudodog. The only thing that distinguishes them from pseudodogs is their ability to create phantom doppelgangers capable of inflicting physical damage.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_mutants_psydog_boss">
    <text>Unusual Psy dog</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_mutants_psydog_boss_descr">
    <text>For several years now, legends have been written about a pack of dogs living on the road from the Garbage to Bar. Many newcomers have died on this dog road, and sometimes even experienced stalkers have had enough trouble with it. Where does the Duty look, which is unable to take care of the security of the approaches to its base? Such conversations could often be heard behind the bar. Years later, knowledgeable stalkers did learn how to competently circumvent the dangers and get past the dogs. Recently, however, an unusual pack of psy-dogs, far superior in strength to their kin, have been spotted along the way. The monsters have lightning speed, are able to generate phantoms from inanimate objects and influence the human mind. Fighters of the group Duty repeatedly made attempts to track down a pack of psy-dogs, but all this did not lead to success. That's why the road to Baru at the moment is a lottery and a test of strength for Stalker.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_mutants_cat">
    <text>Cat</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_mutants_cat_descr">
    <text>It's a cat with all the consequences. It sees in the dark, stays out of water and fire, is afraid of dogs and eats mostly birds and rats, which are plentiful in the Zone. When defending itself from a threat, it uses not only its sharp claws, but also a special directional half-snarl-half-swipe. It sounds like an ordinary cat's meow in the middle of a March fight, only amplified many times. The howl also contains frequencies indistinguishable to the ear. The creature, in the direction of which the bayou howls at point-blank range, experiences a short-term panic attack (confused actions, rapid pulse, trembling limbs, nausea, hearing impairment — all the charms of acoustic shock), and the kitty tries to claw at it or just run away. The body is well-developed, covered with wispy hair, similar to a cat's, but twice as big, and wider and taller in the front than in the back. Quite muscular — very strong paws and a protruding jaw. The top of the head is quite feline too, though disproportionately large even compared to the body, the differences start with the jaws. They are very powerful, but protrude forward. On the sides of the throat hang resonator sacs.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_mutants_tushkano">
    <text>Tushkano</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_mutants_tushkano_descr">
    <text>The hunter's terror! One of the stupidest mistakes you can make in life is to underestimate animals because of their small size. Tushkans are insanely fast and skittish and always move in large packs.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_mutants_bloodsucker">
    <text>Bloodsucker</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_mutants_bloodsucker_descr">
    <text>A semi-legendary monster, described by seasoned stalkers as a tall, stooped humanoid with many tentacles where its mouth used to be. According to them, this creature feeds on its tentacles: by digging them into the neck of a living victim, it paralyses its prey and sucks its blood; after this procedure, only a dried, mummy-like shell remains of the person. The most amazing thing about the bloodsucker is its ability to become invisible. Apparently, these creatures are responsible for the deaths of a large number of stalkers. Few of the eyewitnesses survived — and judging by the stories of those lucky ones, the bloodsuckers prefer damp places like swamps and dungeons.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_mutants_electric_bloodsucker">
    <text>Electro-Bloodsucker</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_mutants_electric_bloodsucker_descr">
    <text>In studying the fauna of the Chornobyl Exclusion Zone, scientists have long come to one conclusion — monsters change their habits, appearance, and even abilities depending on where they live. To this type can be attributed a family of Bloodsuckers, living in the Army Depots, near the electrical substation. It is as if they are charged with Electra, and later on even use its charge to attack the enemy. If earlier Bloodsuckers met their victim with a whipping slap and a savoury hickey, now the poor guy will also get a decent electric shock. Thankfully, such electricians — a very rare phenomenon in the Zone.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_mutants_pseudogigant">
    <text>Pseudogiant</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_mutants_pseudogigant_descr">
    <text>A huge carcass consisting of a drop-shaped torso and a pair of hypertrophied limbs is what a Pseudogiant is. Handeleg are used by this creature to move around and grab prey. An adult reaches a weight of two tonnes at a height of about two metres. External clumsiness is very deceptive — pseudogiants are rapid in movement, their muscles have simply amazing power, and the bones are as strong as metal. The brain is protected by a thick skull — about 100 millimetres thick! — and many complex functions are performed by the spinal cord. The ability of the pseudogiants to form localised shock waves on the surface of the earth, striking all living things within a limited radius, is also remarkable.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_mutants_chimera">
    <text>Chimera</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_mutants_chimera_descr">
    <text>A two-headed beast on four powerful clawed paws. A very cunning and powerful creature, it can be near its prey in the blink of an eye and cut it open with its sharp claws. Several stalkers have been killed by its claws, the stalkers called this creature a chimera. The chimera is immune to some anomalies. The presence of two heads can indicate an advanced intelligence.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_mutants_night_chimera">
    <text>Night-Chimera</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_mutants_night_chimera_descr">
    <text>It looks like an ordinary Chimera, but at the same time, possessing the ability to become invisible. How the monster got such abilities — remains a mystery. Perhaps it is another result of experiments of scientists, or a natural process of local evolution. To the delight of stalkers — such types of Chimera are extremely rare in the Zone.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_mutants_burer">
    <text>Burer</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_mutants_burer_descr">
    <text>Burers are fat, short freaks with telekinetic powers. They can move heavy objects with their thoughts alone, and create invisible force barriers. The Burers were once ordinary people — most likely prisoners or stupid volunteers who were unlucky enough to be part of a programme to enhance supernatural, particularly telekinetic, abilities. As a side effect, they turned into real monsters — they lost their human form and went insane. Burer's alien to human morality and compassion, they kill people for entertainment and sustenance, using a variety of tricks from their supernatural arsenal — known cases when these freaks lured stalkers into an ambush, pretending to be normal people. Spacious clothing, most likely the remnants of special uniforms, which the Boorers cherish far more than other mutants of the Zone, helps them pass for human (at least from afar). Most of these creatures remain living near the abandoned laboratories that spawned them.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_mutants_snork">
    <text>Snork</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_mutants_snork_descr">
    <text>These creatures appear to have once been human, though it's hard to imagine what conditions could drive a human to such a state. Snorks are crazy, animalistic creatures that are not much different from the predatory monsters of the Zone. They move on four limbs, bouncing above the ground and constantly sniffing it to catch the scent of their prey. They hunt cautiously and calculatingly, sneaking up on stalkers like predatory animals. Lightning-fast reflexes and hypertrophied muscles allow snorkels to make long, precise jumps and tear their prey to shreds in seconds. Some of them still have parts of army uniforms or separate parts of equipment, which suggests that they are missing military stalkers.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_mutants_controller">
    <text>Controller</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_mutants_controller_descr">
    <text>A rare mutant found near the center of the Zone. It looks like a humanoid with a disproportionately enlarged head. Possesses advanced perception, as well as the ability to control the behavior of less evolved living creatures.\nThey can take control of even humans. This is a dangerous enemy, meeting with which even the most experienced stalkers are afraid.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_mutants_tubeman_controller">
    <text>Tunnel Controller</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_mutants_tubeman_controller_descr">
    <text>A rare mutant found near the center of the Zone. It looks like a humanoid with a disproportionately enlarged head. Possesses advanced perception, as well as the ability to control the behavior of less evolved living creatures.\nThey can take control of even humans. This is a dangerous enemy, meeting with which even the most experienced stalkers are afraid.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_mutants_val_fake_house_boss_controller">
    <text>Hunter Controller</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_mutants_val_fake_house_boss_controller_descr">
    <text>The fact that Controllers can not only control the minds of stalkers, but also read their thoughts, has long been a well-established fact in the Zone. And what is usually in the mind of the average stalker? Artifacts of the rare kind, of course! The cunning hunter-controller uses this to its advantage by luring stalkers into a trap, in this case located on the outskirts of the Dark Valley. In such situations, stalkers don't even realize that while they are hunting for yet another artifact — they are the ones being hunted. The thirst for profit immediately turns into a game of survival, which obviously not everyone can win. After all, their opponent will be an extremely inventive mutant, capable of causing elegant, confusing hallucinations.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_mutants_boss_controller">
    <text>Master</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_mutants_boss_controller_descr">
    <text>Not all people accepted the fate of leaving their homes after the Chornobyl accident in 1986. Many local residents decided to return to their native lands, despite the dangerous effects of radiation. But as it turned out, the main threat to them was the activity of scientists who deployed a network of underground laboratories at Chornobyl. It is not known what research they were doing there, but one thing was certain — the village, which was located near the current Dark Valley, began to disappear en masse. Many locals immediately connected the disappearances it with the rumors about nearby secret laboratories, but never left their native village despite this. That was until the first emission occurred in 2006, which turned this place into an anomalous zone. After the most of locals evacuated their homes, and apparently for good. But what became of those who went missing? One of them was discovered in the undergrounds tunnels benearg the Dark Valley. He turned out to be one of the escaped lab subjects, who had been irreversibly mutated into something resembling a Controller. Despite possessing telepathic abilities, he still retained a modicum of humanity... But don't let that confuse you. Despite feelings of pity, you should always remember that this is already more monster than human...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_mutants_tele_poltergeist">
    <text>Telepathic Poltergeist</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_mutants_tele_poltergeist_descr">
    <text>Truly supernatural invisible creatures that are found only in the depths of the Zone and typically dwell inside dilapidated buildings. Not much is known about the origin of these creatures; some say that these are the spirits of stalkers who succumbed to powerful emissions, while others say that it's a bunch of bullcrap. There's really no telling here. The way these creatures manifest themselves is similar to poltergeists in folklore (whence the name) and is characterized by periodic howling, laughter, and dangerous fire orbs that appear out of nowhere. Unfortunately, all information about this phenomenon is drawn from vague and rather contradictory stories, the veracity of which is questionable.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_mutants_fire_poltergeist">
    <text>Fire Poltergeist</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_mutants_fire_poltergeist_descr">
    <text>Truly supernatural invisible creatures that are found only in the depths of the Zone and typically dwell inside dilapidated buildings. Not much is known about the origin of these creatures; some say that these are the spirits of stalkers who succumbed to powerful emissions, while others say that it's a bunch of bullcrap. There's really no telling here. The way these creatures manifest themselves is similar to poltergeists in folklore (whence the name) and is characterized by periodic howling, laughter, and dangerous fire orbs that appear out of nowhere. Unfortunately, all information about this phenomenon is drawn from vague and rather contradictory stories, the veracity of which is questionable.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_mutants_red_poltergeist_guard">
    <text>Poltergeist Guard</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_mutants_red_poltergeist_guard_descr">
    <text>Truly supernatural invisible creatures that are found only in the depths of the Zone and typically dwell inside dilapidated buildings. Not much is known about the origin of these creatures; some say that these are the spirits of stalkers who succumbed to powerful emissions, while others say that it's a bunch of bullcrap. There's really no telling here. The way these creatures manifest themselves is similar to poltergeists in folklore (whence the name) and is characterized by periodic howling, laughter, and dangerous fire orbs that appear out of nowhere. Unfortunately, all information about this phenomenon is drawn from vague and rather contradictory stories, the veracity of which is questionable.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_mutants_red_poltergeist_leader">
    <text>Poltergeist Leader</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_mutants_red_poltergeist_leader_descr">
    <text>The roots of the legend About the creature in the hangar lead to the abandoned underground laboratory X-18. It is there that the most important, and more important to say — the strongest Poltergeist of the entire Zone settled! He equipped himself a very cozy nest on the lower levels of the dungeons, and as a weapon used abandoned scientists equipment, computers, boxes and other utensils. It will cause its victim a lot of trouble if it hits him on the head! Food is delivered to him by his faithful servants — poltergeists, living in the factory at the entrance to the laboratory. In the few months that the creature has been undisturbed, it has grown to an impressive size. Have you pictured the face of whoever's gonna fight it? </text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_mutants_soldier_poltergeist">
    <text>Poltergeist-Soldier</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_mutants_soldier_poltergeist_descr">
    <text>A blob of energy of unknown nature, which at first glance resembles a Poltergeist. However, in reality, the creature is non-aggressive and clearly has no telekinetic abilities. Usually, seeing this creature, stalkers either try to avoid it or open fire. True to shoot an unknown substance has not yet managed to anyone. But there have been cases when with this creature tried to establish contact. It was found out that before "it" was an ordinary man, but some atrocities of scientists led to irreversible changes in appearance and form of life. But the creature's humanity, surprisingly, was still preserved.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_mutants_zombie">
    <text>Zombie</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_mutants_zombie_descr">
    <text>Zombified civilians with half-decomposed human bodies in badly ragged clothing. Physically, they are people who have completely lost their personality and ability to think as a result of exposure to Controllers or psy radiation. The only things left are instincts and life habits. The destruction of personality depends on the strength and duration of exposure. There are reports that zombified calmly tolerate radiation and psy radiation, so they can attack stalkers in conditions in which the latter can not fight normally. Contrary to all ideas about the dead, zombies have residual intelligence and memory: they remember some phrases and apply them in appropriate situations. This also indicates working vocal cords and facial muscles. This stage of personality destruction is already irreversible, both on the mental and physiological levels. The degree of decomposition of bodies in zombies differs — there are both "fresh" dead and almost mummified remains. The weak point of a dead person is the head, namely the brain. Zombies are capable of "limited" regeneration. Inhibition of all physiological processes in the zombie's body leads to the fact that it is quite difficult to kill them. Most likely, it is manifested in low sensitivity to pain, slow metabolism and denser arrangement of tissues due to their adhesion, which does not waste the resources of their body.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_mutants_zombie_katakomb">
    <text>Servant</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_mutants_zombie_katakomb_descr">
    <text>Zombified humans; probably former test subjects of the X-18 lab. They are under the careful control of the Master, and therefore follow his instructions. Servants show no signs of aggression to anyone.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_mutants_smoke_ghost">
    <text>Ghostly smoke</text>
  </string>
  <string id="encyclopedia_mutants_smoke_ghost_descr">
    <text>An unknown anomalous matter that formed after the horrific death of a private from the Duty faction. Its appearance resembles a thick gray smoke with electrical discharges around it. It appears to be capable of disabling electrical appliances and lights, as well teleportation of physical matter. Behaves aggressively only towards specific individuals; does not target ordinary stalkers. While it may be the spirit of the deceased Duty private or yet another anomaly of the Zone — its true nature still remains unclear.</text>
  </string>
</string_table>
